<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Darvein</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/</link><description>Recent content on Darvein</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.darvein.net/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/01_devops_todos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/01_devops_todos/</guid><description>Devops TODOs Board TODOs AWS Documentation Kubernetes documentation Book: From bash to Z she&amp;rsquo;ll, kiddle peek Kindle: Site Reliability Engineering: How Google Runs Production Systems Kindle: Shell Scripting: How to Automate Command Line Tasks Using Bash Scripting and Shell Programming Some other TODOs Study Terraform Study Prometheus Docker in deep, linux internals Git internals Bash scripting 101 Python scripting for devops Ansible collections vs playbooks Monitoring &amp;amp; Logging: Grafana, ELK, Prometheus, New Relic, Datadog, Splunk, Papertrail Databases and Storage: Redis, Mysql, Elasticsearch, Mongodb, RabbitMq, Kafka Servers: Nginx, Apache Datascience: Spark, Hadoop, Flink, Airflow, Arrow AI Deep Learning: Kubeflow, MLFlow Books to search The phoenix project, gene kim Continuos delivery, jez humble The devops handbook, gene kim Site reliability engineering, betsy beyer Accelerate, Nicole Forsgren Cloud native patterns, cornelia davis Cloud computing, Ray Rafaels Architecting the cloud, michael kavis AWS Certified solutions architect official study guid, joe baron The cloud at your service, johy rosenberg How linux works, brian ward The linux command line, william shotts Linux bible, christopher negus Linux pocket guide, daniel barret Unix and linux system administration handbook, evil nemeth Linux for beginners, jason cannon Linux kernel development, robert love Understanding the linux kernel, daniel bovet Mastering embedded linux programming, chris simmonds Practical guide to linux commands, editors, and shell programming, mark sobell Books to read Unix and Linux administration handbook, nemeth Snyder Rhcsa rhce, ex200 and ex300 BPF performance tools, Gregg The practice of cloud system administration, Limoncelli Continuous delivery, humble Farley IT infrastructure architecture, sjaak Laan Books to read (kindle) Continuous Delivery: Reliable Software Releases through Build, Test, and Deployment Automation (Adobe Reader) (Addison-Wesley Signature Series (Fowler)) Building Microservices: Designing Fine-Grained Systems DevOps and Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) Handbook : Non-Programmer’s Guide ( Second Edition) The Linux Command Line, 2nd Edition: A Complete Introduction Incident Management for Operations The Linux Programming Interface: A Linux and UNIX System Programming Handbook IT Infrastructure Architecture - Infrastructure Building Blocks and Concepts Third Edition The TCP/IP Guide: A Comprehensive, Illustrated Internet Protocols Reference rtfm* Wicked Cool Shell Scripts, 2nd Edition: 101 Scripts for Linux, OS X, and UNIX Systems Linux Command Line and Shell Scripting Bible Mastering Linux Shell Scripting RHCSA/RHCE Red Hat Linux Certification Study Guide (Exams EX200 &amp;amp; EX300), 6th Edition (Certification Press) Command Line Kung Fu: Bash Scripting Tricks, Linux Shell Programming Tips, and Bash One-liners Troubleshooting: A Technician&amp;rsquo;s Guide, Second Edition (Isa Technician Series) Kindle: Terraform: Up &amp;amp; Running: Writing Infrastructure as Code Local PDF files found on my computer ├── AL-MigrationplanofJavaApplicationsfromHanaCloudintoAWS-020318-2059.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/basic-aws-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/basic-aws-roadmap/</guid><description>AWS Basic and Essential Roadmap Some references:
ec2: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/concepts.html ec2 autoscaling: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/autoscaling/ec2/userguide/what-is-amazon-ec2-auto-scaling.html EC2 AMIs AWS AMIs (features Amazon Linux AMI vs Ubuntu AMIs) How to find AMIs AMI Types How to create AMI? How to purchase and sell an AMI Sharing AMIs Instance Types Type of instances Pricing Models or Purchase options How to connect to an EC2 (windows, linux)? linux: SSH Daemon, SSM windows: RDP Storage (EBS) EBS Volumes What is it?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/ec2/</guid><description>EC2 Notes AMIs Amazon Machine Images.
AWS Provides 3 AWS-based images:
AMI, AMI2, AMI2023 The current one is AMI 2023, which comes with better security (python3 upgraded, selinux, openssl3, imdsv2). XFS file system for root / and gp3 volume by default. Read More IMDSV2 provides an enforced authentication to the Instance AWS Metadata Info AWS AMI are images from where you can lunch EC2 Instances.
You can create your own AMIs from running instances with your own pre-configured and installed software You can use existing AMI from AWS Marketplace or you can buy an AMI Keep in mind we can create AMIs that are EBS-backed or InstanceStore-backed.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/readme/</guid><description> AWS Notes My notes on AWS Learning
TODOs Continue here: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/virtualization_types.html</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-certifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-certifications/</guid><description> AWS Certifications Notes on both AWS Certifications
AWS Solutions Architect Associate &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS API Gateway &amp;#x1F5D2; Assoc exam &amp;#x1F5D2; Cloudfront &amp;#x1F5D2; CloudWatch &amp;#x1F5D2; Security &amp;#x1F5D2; DynamoDB &amp;#x1F5D2; Virtual hard disk. Block based storage. &amp;#x1F5D2; EC2 &amp;#x1F5D2; EFS Elastic filesystem &amp;#x1F5D2; Elastic Encoder &amp;#x1F5D2; Elasticache &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS Exam Prep &amp;#x1F5D2; Generalities &amp;#x1F5D2; Identity Access Management &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS Kinesis &amp;#x1F5D2; Lambda &amp;#x1F5D2; Load Balancer &amp;#x1F5D2; RDS &amp;#x1F5D2; Redshift &amp;#x1F5D2; Route53 &amp;#x1F5D2; Simple Storage Service S3 &amp;#x1F5D2; Segurity groups &amp;#x1F5D2; Snowball &amp;#x1F5D2; SNS Simple notification service &amp;#x1F5D2; SQS &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS Storage Gateway &amp;#x1F5D2; Simple Workflow Service &amp;#x1F5D2; VPC AWS Solutions Architect Professional &amp;#x1F5D2; Associate arch plan and notes &amp;#x1F5D2; Cognito &amp;#x1F5D2; Directory Service &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS Exam Prep &amp;#x1F5D2; IAM &amp;#x1F5D2; RAM &amp;#x1F5D2; S3 &amp;#x1F5D2; Service Quotas &amp;#x1F5D2; VPC &amp;#x1F5D2; VPN &amp;#x1F5D2; Well architected framework &amp;#x1F5D2; Workspaces &amp;#x1F5D2; Written notes</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-jq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-jq/</guid><description>AWS and JQ Examples # List instances by creation time aws ec2 describe-instances --query &amp;#39;Reservations[*].Instances[*].[InstanceId,LaunchTime]&amp;#39; --region us-west-2 --output text | sort -n -k 2 # List all EC2 Instances aws ec2 describe-instances --region us-east-1 \ | jq -r \ &amp;#39;.Reservations[].Instances[] | [.InstanceId, .PublicIpAddress, (.Tags[]|select(.Key==&amp;#34;Name&amp;#34;).Value)]&amp;#39; aws ec2 describe-instances |\ jq -r \ &amp;#39;.Reservations[].Instances[] | select(.Tags[].Key | contains(&amp;#34;auto&amp;#34;)).PublicIpAddress&amp;#39; aws rds describe-db-instances |\ jq -r \ &amp;#39;.DBInstances[] | select(.Engine==&amp;#34;postgres&amp;#34; and .DBInstanceIdentifier==&amp;#34;acmeorg-eks-apps-production&amp;#34;).DBInstanceStatus&amp;#39; aws ec2 describe-subnets |\ jq -r \ &amp;#39;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/api-gateway/</guid><description> AWS API Gateway Basics Easy service to publish, maintain and monitor and secure APIs at any scale. &amp;ldquo;front door&amp;rdquo; to different backend services that runs on EC2 or Lambda, etc. Low cost and efficient Throttle api gtwy support to prevent attacks Cloudwatch integrations + logs Same-origin-policy support Cross-origin resource sharing support API Caching improves the latency cache is expired on a certain TTL period</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/assoc-exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/assoc-exam/</guid><description>Assoc exam ec2 + autoscaling, alb/elb/nlb windows and nfs, fsx (windows) direct gateway, snowball, vpns on-prems s3, glacier cloudfront vpc, nat gateways api gateway, lambda, route53 sqs, sns, swf iam, scp, aws orgs rds, dynamodb, redshift</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/cloudfront/</guid><description>Cloudfront It is a content delivery service. Content is replicated across different edge location. An edge location is not a region nor a AZ, it is a location where data is cached.
it caches static content (web distribution), dynamic, streaming (rtmp) data.
it well integrates with s3, ec2, elb, route53.
a origin for the CDN can be a ec2, s3 or a elb.
objs in CDN are cached with a TTL</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/cloudwatch/</guid><description> CloudWatch Basics Standard monitoring = every 5mins. Detailed monitoring = every 1min. Ability to create custom dashboards with different widgets EC2 instances by default have: cpu utilization, disk i/o, net i/o, status machine/host. (No RAM) Ability to create Alarms based on Tresholds via AWS SNS. Ability to create Events as respond to state changes in aws resources Centralized place for log aggregation It is not Cloudtrail</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/concept-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/concept-security/</guid><description> Security AWS have Shared responsability model Least privileges aws has lot of certifications (ISO 2007, etc)s Facets
Identiy Authentication Authorization (iam) Trust IdP (aws cognito, facebook, gmail) SSO SAML, Oauth, OpenID Multi-account management for who ones?
large organizations segreation duties, costs, agillity do we need it?
administrative isolations? limited visibility and discovery of workloads limited and strong isolation for recoveries and/or auditing data?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/dynamodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/dynamodb/</guid><description>DynamoDB Basics Fast nosql: mobile, web, gaming, ad-tech, IoT, etc.
Low latency to applications.
Expensive for writes, cheaper for reads.
Stored on SSD
Spread across 3 geographicall distinct data centres (AZs)
dynamodb read/write capacity scales on the fly, no downtimes
eventual consisten reads
consistency acorss all copies of data is within a second (best read performance) strongly consisten reads
returns the results that reflects all writes were successful, prior the read Indexes ?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/ebs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/ebs/</guid><description>Virtual hard disk. Block based storage. Generalities Tied to a single AZ Can be attached to only one EC2 instance at once EBS has to be in the AZ (subnet) than the EC2. Otherwise move the EBS to other AZ by creating a Snapshot. Same for regions. Can be modified/upgraded on the fly Multiple EBS mounted in a EC2 can help to form a RAID 5/10/0 Defaults Termination protection is turned off by default EBS root vol is by default deleted once upon EC2 termination Encryption EBS root volume CAN NOW be encrypted (only via thrid party solutions).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/ec2/</guid><description>EC2 Basics EC2 instances backed with EBS can easily recovered by restarting into a different hypervisor InstanceStore in the other hand if the instance fails, the machine and data is lost. Supports user data if a script execution is needed after the machine is boot. ** clustered placement group (one AZ) and spread placement group (multiple AZs). Nitro and XEN are the underlying hypervisors for AWS EC2 Options on-demand: hourly paid.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/efs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/efs/</guid><description> EFS Elastic filesystem Can be attached to multiple ec2 instances at once Scales automatically on size of storage Supports NFSv4 Works only within a Region and multiple AZs in the Region Multi-AZ replication Read after write consistency Can be mounted from on-premises (unsecure without tunnels) Or se AWS Datasync in on-prem infra to sync data to EFS Preserves ownership and permissions from OS You pay for what the size you currently use Multiple EFS&amp;rsquo; can be in sync with with AWS DataSync Pricing 3x times more expensive than EBS 20x times more expensive than S3</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/elastic-transcoder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/elastic-transcoder/</guid><description> Elastic Encoder basics convert media files for different formats (smarhphones, tables, PCs) no need to guess what would be the best option for the client depending on their internet connection pricing pay based on the minutes of the transcode process and the resolution</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/elasticache/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/elasticache/</guid><description> Elasticache engine options memcached and redis best option against slower disk-based databases improved latency intensive I/O works purely on memory Memcached really good for read-heavy scenarios Redis supports multi-az with master and slave instances</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/exam/</guid><description> AWS Exam Prep Solutions Architect Associate General knowledge from AWS needed:
Network: VPC Route53 Migrations Direct connect Snowball, edge, snowmobile Data sync Compute: EC2, ECS Queues: SQS, SNF High availability Serverless Caching: CDN Database: RDS Storage: EFS, EBS, S3 Users (users, roles, policies) NoSQL: Dynamodb Athena Redshift Elasticsearch? Tips: Exam keywords: cost, performance Resources cantrill: https://learn.cantrill.io/p/aws-certified-solutions-architect-associate-saa-c02</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/glacier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/glacier/</guid><description> Generalities An offline and cheaper storage.
Long-term archival service Chepear but slow Backend for AWS Storage Gateway Virtual Tape Library Faster speed retrievals have more higher pricing Max size 40TB Archives/Objs become inmutable when Locked (it takes 24hrs to be locked) Support IAM Policies to make sure objs are not accidentilly deleted</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/iam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/iam/</guid><description>Identity Access Management Generalities Root account shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be used for shopping. First account when you create an AWS Account AWS Accounts created by a single Root user are isolated and secure Each account handles: Authentication, Authorization and Billing individually Objs: Users Groups Roles Permissions (policies) Security principles: Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization Chain of credentials https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSJavaSDK/latest/javadoc/com/amazonaws/auth/DefaultAWSCredentialsProviderChain.html Generalities v2 Root Users/User Groups Groups: Administrators, Devops, Developers, Externals (&amp;ldquo;readonly&amp;rdquo;) Users: regular users for people!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/kinesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/kinesis/</guid><description> AWS Kinesis Service for high support streaming data from different sources (games, amazon purchaces, stock pirces, etc)
Basics 3 kinesis: Streams, Firehose and Analytics producers (ec2, mobiles, computers, IoT devs) consumers (ec2 instances, redshift, elasticsearch) Kinesis Streams data producers -&amp;gt; kinesis streams (stored 24h-7days) in shards -&amp;gt; data consumers -&amp;gt; storage the capacity is measured by the number of shards Kinesis Firehose data producers -&amp;gt; kinesis firehose (not need for data consumers nor shards) -&amp;gt; s3 -&amp;gt; data consumers data is not stored, it gets deleted as soon is proceesed by firehose Kinesis Analytics data procucers -&amp;gt; kinesis analytics -&amp;gt; data consumers (s3, redshift, es) fast sql over the data</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/lambda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/lambda/</guid><description>Lambda Basics Serverless service. The underlying infrastructure is managed by AWS.
Even-driven compute service (s3, dynamodb) Response of HTTP requests via AWS API Gateway Supports multiple languages engines (node, python, c#, java). An IAM Role is needed A variaty of triggers (alexa skills, cloudfront, cloudwatch, dynamodb, s3, , api gateway, etc). 1 lambda function execution per request. The evolution would be Data Centre -&amp;gt; IaaS -&amp;gt; PaaS -&amp;gt; Containers -&amp;gt; Serverless.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/load-balancer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/load-balancer/</guid><description>Load Balancer Basics Types: Application, Network, Classic load balancer. X-forward-For header is forwared from outside to the instance server HTTP 504 if the backend app is having issues, not reacheable. LBs costs money :) Application load balancer HTTP/HTTPS (based on methods, routes) operates on layer 7 Network load balancer TCP traffic based layer 4 millions of requests per second, ultra low latencies Classic load balancer Elastic load balancer Mix of layer 7 and 4.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/rds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/rds/</guid><description>RDS Supports relational: SQL Server, Oracle, Mysql, Aurora, PostgreSQL, MariaDB Supports nosql: dynamodb Data warehousing: redshift (OLAP) Encryption is supported (only applies if the db is being created and encryption option is enabled) All RDS are OLTP Backups two types: automated backups and database snapshots automated backups: aws takes a full daily snapshots with a retention period of 35 days. enabled by default stored in s3 during the backup process, the db i/o may be suspended or increased latency may be seen database snapshots: user initiazed triggered when a db is deleted the restore process creates a new RDS snapshots can be encrypted Multi-AZ Databases are replicated to different AZs (subnets).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/redshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/redshift/</guid><description>Redshift OLAP data housing service. Data is organized in columns.columns.
Basics advanced compresion doesn&amp;rsquo;t require indexes nor materialized views. massive parallel processing (MPP) columnar data storage (less I/Os) Cluster a single node has 160Gb a multi-node solution can be up to 128 nodes. Consists on a leader node and compute nodes. not multi-az. only available on 1 AZ. (Not available) Pricing billed per unit of process on a node on a hour not charged for the leader backups data transfer Encryption in-transit SSL.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/route53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/route53/</guid><description> Route53 Global AWS service Supports public and private Hosted zones Initial limit of 50 domain registration only Routing policies it basically supports:
simple routing Records that routes to something: MX, A, CNAME, TXT, etc. weighted routing basically splits traffic between targets based on a weight number (0-100) latency-based routing route53 automatically routes based on the origin&amp;rsquo;s response latency (ec2 or lb) failover routing a route53 healthcheck setup is needed works for DR environments two record sets is nedded, one primary and the other secundary geolocation routing based on the client&amp;rsquo;s region geolocation region locations has has to manually be configured in route53 geoproximity based on the geolocation of the aws resources multivalue answer routing basically multivalue servers to server a specific A dns record</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/s3/</guid><description>Simple Storage Service S3 Flat files storage service, object-based storage service. Not a block storage service.
Buckets Versioning Encryption Unlimited storage Lifecycle management Logging for accesses Host static web sites Buckets names are unique globally Supports ACLs and Torrent/BiTorrent Defaults By default a bucket is private By default up to 100 buckets are allowed Objects Obj properties: Key(obj name) and Value(bytes), version id, metadata. If the obj is deleted, it is not actually deleted instead a new version as deleted is created Restore an obj: remove the Marker delete obj version Each obj version has independent version on public property Objs size can be from 0b to 5TB.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/security-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/security-group/</guid><description> Segurity groups A virtual firewall.
Basics Controls inbound and outbound traffic Inbound is blocked by default Outbound is allowed by default EC2: mutliple SGs can be assigned SGs are STATEFUL (ACLs are stateless) Best practices Don&amp;rsquo;t block specific ip address with SGs instead use NACLs</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/snowball/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/snowball/</guid><description>Snowball A powerfull compute box, similar like having an small AWS datacenter in a physicall box, it is a petabyte-scale data storage and transport. A Snowball edge can be installed on-premises, it is a up to 100TB data transport solution that finally goes to AWS S3. A snowballmobile is a truck with a bucn on snowball edges on it. It transfer up to 100PB of data.
Basically an import/export aws solution for on-premises.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/sns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/sns/</guid><description>SNS Simple notification service basics powerful notification system push-based service publish-subscribe (pub-sub) messaging paradigm. No periodically checks. integrations with aws autoscaling, email notif, SMS, HTTP Endpoints, etc. messages are stored reduntantly across different AZs message format for email is JSON Only works over HTTP topics where subscribers are grouped in order to get an identical copy of the message notification a single topic can support multiple endpoints for delivery such as iOS, android, SMS recipients, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/sqs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/sqs/</guid><description>SQS First service ever on AWS. Distributeded queue system for messages between applications
Basics it is a PULL based system messages can contain up to 256 Kb of text on any format messages can be retrieved via AWS SQS API messages can be kept in queue from 1min to 14 days (default is 4days) autoscaling can be built into the service SQS guaratees that messages will be processed at leas once Supports dead-letter queue for not consumed?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/storage-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/storage-gateway/</guid><description>AWS Storage Gateway An AWS service that allows on-premise network to direct connect with AWS (via AWS Direct Connect) and store data on different services, s3 or glacier.
Generalities It is runs a VM that can run on a VMWare/Hypervisor Provides local storage backed by S3/Glacier Used by DR environments Used by Cloud Migrations Types NFS (File Gateway) Can be stored on S3 via NFS/SMB Ownership, permissions and timestamps are preserved in s3 obj meta-data Supports native objects functionality (lifecycle, cross-region replication, etc) iSCSI (volumes gateway, non flat, block-based storage): for Operating Systems, DB engines.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/swf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/swf/</guid><description> Simple Workflow Service Basics task-oriented API, not like SQS which is a message-oriented API SWF ensures that tasks are assigned only once (not possible twices like SQS) SWF keps track of all events in an app (not like SQS, you need to implement your own app-level tracking) makes easy coordinations work between different componentes steps like: media processing, web app backends, business process workflows, analytics pipelines example: amazon shopping from order, cc check, ship order, completion and end needs workers and deciders (EC2 instances)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/vpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/vpc/</guid><description>VPC Basics supports hardware virtual private network VPN for on-prems datacenters limit of 5 VPCs by default components: igw or vpg (vpn) routing tables nACLs subnets vpc region 1 subnet = 1 AZ LAN options: 10.0.0.0 - 10.255.255.255 (10/8) 172.16.0.0 - 172.31.255.255 (172.16/12) 192.168.0.0 - 192.168.255.255 (192.168/16) Only 1 IGW per VPC ** SGs are stateful. NACLs are stateless. instead of a igw a NAT Instance (ec2) can be used or just a Nat gateway (EIP) network traffic logs can go to cloudwatch via VPC FLowLogs option enabled (not peered vpcs) vpc flow can be created at VPC, subnet and network intf levesl VPC endpoints can be enabled to allow internal aws ec2 instances to connect to other aws services (s3) vulnerability scans are not allowed, even on your own VPC when creating a vpc it by defaults create: ACL, SGs and a RT Egress-Only, allows vpc based ipv6 access to the internet, but prevents outisde ipv6 connections to the vpc Subneting on a VPC, the first 4 IP addrs and the latest one are reserved for AWS .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/aws-certification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/aws-certification/</guid><description> Associate arch plan and notes Check these: https://d0.awsstatic.com/training-and-certification/docs-sa-pro/AWS_certified_solutions_architect_professional_blueprint.pdf Resources to follow: http://aws.amazon.com/training/architect/ http://aws.amazon.com/whitepapers/ AWS training and certification AWS Training | Architecting Learning Path Consider for the exam AWS Services for build&amp;amp;deployments HA and Business continuity (DR) Security Networking Storage</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/cognito/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/cognito/</guid><description>Cognito Authentication &amp;amp; authorization
User management
Integration with Facebook, Google, &amp;hellip;
Also support unauthenticated users
Cognito (mobile/desktop client SDK) generates JWT that is sent to Cognito service which can be then used to auth to Facebook, Dropbox, Google, etc.
A cognito pool can assume a role or generate temporal aws credentials</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/directory-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/directory-service/</guid><description>Directory Service SSO / SAML 2.0 AWS can talk SAML2.0 from external IdPs if the SAML Assertion to be send to AWS is correct then AWS provides temporal AWS Creds (AWS STS) AD Federated users -&amp;gt; AWS SSO -&amp;gt; Dropbox, Slack, Salesforce&amp;hellip; or SAML Apps Ad Connector AD endpoints injected in a VPC via ENIs Uses an existing on-prem AD Multiple AD connections to speed and distribute load Requieres at least 2 subnets Supports network to VPN or Direct Connect Ideally works as PoC or backup for a Direct Connect Nothing is stored or acched, it just redirects AD traffic to on-prem AD servers Network becomes a single point of failure Microsoft Managed AD Microsoft 2012 R2 Managed using standard AD Tools Standard: 30k users, Enterprise: 5000k Users Radius-base MFA support By default support HA Support 1-way or 2-way trust (with on-prem) Supports AD Native scheme extensions Simple AD ?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/exam/</guid><description>AWS Exam Prep Solutions Architect Professional General knowledge from AWS needed:
Cloudformation
Hybrid scenario on-prem &amp;amp; cloud
Direct connect
AWS VPN
Migrations strategies:
snowball, site to site vpn, DX connections SMS &amp;amp; VM import/export database migrations strategies application migration service migration hub Cheapest and costly aws services
IAM
org level policies sts and iam scp vs iam policies Disaster recovery
RTO of 4 ? what does it mean? AWS Organizations</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/iam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/iam/</guid><description> IAM curl http://169.256.169.254/latest/meta-data/iam/security-credentials whill show current role curl http://169.256.169.254/latest/meta-data/iam/security-credentials/$ROLE_NAME will give current security-credentials IAM Boundaries Denies the action if something is out of Boundaries A separated iam policy just to define Boundaries Policy evaluation top-down Explicit deny SCP Resource independent policies Session policies Identity policies Tips Invalidate existing sessions: Attach an iam role Apply a Revoke Policy based on a date (iam policy conditional)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/ram/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/ram/</guid><description> RAM Resource Access Manager
Share AWS resources to different aws accounts No more of unneccesary vpc peerings Only owners of resources have ownership Can invite external organizations or local org accounts Invited cannot see who others are also part of the sharing resources Resources ids keep the same across aws accounts Invited has no ability to edit a shared resource</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/s3/</guid><description> S3 Accesses ACL for cross aws accts accs Bucket policy (cross acct and principal) IAM Role (cross acct). Single owner of bucket&amp;rsquo;s objects</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/service-quotas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/service-quotas/</guid><description> Service Quotas IAM Users has a hard limit of 5000, cannot be created more users, customers are expected to host users outside if the quota is exceeded Usually default quotas are per region, pero account Quotas can be requested for increasal Monitoring and alerting can be setup for quotas AWS Organizations: Templates creation for child aws accounts</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/vpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/vpc/</guid><description> VPC In order to connect a VPC with on-prem: Direct Connect or VPC VPC supports dhcp service VPC supports DNS NTP support Route tables High CIDRS masks have high priority Stateless Need to specify ports in and out Stateful Automatically knows what port to use as return NACL 1 per subnet Stateless it is based on rules 1 acl can be used in multiple subnets SGs Allows only, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t deny A SG can be referenced to another SG A SG can be self-referenced</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/vpn/</guid><description> VPN Site-to-site VPN Connects a VPC with on-prem subnets VGW -&amp;gt; CGW, has HA by default Works for 1.25 Gbps Costs per each Gb out/in Considered as backup of Direct Connect, means, not stable Accelerated site to site 2 IPSec Global accleration underneath Can be used only if TWG is used BGP AS / ASN It is a routing protocol BGP vs eBGP Global Accelerator Anycast ip addresses Less routers hops to reach AWS Network Works with TCP and UDP At Network Level (OSI)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/well-architected-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/well-architected-framework/</guid><description>Well architected framework The framework Collection of best practices and architectural definitions to provide a well designed cloud infrastructure based on the 5 pillars: operational excellence, security, reliability, performance efficiency and cost optimization.
Generalities design principles stop guessing your capacity needs test systems at prod scale automate to make architectural experimentatino easier allow for evolutionary architectures data-driven architecures improve through game days (I) Operational excellence (II) Security Design principles Apply security at all layers (acls, sgs, ec2) Enable traceability (cloudtrail) Automate response to security events (SNS, brute-forces) focus on securing your system automate security best practices (hardened amis) Definitions data protection Data should be segmented and classified so certain data can be only accesible by certain group of persons and no others.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/workspaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/workspaces/</guid><description> Workspaces Desktop as a service Montly and hourly payment Ad simple and Ad connector integration for User management Has its own ENI in a VPC It can connect to FSX and/or EFS Access to on-prem via VPC or Direct connect Runs on AWS Managed VPC It can connect to on-prem managed network It is not HA It only work with an existing directory service (Active Directory)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/written-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/written-notes/</guid><description> Written notes &amp;#x1f4cc; Notes from Cantril
&amp;#x1f4cc; What I&amp;rsquo;ve missed in the exacm &amp;#x1f4cc; More references
https://github.com/acantril/aws-sa-pro https://github.com/Ernyoke/certified-aws-solutions-architect-professional</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/awsiam-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/awsiam-challenge/</guid><description>AWS IAM Challenge challenge 1 All you need to is to use awscli to navigate a S3 Bucket:
aws s3 cp s3://thebigiamchallenge-storage-9979f4b/files/flag1.txt -
challenge 2 In order to pass this one you just need to pull messages from the queue:
aws sqs receive-message \ --queue-url https://sqs.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/XXXXX/XXXXX challenge 3 This policy is given, we just need to subscribe to the SNS topic and bypass the condition which is *@tbic.wiz.io.
{ &amp;#34;Version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2008-10-17&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Statement1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Statement&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;Sid&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Statement1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Effect&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Allow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Principal&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;AWS&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;*&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;Action&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SNS:Subscribe&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Resource&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;arn:aws:sns:us-east-1:123123123123:TBICWizPushNotifications&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Condition&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;StringLike&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;sns:Endpoint&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;*@tbic.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/cloudwatch/</guid><description> AWS Cloudwatch # insights LE dry-run fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /The dry run was successful/ fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /The following errors were reported by the server/ fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /ALB is not ready after 200 tries/ # insights LE real fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /Your certificate and chain have been saved at/ fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /unauthorized/ fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /Exception/</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/notes/</guid><description> AWS Notes Useful links AWS IAM Generator and Info: https://www.awsiamactions.io/</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/s3/</guid><description>S3 Bucket S3 Bucket, (0) it exists you have permissions, http404 doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, http403 it exists but you don&amp;rsquo;t have permissions aws s3api head-bucket --bucket $BUCKET_NAME</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/devops-interviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/devops-interviews/</guid><description>Devops Interviews I&amp;rsquo;m writing down for the first time the pattern I&amp;rsquo;ve found across all my interviews &amp;#x1f44d;
Currently this document is a Draft, I will keep updating this while I remember all my interview cases.
Your introduction Here you already have to have a prepared introduction, you will not be interrumped, so you will have to memorize it.
Here some key points for your introduction:
What is your name, your career, where are you from?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/daemonset/daemonset/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/daemonset/daemonset/</guid><description>Workload: Daemonset Deploying Resources Mysql ~z➤ k apply -f mysql.yml configmap/sql-create created secret/mysql-secret created service/mysql-service created statefulset.apps/mysql created Backend ~z➤ k apply -f backend.yml deployment.apps/backend-deployment created service/backend created ~z➤ k get pods NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE backend-deployment-6b77dc6779-5rznl 0/1 Init:1/2 0 2s mysql-0 1/1 Running 0 2m22s ~z➤ k get pods NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE backend-deployment-6b77dc6779-5rznl 1/1 Running 3 (33s ago) 3m8s mysql-0 1/1 Running 0 49s Frontend ~z➤ k apply -f frontend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/deployment/deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/deployment/deployment/</guid><description>Workload: Deployment Testing two docker images # Build the apps ~➤ docker build -t backend . ~➤ docker build -t frontend . # Run the apps ~z➤ docker network create dummy ~z➤ docker run --network dummy -p 3000:3000 --name backend backend # Tag and publish to docker hub docker tag backend darvein/bapp:v1 docker tag frontend darvein/fapp:v1 docker push darvein/bapp:v1 docker push darvein/fapp:v1 Deploy both apps in k8s ~z➤ kubectl apply -f backend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/jobs-cronjobs/daemonset/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/jobs-cronjobs/daemonset/</guid><description>Workload: Daemonset Deploying Resources Mysql ~z➤ k apply -f mysql.yml configmap/sql-create created secret/mysql-secret created service/mysql-service created statefulset.apps/mysql created Backend ~z➤ k apply -f backend.yml deployment.apps/backend-deployment created service/backend created ~z➤ k get pods NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE backend-deployment-6b77dc6779-5rznl 0/1 Init:1/2 0 2s mysql-0 1/1 Running 0 2m22s ~z➤ k get pods NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE backend-deployment-6b77dc6779-5rznl 1/1 Running 3 (33s ago) 3m8s mysql-0 1/1 Running 0 49s Frontend ~z➤ k apply -f frontend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/minikube/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/minikube/</guid><description>Installing minikube Needed packages: - minikube: For installation follow instructions: https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/start/ - most package managers have a binary ready to be installed on your system. - vagrant
Star up k8s cluster with minikube:
➤ minikube start --driver=virtualbox 😄 minikube v1.31.2 on Arch ✨ Using the virtualbox driver based on user configuration 💿 Downloading VM boot image ... E1005 17:51:25.025455 4640 iso.go:90] Unable to download https://storage.googleapis.com/minikube-builds/iso/16971/minikube-v1.31.0-amd64.iso: getter: &amp;amp;{Ctx:context.Background Src:https://storage.googleapis.com/minikube-builds/iso/16971/minikube-v1.31.0-amd64.iso?checksum=file:https://storage.googleapis.com/minikube-builds/iso/16971/minikube-v1.31.0-amd64.iso.sha256 Dst:/home/n0kt/.minikube/cache/iso/amd64/minikube-v1.31.0-amd64.iso.download Pwd: Mode:2 Umask:---------- Detectors:[0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640] Decompressors:map[bz2:0xc0005d3360 gz:0xc0005d3368 tar:0xc0005d3310 tar.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/statefulset/statefulset/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/statefulset/statefulset/</guid><description>Workload: Statefulset Testing two docker images # Build the apps docker build -t backend . docker build -t frontend . # Tag and publish to docker hub docker tag backend darvein/bapp:v1 docker tag frontend darvein/fapp:v1 docker push darvein/bapp:v1 docker push darvein/fapp:v1 Deploy both apps in k8s First create the SQL file as configmap:
k create configmap mysql-initdb-config --from-file=init-db.sql # Create the Mysql service k apply -f mysql.yml k apply -f backend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/network/</guid><description>Network, Ingress, Services, etc Content Network, Ingress, Services, etc Content Pods Networking Network policies for Pods: DNS Services Ingress Gateway API Pods Networking We can bootstrap kuberentes via minikube with these configs:
minikube start \ --memory=8192 --cpus=4 \ --nodes=3 \ --driver=virtualbox \ --network-plugin=cni --cni=calico \ --feature-gates=JobPodFailurePolicy=true,PodDisruptionConditions=true \ --insecure-registry &amp;#34;registry.local:5000&amp;#34; \ --container-runtime=docker \ --service-cluster-ip-range=10.96.0.0/12 \ --extra-config=controller-manager.cluster-cidr=10.244.0.0/16 \ --extra-config=controller-manager.node-cidr-mask-size-ipv4=24 Highlights:
cluster-cidr: CIDR where pods will be deployed service-cluster-ip-range: ClusterIP for services Kube-proxy on each node receives traffic from the service-cluster-ip-range and forwards to the backend pods.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/security/</guid><description>Kubernetes security In a nutshell these are the most important aspects to consider:
Cloud security Cluster security Network security Container security Secrets Management Cloud security The documentation mention the 4Cs:
Cloud: best practices Cluster: control plane protection, encryption, security policies Container: image scanners, pod security Code: dynamic attack testing, static analyzis In case of AWS what security involves:
IAM: users, groups, roles, policies Networking: VPC security-groups, NACLs, AWS Shield Data encryption: KMS, in-transit (tls/ssl, vpn) Monitoring and Logging: Cloudwatch , Cloudtrail Etc: Guarduty, AWS Config, SCPs Cluster Security Node security Some Node security best practices</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/storage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/storage/</guid><description>Storage Volumes Containers state are ephemeral, once the container is terminated then the Controller will recreate the container but data from the crashed/deleted container is lost. We can persist the container or containers data by using Volumes, but it will last only while the Pod is alive, once the Pod is eliminated then the volume is gone.
More references: kubectl explain pod.spec.volumes Pod have shared filesystem so all containers can share the files with a volume Ephemeral Volumes: emptyDir, configMap, secrets Persistent Volumes: hostPath, local, ebs (aws), etc Mount propagation: Which can be None, HostToContainer, Bidirectional.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/workloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/workloads/</guid><description>Workloads Objects in kubernetes Pods have unique name All k8s objects have an UID labels and selectors to tag and organize objects, helpful from cli or UI. kubectl get pods -l environment=production,tier=frontend kubectl get pods -l 'environment,environment notin (frontend)' Recommended labels: app.kubernetes.io/name: mysql app.kubernetes.io/instance: mysql-abcxzy app.kubernetes.io/version: &amp;#34;5.7.21&amp;#34; app.kubernetes.io/component: database app.kubernetes.io/part-of: wordpress app.kubernetes.io/managed-by: helm Namespaces, are used as environments (useful to allocate users via Resource Quota) DNS when creating a service: &amp;lt;service-name&amp;gt;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/k8s-doc/01.architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/k8s-doc/01.architecture/</guid><description>Kubernetes Architecture Kubernetes Components Master: Components:
API Server Cloud Controller (optional) Controller Manager Etcd Scheduler Nodes: Components:
Kubelet Kube-proxy This is where workloads are deployed and run.
Nodes have:
Status Heartbeats Node Controller (on control plane) Eviction Limits (?) Node topology Graceful node shutdown Kubelete and Kube-proxy are the components that interact with k8s API in control plane via HTTPS.
Other components of a Node:
Cgroupv2: based on linux cgroups Container Runtime: docker, runc?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/k8s-doc/02.workloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/k8s-doc/02.workloads/</guid><description>Workloads https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/ All the different ways we have to run applications in kubernetes. The workloads.
These are:
Pods Deployments ReplicatSet StatefulSet DaemonSet Jobs CronJobs Pod These are ephimeral objects. Once stopped the storage is gone, the ip address is gone.
The different phase of a pod lifecycle are: Pending, Running, Succeeded, Failed and Unknown.
Also the container lifecycle phases: Waiting, Running, Terminated.
Here we can see all the Pod spec fields available:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/readme/</guid><description>Kubernetes Notes Index This repo contains my notes and laboratorious on Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/archlinux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/archlinux/</guid><description> Arch Linux Notes Notes when installing Arch Linux.
alias archinstall=&amp;#39;sudo yay -S&amp;#39; # Monitoring btop # Coding nvim # Multimedia pulsemixer # Others nerd-fonts redshift zplug zsh patat-bin lolcat glow gron ffmpegthumbnailer tumbler nomacs android-apktool jadx exploitdb evil-winrm mycli mediainfo pirate-get copyq Pip pipx install certipy-ad</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/battery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/battery/</guid><description>Linux Battery Administration LTP LTP is one of the most commons to analyze and manage battery usage in a laptop computer.
yay -S ltp systemctl enable ltp
Here an config example for /etc/ltp.d/01-custom.conf
# TLP Configuration - Optimized for use with auto-cpufreq # Avoid changing CPU settings to prevent conflicts with auto-cpufreq # CPU_SCALING_GOVERNOR_ON_AC=performance # CPU_SCALING_GOVERNOR_ON_BAT=powersave # CPU_HWP_ON_AC=balance_performance # CPU_HWP_ON_BAT=balance_power # Disk Devices: Set disk APM level on battery to 128 and enable spin down after 10 seconds DISK_APM_LEVEL_ON_BAT=&amp;#34;128&amp;#34; DISK_IDLE_SECS_ON_BAT=10 # SATA aggressive link power management (ALPM): # min_power for battery, medium_power for AC SATA_LINKPWR_ON_AC=medium_power SATA_LINKPWR_ON_BAT=min_power # Runtime Power Management for PCI(e) devices RUNTIME_PM_ON_AC=on RUNTIME_PM_ON_BAT=auto # USB autosuspend feature USB_AUTOSUSPEND=1 # Disable Wake On LAN WOL_DISABLE=Y # Wi-Fi Power Saving mode: 1=disable, 5=enable WIFI_PWR_ON_AC=off WIFI_PWR_ON_BAT=on # Bluetooth power saving BLUETOOTH_DISABLE_ON_BAT=1 # Disable autosuspend for specified devices, e.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/iptables_tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/iptables_tips/</guid><description>IPTables cheatsheet ## Centos 7 iptables systemctl stop firewalld systemctl mask firewalld systemctl enable iptables yum install iptables-services systemctl enable iptables systemctl [stop|start|restart] iptables chkconfig --level 345 iptables on iptables -L -n -v iptables -F service iptables save iptables-save ## FLUSH de reglas iptables -F iptables -X iptables -Z iptables -t nat -F iptables -L -n -v ## FLush rules on centos cat /etc/sysconfig/iptables iptables -F iptables -L service iptables save service iptables stop service iptables start cat /etc/sysconfig/iptables iptables -L ## Establecemos politica por defecto iptables -P INPUT ACCEPT iptables -P OUTPUT ACCEPT iptables -P FORWARD ACCEPT iptables -t nat -P PREROUTING ACCEPT iptables -t nat -P POSTROUTING ACCEPT ## Empezamos a filtrar # El localhost se deja (por ejemplo conexiones locales a mysql) /sbin/iptables -A INPUT -i lo -j ACCEPT # A nuestra IP le dejamos todo iptables -A INPUT -s 195.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/sudo-linux/sudo-linux-darvein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/sudo-linux/sudo-linux-darvein/</guid><description>Sudo resume Sudo is a program that allow an user to run a command as another user, usually superuser sudo is not su, sudo requires user&amp;rsquo;s password sudo activities are logged in systemd (journalctl) By default sudo invocation rights last 5 minutes openbsd has doas, windows as runas /etc/sudoers Config file is located at /etc/sudoers. The tool visudo edits sudoers file in a safe manner: syntax check and locks</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/systemctl_cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/systemctl_cheatsheet/</guid><description> Systemctl cheatsheet # Check logs for a particular service journalctl -u service-name.service</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/mysql/mysql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/mysql/mysql/</guid><description>Mysql tips Create user in AWS RDS and grant permissions like a master
CREATE USER &amp;#39;jacob&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;%&amp;#39; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;xxxxxxxx&amp;#39;; GRANT SELECT,INSERT,UPDATE,DELETE,DROP on synapbox_qa.* TO &amp;#39;jacob&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;%&amp;#39;; or GRANT SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE, CREATE, DROP, RELOAD, PROCESS, REFERENCES, INDEX, ALTER, SHOW DATABASES, CREATE TEMPORARY TABLES, LOCK TABLES, EXECUTE, REPLICATION SLAVE, REPLICATION CLIENT, CREATE VIEW, SHOW VIEW, CREATE ROUTINE, ALTER ROUTINE, CREATE USER, EVENT, TRIGGER, LOAD FROM S3, SELECT INTO S3, INVOKE LAMBDA ON synapbox_qa.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/nginx/nginx-certbot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/nginx/nginx-certbot/</guid><description>Nginx and certbot sudo apt update sudo apt install -f certbot python3-certbot-nginx nginx sudo certbot --nginx -d acme.net -d www.acme.net sudo vim /etc/nginx/sites-available/acme.net #Successfully received certificate. #Certificate is saved at: /etc/letsencrypt/live/acme.net/fullchain.pem #Key is saved at: /etc/letsencrypt/live/acme.net/privkey.pem sudo crontab -e 0 1 * * * /usr/bin/certbot renew --quiet Nginx config:
client_max_body_size 100M; # Enable gzip compression #gzip on; gzip_vary on; gzip_proxied any; gzip_comp_level 6; gzip_types text/plain text/css text/xml application/json application/javascript application/rss+xml application/atom+xml image/svg+xml; # Cache settings proxy_cache_path /var/cache/nginx levels=1:2 keys_zone=my_cache:10m max_size=1g inactive=60m; proxy_cache_key &amp;#34;$scheme$request_method$host$request_uri&amp;#34;; server { listen 80; server_name acme.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/compressions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/compressions/</guid><description>Compression notes There are different ways to compress in a linux environment with general compression algorithms and so.
Tar and GZIP tar:
GNU &amp;rsquo;tar&amp;rsquo; saves many files together into a single tape or disk archive, and can restore individual files from the archive.
gzip
Compress or uncompress FILEs (by default, compress FILES in-place).
Both are different tools, but tar can call bzip in order to compress an archived file.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/elasticsearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/elasticsearch/</guid><description>Elasticsearch cheatsheet export HST=https://elasticsearch.devbox-apps.acme.com # see why not allocate shareds curl -s -XGET localhost:9200/_cluster/allocation/explain?pretty # check unallocated shareds curl -s -XGET localhost:9200/_cat/shards? # check installed plugins curl -X GET &amp;#34;localhost:9200/_cat/plugins?v&amp;amp;s=component&amp;amp;h=name,component,version,description&amp;amp;pretty&amp;#34; # check ES health curl -sX GET &amp;#34;$HST/_cluster/health&amp;#34; | jq curl -sX GET &amp;#34;https://vpc-msops-es-cluster-edwk7ppi4dw5gkcpqbqangmbvm.us-west-2.es.amazonaws.com/_cluster/health&amp;#34; | jq # stats curl -X GET &amp;#34;localhost:9200/_nodes/stats&amp;#34; | jq curl -X GET &amp;#34;localhost:9200/_nodes/stats/indices&amp;#34; | jq curl -X GET &amp;#34;http://localhost:9200/_stats?all=true&amp;#34; | jq # List indexes curl -s &amp;#34;$HST/_aliases?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/others-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/others-tools/</guid><description>Other useful tools Table of Content Other useful tools Table of Content Content My bash aliases Devops Coding Infosec More Arch packages Content My bash aliases _s: Chatgpt3 + Azure cognitive search _sc: Chatgpt3 _ddgr: Search on Duckduckgo, put 9 results on nvim buffers _web: Get a web page and load it on nvim _tvim: copy/paste current terminal buffer to nvim _dbox_share: Share local file and get a Dropbox URL _twitter: Search something on twitter ( https://github.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/ranger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/ranger/</guid><description> Ranger - file navigator in terminal Tips oa # sort by time os # sort by size Mh # show human-readable date Mp # show permissions yp # yank full path of current file Shift+S # exit ranger on the current new directory Resources ranger cheatsheet: https://dquinton.github.io/debian-install/files/ranger-keybinds_quinton.pdf</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/ssl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/ssl/</guid><description>SSL Cheatsheet # View single certificate echo | openssl s_client -showcerts -servername [gnupg.org](http://gnupg.org) -connect [gnupg.org:443](http://gnupg.org:443) 2&amp;gt;/dev/null | openssl x509 -inform pem -noout -text | tee output.log openssl pkcs7 -print_certs -in old.p7b -out new.crt # openssl pkcs7 -print_certs -in old.p7b -out new.cer # generate RSA public/private key openssl genrsa -des3 -out darvein.pem 2048 # export RSA public key openssl rsa -in private.pem -outform PEM -pubout -out public.pem # export RSA private key openssl rsa -in private.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/tcpdump/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/tcpdump/</guid><description>Tcpdump tcpdump sniff on docker containers Check first the container ip address: docker inspect $container Get the interface network ifconfig | less Then TCPDump it: # This is an nginx container sudo tcpdump -i br-11a73f6ac535 -A -p -s 0 -l -vv -nn &amp;#39;host 172.22.0.50&amp;#39; # GET|POST packets sudo tcpdump -i br-11a73f6ac535 -A -p -s 0 -l -vv -nn &amp;#39;tcp[((tcp[12:1] &amp;amp; 0xf0) &amp;gt;&amp;gt; 2):4] = 0x47455420&amp;#39; # Receive on django sudo tcpdump -i br-11a73f6ac535 -A -p -l -vvvs 1500 -nn -SX &amp;#39;src 172.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/tmux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/tmux/</guid><description> Tmux tips # General shortcuts prefix + u # urls picker prefix + C # new session with custom name prefix + c # new session prefix + I # install plugins prefix + f # open files prefix + , # rename current window # copycat prefix + ctrl-f - simple file search prefix + ctrl-g - jumping over git status files (best used after git status command) prefix + alt-h - jumping over SHA-1/SHA-256 hashes (best used after git log command) prefix + ctrl-u - url search (http, ftp and git urls) prefix + ctrl-d - number search (mnemonic d, as digit) prefix + alt-i - ip address search</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/vim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/vim/</guid><description>Vim tips Content Vim tips Content Motions Moving things around Edits Files Buffers Search Commands Powerful plugins Git mkdx Copilot Folding Motions ciw: Change the inner word dwi: Delete current word and enter edit mode d$ or D: delete all after current position $: go to the last char normal-mode w and b: move a word forward or backwards daw: delete from the current char til the first letter on next word d9w: delete 9 words dap: delete around paragraph dd: delete a line 2dd: delete two lines u and ctrl+o: undo and redo editions 4gt: Go to Tab number 4 more of this:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/postgres/postgres_cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/postgres/postgres_cheatsheet/</guid><description>Postgresql general cheatsheet General \dt # list all tables \l # list all databases \d # describe table #ssh jumpbox: ssh -i ~/.ssh/devops-synapbox.pem -N -L 5432:synapbox-dev-postgresql.cluster-ro-cxt0zmlbsvfo.us-west-2.rds.amazonaws.com:5432 ec2-user@52.24.146.217 Export and import database pg_dump -h $HOST -U $USER -W -F t $DBNAME &amp;gt; dump.tar pg_restore -h $HOST -d $DBNAME dump.tar -c -U $USER Misc # create user and database sudo su - postgres createuser dennis createdb -O dennis dennis # test user psql -h localhost -d dennis -U dennis -W psql -h localhost -d postgres -U postgres -W psql -h 192.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/postgres/psql_sqls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/postgres/psql_sqls/</guid><description> cheatsheet psql remove all tables in the current schema DO $$ DECLARE r RECORD; BEGIN FOR r IN (SELECT tablename FROM pg_tables WHERE schemaname = current_schema()) LOOP EXECUTE &amp;#39;DROP TABLE IF EXISTS &amp;#39; || quote_ident(r.tablename) || &amp;#39; CASCADE&amp;#39;; END LOOP; END $$;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/bash-vs-zsh/bash-zsh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/bash-vs-zsh/bash-zsh/</guid><description>Bash vz ZSH title: Bash vs ZSH author: Dennis Ruiz date: 22/10/21 theme: Copenhagen Shell features Shell feature:
Jobs Input, Output and redirections Aliases History Completion Wildcard and expansiosn config files bash:
/etc/profile /etc/bash.bashrc ~/.bashrc ~/.bash_profile ~/.bash_login ~/.profile ~/.bash_logout zsh:
/etc/zsh/zshenv ~/.zshenv /etc/zsh/zprofile ~/.zprofile /etc/zsh/zshrc ~/.zshrc /etc/zsh/zlogin ~/.zlogin ~/.zlogout /etc/zsh/zlogout Global qualifiers ls **/*.(dll|py) # list the 3rd file ls *(.[3]) # match files only, no dirs, no special files du -h *(.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/intro-linux-shell/intro-linux-shell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/intro-linux-shell/intro-linux-shell/</guid><description>Trivial question title: Introduction to Linux Shell author: Dennis Ruiz date: 7/3/21 theme: Copenhagen Why does sudo id works and sudo cd does not?
Why does sudo id works and sudo cd does not?
Because cd is a builtin command not a program (executable).
$ compgen -b jobs exit bg pwd source eval alias cd export echo wait kill fg ... What is a Linux shell? It is a command-line interpreter software that can be interactive or scripted.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/jenkins-lab/jenkins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/jenkins-lab/jenkins/</guid><description>Jenkins overview &amp;amp; installation Jenkins is an automation server.
We can use it to automate almost anything we need or want.
Continuous integration jobs Continuous delivery jobs Ad-hoc jobs Jenkins installer can be found for:
Docker Kubernetes Linux macOS WAR files Windows Single ad-hoc jobs Freestyle Pipeline (declarative) Pipeline from a git repository Multi-branch pipeline Secrets management Stores sensitive information:
SSH Keys Certificates Passwords, Tokens Jenkins slaves Static slave Global configuration tool AWS EC2 Auto-provisioning slaves Slack notifications Jenkins pipelines Scripted vs Declarative Questions &amp;amp; Answers Time for questions!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/productivity/productivity-talk-darvein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/productivity/productivity-talk-darvein/</guid><description>Productivity 101 Being productive is to regulary produce something desired or expected in a timely manner.
Acceptable results and satisfaction can be considered a way to measure success.
Resources and priorities First of all, size and measure mentally what you will do and how you will do it:
::: columns :::: column
Resources Costs Time Quality :::: :::: column
Priority Urgent Important :::: ::: We can&amp;rsquo;t always have high quality, cheap and fast, we have to trade off resources.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/terraform/talk-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/terraform/talk-terraform/</guid><description>Terraform talk (30min) Topics to cover: what is for terraform How it works TF main parts (provider, resources, variables, outputs, backend, templates/data, provisioners, null_resource, data+program+bash, ) Where not to use it / when to use it Syntax and programming + tricks (variables types,maps,locals, tulle, objects) Logic: loops, conditionals, TF env vars for vars Modules usage and creation Terraform registry Workspaces Remote states Secrets Locking state (s3, dynamodb) Integrations: Vault, ansible, chef, packer, user data , aws secrets, Terraform and docker (ECS/EKS) Terraform and machine learning?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/terraform/terraform_basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/terraform/terraform_basics/</guid><description> Terraform basics How to terraform import Link: https://www.dropbox.com/s/qdlgiytja6u3adc/2022-09-13_19-52-07.mp4?dl=0&amp;amp;dl=0</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/webapps/wordpress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/webapps/wordpress/</guid><description>Wordpress Content Installation Given an Ubuntu 22.04 Machine
sudo apt update sudo apt-get upgrade -y sudo apt install -f php-fpm nfs-kernel-server nginx php-mysql sudo apt install -f php8.1-mysql php8.1-mbstring php8.1-xml php8.1-curl sudo apt install -f memcached libmemcached-tools -y Check the nginx config:
client_max_body_size 50M; server { listen 80; listen [::]:80; root /var/www/acme.com/html; server_name _; index index.php; charset utf-8; access_log /var/log/nginx/wordpress_access.log; error_log /var/log/nginx/wordpress_error.log; location / { try_files $uri $uri/ /index.php?$args; } location ~ \.</description></item></channel></rss>