<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Darvein</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/</link><description>Recent content on Darvein</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.darvein.net/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/books_todos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/books_todos/</guid><description>Books TODOs Board TODOs Book: To kill a mockingbird, Harper Lee Audiobook: Frankenstein By Mary Shelley (fiction) Book: Sigma (terminar de leer y documentar) Audiobook: Santa Biblia - Reina Valera 2000 DOCUMENTAR Audiobook: Rich Dad Poor Dad By Robert T. Kiyosaki DOCUMENTAR Audiobook: The 4-Hour Workweek: Escape 9-5, Live Anywhere, and Join the New Rich (Expanded and Updated) By Timothy Ferriss DOCUMENTAR Book: The alchemist, Paolo Cohelo DOCUMENTAR Kindle: Clean Book: El Aleph Book: The Game: Penetrating the Secret Society Book scifi: 1984, George Orwell Kindle: Ragnarok Kindle: Men Without Women Kindle: A Clockwork Orange Book: Meditaciones de marco Aurelio Book: Cartas a lucilio de Seneca Book: Enquiridion de epicteto Search books &amp;ldquo;Critical Thinking&amp;rdquo; Jerry tennant, healing is voltage Kids Crónicas de Narnia &amp;#x1f517; https://telegra.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/4-hour-week/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/4-hour-week/</guid><description>Book: 4 hour week work first and foremost escape night to five, no retirement people don&amp;rsquo;t want to be millionaires they want to experience definiton, elimination, automation, liberation. Deal d is for definition mini retirements
do what you like,work for you
have others working for you
be owner, not the boss or employee
pay day everyday goal
don&amp;rsquo;t fool yourself!
ability to choose!
everything popular is wrong
retirement is not a goal, is the worst case scenario</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/rich-dad-poor-dad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/rich-dad-poor-dad/</guid><description>Book: Rich Dad Poor Dad Notes Aprender contabilidad Educación fundamento profundo para flexibilidad
Rules: Saber asset vs lialabilities: asset richs, liability poors
Chap3 Focus on assets rather than income No debts no credit cards
Chap4 Capitaliam vs government socialists Gobernment, employes, and banks take a big share With no knowledge power the world pushes you around More employees to get more assetsp
Accounting skill Investing Understand market The lawsuits, protect assets</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/zero-to-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/zero-to-one/</guid><description>Zero to one - Peter Thiel Información Breve.
Info Value Autor Peter Thiel y Blake Masters Fecha 2014 Formato Físico Notas Chapter 1: The challenge of the future
Monopolios y competencia: Thiel sostiene que los monopolios son buenos para la innovación y que la competencia puede ser perjudicial, ya que las empresas pueden quedar atrapadas en una lucha constante por el mercado, sin enfocarse en ideas nuevas y transformadoras. La ley de las startups: Thiel propone que una startup debe centrarse en un mercado pequeño y nicho antes de expandirse a mercados más grandes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/mastering-python-networking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/mastering-python-networking/</guid><description>Mastering Python Networking - Eric Chou empty</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/python-crash-course/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/python-crash-course/</guid><description>Python Crash Course empty</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/violent-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/violent-python/</guid><description> Violent Python - O-connor</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/book-project-phoenix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/book-project-phoenix/</guid><description> Project phoenix Things to research theory of constraints Toyota production system lean principles and concepts References ITIL reference The goal (book) Notes of the book Types of work
business requirements internal team tasks change tasks unplanned/firefighting work</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/devops-handbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/devops-handbook/</guid><description>Devops Handbook Book: devops handbook notes
Velocity conference materials Points
Developers: respond to rapid market change IT Ops: protects prod envs having stable, secure and reliable envs Book to read: the mythical man-month Lean manfuctaring principles Book: the goal: a process of ongoing improvement Three ways devops
Flow: CI/CD smooth Feedback Learning experiments Intro Problem: misaligned internal goals
Developers: respond to the rapidly changing competitive landscape It: provide stable, reliable and secure service to the customer Which causes daily workaround, firefighting on different areas PM, Development.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/unix-linux-system-admin/ch2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/unix-linux-system-admin/ch2/</guid><description>Chapter 2 This document is a summary of my own notes on this book.
Boot process Bootstrap process overview:
BIOS vs UEFI? meh&amp;hellip;
Init Variants?: SystemV init, SystemV upstart
Ubuntu 14 running init:
vagrant@worker:~$ ps -fp 1 UID PID PPID C STIME TTY TIME CMD root 1 0 0 03:46 ? 00:00:00 /sbin/init vagrant@worker:~$ /sbin/init --version init (upstart 1.12.1) Copyright (C) 2006-2014 Canonical Ltd., 2011 Scott James Remnant Exploring units:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/unix-linux-system-admin/ch3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/unix-linux-system-admin/ch3/</guid><description>Chapter 3 System has users and groups Everything is a file: processes, devices, network connections and have uid/gid
root is always 0, gid 0, users starts from 1000
su != sudo
setuid and setgid setuid and setgid: Runs with pre-defined uid/gid instead of the runner user&amp;rsquo;s uid/gid https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/setuid-setgid-and-sticky-bits-in-linux-file-permissions/ sudo /etc/sudoers
sudoreplay Defaults log_output Defaults!/usr/bin/sudoreplay !log_output Defaults!/sbin/reboot !log_output visudo
Disable root account with /bin/false /bin/nonlogin on /etc/passwd
PAM PAM: single-signon Kerberos: network crypto auth (part of AD)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/fiction/i-robot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/fiction/i-robot/</guid><description>I Robot by Asimov I enjoyed this book a lot!. It caught my attention many times, I fall into the stories on how a robot can really care about us (humans) to the point to lie to us, to hide us information and even control our future, just for the sake of our wellbeing. Robots are designed and built with heavy emphasis of the 3 Robots Laws.
A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/infosec/the-web-application-hackers-handbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/infosec/the-web-application-hackers-handbook/</guid><description>The web application Hackers Handbook Second Edition.
Finding and Exploiting Security Flaws.
By Dafydd Stuttard.
Chapter 1 Web applications are everywhere.
The most common web vulnz:
Cross-site scripting Cross-site request forgery Information leakage Broken access controls Broken authentication SQL Injection Chapter 2 Most web apps ensures security controls with: Authentication, Access Control and Session Management.
As general rule, untrust all user input data. Always sanitize the INPUT as well as the OUTPUT content.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/atomic-habits/</guid><description>Atomic Habits tiny changes make a big difference the quality of our lives depend on the quality of our habits
to write a great book you have to become the book
results doesn&amp;rsquo;t come quickly, habits are dismissed bcoz of that
small changes can really impact in the future for good or bad
pay attention to your life trajectory no that much on the results
in order to see results persistence is needed</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/sigma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/sigma/</guid><description>SIGMA: Mentalidad para un mundo caótico Este libro resume algunos otros libros sobre el la consientización del valor del hombre hoy en día en base a la historia, biología y naturaleza del mismo en una sociedad que busca aprovecharse de él.
Puntos clave del libro Vive con tus propias relgas y valores, no las del sistema o sociedad El hombre es demigrado en la mente de las personas, todos están en tu contra Se el centro del universo para ti, ponte en primer lugar no mires a otros, no te preocupes por las noticias, olvida todo, tu eres lo primero, tu eres la novedad, tu eres lo importante No busques felicidad busca estar orgulloso de tus logros Los alfas caen atrapados en matrimonios y los beta buscan ser esclavos El hombre no pide permiso ni perdón, toma lo que quiere del mundo Si el enemigo no te teme entonces como podría respetarte?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/the-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/the-game/</guid><description> The Game - Penetrating the Secret Society</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/readings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/readings/</guid><description>Kids Readings Coco y la luna TBD
El perro y la cometa magica Érase una vez un perro conocido por sus grandes dotes artísticas. Aquel perro era un auténtico fabricante de sueños y de alegrías, gracias a las cometas artesanales que fabricaba. Preciosas estelas que surcaban el cielo tiñéndolo de deliciosos colores.
¡Era tan feliz haciendo lo que hacía! Haciendo feliz a montones de niños que, boquiabiertos con las cometas, conseguían convencer a sus padres para llevarse una y hacerla volar al aire libre.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/religion/biblia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/religion/biblia/</guid><description> Biblia Reyna Valera Overview Antiguo testamento antes de Jesucristo. Nuevo Testamente después de Jesucristo Torah, Coran y Antiguo testamento son similares. Algunos libros son los mismos Nuevo testamento: apóstoles de Jesucrísto, fundaciones de la iglesia y fin de los tiempos Antiguo Testamento Genesis: Abraham -&amp;gt; Isaac -&amp;gt; Jacob -&amp;gt; ??</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/tech/staring-into-the-singularity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/tech/staring-into-the-singularity/</guid><description>Staring into the singularity 1.2.5 by Eliezer Yudkowsky (article) Source: https://web.archive.org/web/20070613184827/http://yudkowsky.net/singularity.html This article talks about what is the Singularity in technology and how inevitable it is. Given the common sense of math and human evolution, we should reach a point where Artificial Intelligence, Augemented Intelligence or Superintelligent humans (neuron-to-sillicon interfaces) will exist and will enhance themselfs better than ourselves.
It talks about definitions of Smartness and Perceptual Transcends which is basically based on our experience and general knowledge on what we understand our current reality.</description></item></channel></rss>