<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Darvein</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/</link><description>Recent content on Darvein</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.darvein.net/lang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/en/english-basic-4-weeks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/en/english-basic-4-weeks/</guid><description>English basic in 4 weeks This is aimed to help you learn english in a fast way 100% intense, designed to be applied for 1 month (4-5 weeks).
Everything will be needed here:
Resources: Chatgpt, Google, Youtube, Instagram, Computer, Pen&amp;amp;Paper Yourself: Good sleep, healthy food, 100% focus and attention Vocabulary words:
Office Movies Restaurant Concert Zoo This is the roadmap:
Semana 1: Fundamentos Básicos Conversacion: Saludos básicos o Introducciones personales Revisión de adverbios y preposiciones en inglés.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/en/english-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/en/english-notes/</guid><description>English notes &amp;#x1f1fa;&amp;#x1f1f8; Resources to learn Duolingo! Online resource: &amp;#x1f517; https://www.essentialenglish.review/apps/english-grammar-in-use-with-answers https://www.esl-lab.com/easy/ https://www.bbc.co.uk/learningenglish/english/ English Grammar lessons: &amp;#x1f517; essentialenglish.review (read, document) Advanced english vocabulary: https://open.spotify.com/playlist/68XG5ir68L5IMzwDUKj9ui Study english for free: https://www.englisch-hilfen.de/en/ English free online: https://www.englishpage.com/ Song: clean eastwood song Readings [Kids] Where the Wild Things Are by Maurice Sendak: &amp;#x1f517; https://addi.ehu.es/bitstream/handle/10810/30027/JT_Where%20the%20Wild%20Things%20Are.pdf [Comic] The Amazing Spider-Man Collection Movies Beavis &amp;amp; Butthead ( imdb ) The Scene (2004-2006) ( imdb ), youtube The Simpsons ( imdb ) Mind your language: imdb Music Eminem Reading local ├── Basic English Grammar, Book 1[A4].</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/fr/french-basic-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/fr/french-basic-roadmap/</guid><description>Bases de la feuille de route française Grettings Hello: Bonjour (bone-zhoor) Good evening: Bonsoir (bone-swahr) Goodbye: Au revoir (oh ruh-vwahr) Thank you: Merci (mehr-see) You&amp;rsquo;re welcome: De rien (duh ree-uhn); Je vous en prie (zhuh voo zahn pree) Sorry: Pardon (pahr-dohn); Désolé(e) (day-zoh-lay) Excuse me: Excusez-moi (ex-kew-zay mwah) Yes: Oui (wee) No: Non (nohn) How are you?: Comment ça va? (koh-mahn sah vah); Comment allez-vous? (koh-mahn tah-ley voo) I&amp;rsquo;m fine: Ça va bien (sah vah byahn); Je vais bien (zhuh vay byahn) What is your name?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/fr/french-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/fr/french-notes/</guid><description>Notes de langue française &amp;#x1f1eb;&amp;#x1f1f7; Resources Duolingo! https://francais.lingolia.com/en/ https://www.thoughtco.com/french-4133079 https://langue-francaise.tv5monde.com/ https://francaisfacile.rfi.fr/en/exercices/ Listening: https://www.youtube.com/@FrancaisavecPierre CLI Examples: trans -b -p en:fr 'french basics' Apprendre la grammaire française et s’exercer: &amp;#x1f517; francais.lingolia.com (read, document) https://www.lepointdufle.net/p/grammaire.htm https://www.gymglish.com/fr/frantastique-orthographe/grammaire-francaise https://open.spotify.com/show/6YqgG1UezfW9khCvLh8rvw?si=d6799e9926d64c5f Breathless (1960), Jean-Luc Godard Movie: The 400 Blows (1959), by François Truffaut Readings [Kids] Le petit prince: &amp;#x1f517; pdf1 , pdf2 Movies La haine, 1995 imdb Music Stromae ( spotify ) Louane ( spotify ) Zez Christophe Maé General Basic Roadmap Consider these points:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/jp/basic-japanese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/jp/basic-japanese/</guid><description> 日本 Resources Duolingo! https://www.nhk.or.jp/lesson/ja/ https://open.spotify.com/playlist/2grEO8M5oo1xsjNU9LRyqW https://www.tofugu.com/learn-japanese/ https://tsunagarujp.bunka.go.jp/level01/a01 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rZTN5QG0nUM https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6p9Il_j0zjc&amp;amp;list=WL&amp;amp;index=212 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6p9Il_j0zjc&amp;amp;list=WL&amp;amp;index=175&amp;amp;t=297s Readings 鬼滅の刃 bookwalker Death Note: JP Bookwalker Movies Anything from Ghibli かぐや姫の物語 ( ghibli ) Music Yutaka Ozaki: spotify Song: Forget me not, Yutaka. lyrics - youtube Reading local ├── Genki - Elementary Japanese II.pdf ├── Genki I - textboock.pdf</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/ru/basic-russian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/ru/basic-russian/</guid><description>Russian Basics &amp;#x1f1f7;&amp;#x1f1fa; Resources Movie: Battleship Potemkin (1925) - Directed by Sergei Eisenstein Solaris (1972) - Directed by Andrei Tarkovsky Moscow Does Not Believe in Tears (1980) - Directed by Vladimir Menshov Come and See (1985) - Directed by Elem Klimov Stalker (1979) - Directed by Andrei Tarkovsky Greetings trans -b -p en:zh-CN hello
Hello: Здравствуйте (Zdravstvuyte) Hi / Bye: Привет / Пока (Privet / Poka) - informal Goodbye: До свидания (Do svidaniya) Thank you: Спасибо (Spasibo) You&amp;rsquo;re welcome: Пожалуйста (Pozhaluysta) Sorry / Excuse me: Извините (Izvinite) Yes: Да (Da) No: Нет (Nyet) How are you?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-15night-yutaka-ozaki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-15night-yutaka-ozaki/</guid><description>JP: 尾崎豊 - 15の夜 &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yu88zx_--wE Translation: https://lyricstranslate.com/en/juugo-no-yoru-night-night-fifteen-years-old.html Hiragana:
落書きの教科書と外ばかり見てる俺 超高層ビルの上の空 届かない夢を見てる やりばのない気持の扉破りたい 校舎の裏 煙草をふかして見つかれば逃げ場もない しゃがんでかたまり 背を向けながら 心のひとつも解りあえない大人達をにらむ そして仲間達は今夜家出の計画をたてる とにかくもう 学校や家には帰りたくない 自分の存在が何なのかさえ 解らず震えている 15の夜 盗んだバイクで走り出す 行き先も解らぬまま 暗い夜の帳りの中へ 誰にも縛られたくないと 逃げ込んだこの夜に 自由になれた気がした 15の夜 冷たい風 冷えた躰 人恋しくて 夢見てるあの娘の家の横を サヨナラつぶやき走り抜ける 闇の中 ぽつんと光る 自動販売機 100円玉で買えるぬくもり 熱い缶コーヒー握りしめ 恋の結末も解らないけど あの娘と俺は将来さえ ずっと夢に見てる 大人達は心を捨てろ捨てろと言うが 俺はいやなのさ 退屈な授業が俺達の全てならば なんてちっぽけで なんて意味のない なんて無力な 15の夜 盗んだバイクで走り出す 行き先も解らぬまま 暗い夜の帳りの中へ 覚えたての煙草をふかし 星空を見つめながら 自由を求め続けた 15の夜 盗んだバイクで走り出す 行き先も解らぬまま 暗い夜の帳りの中へ 誰にも縛られたくないと 逃げ込んだこの夜に 自由になれた気がした 15の夜 https://lyricstranslate.com Romanji</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-carla-lexcessive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-carla-lexcessive/</guid><description>FR: Carla Bruni - L&amp;rsquo;excessive &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2K5n2nRtF0c Je n&amp;#39;ai pas d&amp;#39;excuse C&amp;#39;est inexplicable Même inexorable C&amp;#39;est pas pour l&amp;#39;extase C&amp;#39;est que l&amp;#39;existence Sans un peu d&amp;#39;extrême Est inacceptable J&amp;#39;suis excessive J&amp;#39;aime quand ça désaxe Quand tout accélère Moi je reste relax J&amp;#39;suis excessive Quand tout explose Quand la vie s&amp;#39;exhibe C&amp;#39;est une transe exquise Y en a qu&amp;#39;ça excède, d&amp;#39;autres que ça vexe Y en a qui exigent que j&amp;#39;revienne dans l&amp;#39;axe Y en a qui s&amp;#39;exclament que c&amp;#39;est un complexe Y en a qui s&amp;#39;excitent avec tous ces X dans l&amp;#39;texte J&amp;#39;suis excessive J&amp;#39;aime quand ça désaxe Quand tout accélère Moi je reste relax J&amp;#39;suis excessive Quand tout explose Quand la vie s&amp;#39;exhibe C&amp;#39;est une transe exquise, oui J&amp;#39;suis excessive J&amp;#39;aime quand ça désaxe Quand tout exagère Moi je reste relax J&amp;#39;suis excessive Excessivement gaie Excessivement triste C&amp;#39;est là que j&amp;#39;existe Pas d&amp;#39;excuse (pas d&amp;#39;excuse) Translation</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-edith-no-regret/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-edith-no-regret/</guid><description> FR: Edith Piaf - Non, je ne regrette rien &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: Edith Piaf - Non, je ne regrette rien Non, rien de rien Non, je ne regrette rien Ni le bien qu&amp;#39;on m&amp;#39;a fait Ni le mal Tout ça m&amp;#39;est bien égal Non, rien de rien Non, je ne regrette rien C&amp;#39;est payé, balayé, oublié Je me fous du passé Avec mes souvenirs J&amp;#39;ai allumé le feu Mes chagrins, mes plaisirs Je n&amp;#39;ai plus besoin d&amp;#39;eux Balayé les amours Avec leurs trémolos Balayé pour toujours Je repars à zéro Non, rien de rien Non, je ne regrette rien Ni le bien qu&amp;#39;on m&amp;#39;a fait Ni le mal Tout ça m&amp;#39;est bien égal Non, rien de rien Non, je ne regrette rien Car ma vie Car mes joies Aujourd&amp;#39;hui Ça commence avec toi</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-em-lose-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-em-lose-yourself/</guid><description>EN: Eminem - Loose yourself &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: Eminem - Lose Yourself (Official Video) (Explicit) Lyrics:
Look If you had One shot Or one opportunity To seize everything you ever wanted In one moment Would you capture it Or just let it slip? Yo His palms are sweaty, knees weak, arms are heavy There&amp;#39;s vomit on his sweater already, mom&amp;#39;s spaghetti He&amp;#39;s nervous, but on the surface he looks calm and ready To drop bombs, but he keeps on forgettin&amp;#39; What he wrote down, the whole crowd goes so loud He opens his mouth, but the words won&amp;#39;t come out He&amp;#39;s chokin&amp;#39;, how, everybody&amp;#39;s jokin&amp;#39; now The clocks run out, times up, over, blaow Snap back to reality, ope there goes gravity Ope, there goes Rabbit, he choked He&amp;#39;s so mad, but he won&amp;#39;t give up that easy?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-em-the-way-i-am/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-em-the-way-i-am/</guid><description>EN: Eminem - The Way I Am &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: Eminem - The Way I Am (Dirty Version) Lyrics:
[Intro] Dre, just let it run Ayo, turn the beat up a little bit Ayo This song is for anyone Fuck it, just shut up and listen Ayo [Verse 1] I sit back with this pack of Zig-Zag&amp;#39;s and this bag Of this weed, it gives me the shit needed to be The most meanest MC on this, on this Earth And since birth I&amp;#39;ve been cursed with this curse to just curse And just blurt this berserk and bizarre shit that works And it sells and it helps in itself to relieve All this tension, dispensin&amp;#39; these sentences Gettin&amp;#39; this stress that&amp;#39;s been eatin&amp;#39; me recently off Of this chest and I rest again peacefully (Peacefully) But at least have the decency in you To leave me alone, when you freaks see me out In the streets when I&amp;#39;m eatin&amp;#39; or feedin&amp;#39; my daughter To not come and speak to me (Speak to me), I don&amp;#39;t know you And no, I don&amp;#39;t owe you a motherfuckin&amp;#39; thing I&amp;#39;m not Mr.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-joe-les-champs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-joe-les-champs/</guid><description> FR: Joe Dassin - Les Champs-Elysées &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1JhYYUWOBBs Je m&amp;#39;baladais sur l&amp;#39;avenue le cœur ouvert à l&amp;#39;inconnu J&amp;#39;avais envie de dire bonjour à n&amp;#39;importe qui N&amp;#39;importe qui et ce fut toi, je t&amp;#39;ai dit n&amp;#39;importe quoi Il suffisait de te parler, pour t&amp;#39;apprivoiser Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit Il y a tout ce que vous voulez aux Champs-Elysées Tu m&amp;#39;as dit &amp;#34;J&amp;#39;ai rendez-vous dans un sous-sol avec des fous Qui vivent la guitare à la main, du soir au matin&amp;#34; Alors je t&amp;#39;ai accompagnée, on a chanté, on a dansé Et l&amp;#39;on n&amp;#39;a même pas pensé à s&amp;#39;embrasser Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit Il y a tout ce que vous voulez aux Champs-Elysées Hier soir, deux inconnus et ce matin sur l&amp;#39;avenue Deux amoureux tout étourdis par la longue nuit Et de l&amp;#39;Étoile à la Concorde, un orchestre à mille cordes Tous les oiseaux du point du jour chantent l&amp;#39;amour Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit Il y a tout ce que vous voulez aux Champs-Elysées Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit Il y a tout ce que vous voulez aux Champs-Elysées  Aux Champs-Elysées, aux Champs-Elysées Au soleil, sous la pluie, à midi ou à minuit</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-wutangclan-cream/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/lang/songs/song-wutangclan-cream/</guid><description>EN: Wu-Tang Clan &amp;#x1f3b5; Youtube Link: Wu-Tang Clan - C.R.E.A.M. Lyrics:
[Verse 1] I grew up on the crime side, the New York Times side Stayin&amp;#39; alive was no jive Had secondhands, Moms bounced on old man So then we moved to Shaolin land A young youth, yo, rockin&amp;#39; the gold tooth, &amp;#39;Lo goose Only way I begin the G off was drug loot And let&amp;#39;s start it like this, son Rollin&amp;#39; with this one and that one, pullin&amp;#39; out gats for fun But it was just a dream for the teen Who was a fiend, started smokin&amp;#39; woolies at sixteen And runnin&amp;#39; up in gates and doin&amp;#39; hits for high stakes Makin&amp;#39; my way on fire escapes No question, I would speed for cracks and weed The combination madе my eyes bleed No question, I would flow off and try to gеt the dough off Stickin&amp;#39; up white boys on ball courts My life got no better, same damn &amp;#39;Lo sweater Times is rough and tough like leather Figured out I went the wrong route So I got with a sick-tight clique and went all out Catchin&amp;#39; ki&amp;#39;s from &amp;#39;cross seas Rollin&amp;#39; in MPVs, every week we made forty G Yo, brothas, respect mine or here go the TEC-9, ch-pow Move from the gate now [Verse 2] It&amp;#39;s been twenty-two long, hard years, I&amp;#39;m still strugglin&amp;#39; Survival got me buggin&amp;#39; But I&amp;#39;m alive on arrival, I peep at the shape of the streets And stay awake to the ways of the world &amp;#39;cause **** deep A man with a dream with plans to make cream Which failed, I went to jail at the age of fifteen A young buck sellin&amp;#39; drugs and such, who never had much Tryin&amp;#39; to get a clutch at what I could not touch (Touch) The court played me short, now I face incarceration Pacin&amp;#39;, goin&amp;#39; upstate&amp;#39;s my destination Handcuffed in back of a bus, forty of us Life as a shorty shouldn&amp;#39;t be so rough But as the world turned, I learned life is hell Livin&amp;#39; in the world no different from a cell Every day I escape from jakes givin&amp;#39; chase Sellin&amp;#39; base, smokin&amp;#39; bones in the staircase Though I don&amp;#39;t know why I chose to smoke sess I guess that&amp;#39;s the time when I&amp;#39;m not depressed But I&amp;#39;m still depressed, and I ask, what&amp;#39;s it worth?</description></item></channel></rss>