<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on Darvein</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/categories/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on Darvein</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.darvein.net/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eminem The Way I am</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/eminem-the-way-i-am/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/eminem-the-way-i-am/</guid><description>I really like this song, I used to listen it back when I was 16-17, back then I feelt down most of my days for different reasons, but what really bothered me was people talking about me &amp;ldquo;how I look like, how I walk, how my hair has a different color&amp;rdquo;. I really hated it, people talking about who my girlfriend is, how bad I&amp;rsquo;m in studies, how bad I am in computer games.</description></item><item><title>Wu Tang Clan CREAM</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/wutangclan-cream/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/wutangclan-cream/</guid><description>&amp;#x1f4dd; Lyrics: C.R.E.A.M. Lyrics This song is amazing. Most people relates this song to the Capitalism that we live, people suffering and being treated badly just because they are poor or belongs to a lower social class. What I find on this song personally is something more, they talk about being in jail and comparing it the same hell as living outside of jail, real life and jail life are the same hell, conflicts are present on both lives.</description></item><item><title>Yutaka Ozaki 15 Teens Night</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/yutaka-15teen-night/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/yutaka-15teen-night/</guid><description>Yeah, maybe the song name is incorrect, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to translate it to english from japanese. It basically talks about a boy who is fifteen years old, it talks about all the feelings he can go through in a single solitary night.
Last year (2022) I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening random music in youtube.com and I ended up with Yutaka&amp;rsquo;s music, some people call him the Japanese Kurt Cobain &amp;#x1f604; - dumb people.</description></item></channel></rss>