<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on Darvein</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/categories/life/</link><description>Recent content in Life on Darvein</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.darvein.net/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Comfort through discomfort</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/comfort-disconfort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/comfort-disconfort/</guid><description>Thanks to the discomfort I&amp;rsquo;m becoming a new person, the real me actually.
Here is a list of what is my new comfort now:
Read one single book every day until I finish it Study one single topic every day for a month. Then change the topic. Stop sleeping late. Sleep at 10pm max and waking up at 4AM. No more junk food. Nutritious food only. Cook my own food Repeat the same plates every day No more social media.</description></item><item><title>Keeping it up!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/keeping-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/keeping-up/</guid><description>I gotta be honest. I was not at my fullest this week.
I was back to procastinating everything again! &amp;#x1f915;
Annoying things like:
Being at computer until 3AM Skipping Lunch?&amp;hellip; well not anymore, but eating non-healthy food Skipping reading (&amp;hellip; a bunch of books actually) Skipping the development of my own projects Spending too much time on Social Networks Not going for a run just because of the rain It was like this since last week and I&amp;rsquo;ve been fighting with myself to avoid this, today I&amp;rsquo;m trying to catch-up all my activities, all my duties, all my responsabilities and objectives.</description></item><item><title>Improving Everyday</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/improving-now/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/improving-now/</guid><description>Hey yeah!
I&amp;rsquo;m loving difficult and challenging days. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized I had just few easy going and relaxing days in my life, I have noticed as well that most people have just few days of easy life, most people have many difficult days, most of us and yet we try to escape our own lives.
We should accept it, that is our nature, that is what we were born for. To accept live as it is, on its own terms, not ours.</description></item><item><title>Less is more</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/less-is-more/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/less-is-more/</guid><description>Long ago I realized I was trying to do many things at once but I didn&amp;rsquo;t put a STOP &amp;#x274c; to that, I kept doing many things at once over and over. I have heard million of times on blog posts, youtube and tiktok videos, books, famouse quotes, chatgpt, etc that we should focus on what is important for us. I already defined what is important for me, I know what is my North I know what is the path and I know how difficult it is, the only pending thing is to execute it like I&amp;rsquo;m doing it right now, the only thing I need to do is to be CONSISTENT every single and fck1ng day.</description></item><item><title>Another trip to Coroico</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/another-trip-to-coroico/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/another-trip-to-coroico/</guid><description>This was an unplanned and cool travel to Coroico, initially I had a thought to go there but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t confirmed until last minute.
So while driving this was my planning on my head:
Truchas para el Almuerzo en Pongo (Lunch) Cascadas San Jancito y Felix (Afternoon) Tocaña (Next morning) Parque Leque (Next afternoon) Right after the lunch I headed out to &amp;ldquo;Cascadas San Jacinto &amp;amp; Felix&amp;rdquo;, but it was 4.</description></item><item><title>Switch to English</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/switch-to-english/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/switch-to-english/</guid><description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve just decided to maintain my personal webpage in English only, I really need to master this language. I&amp;rsquo;ve been speaking this language in a mediocre way, I really wish I could improve it more and get better and better, there is no other way to archive that goal by practicing every day, speaking every day, writting every day, listening every day, that is the way to go.
Starting from now I will share all I want to share in english, hopefully this help me a lot and I can have more readers obviosly &amp;#x1f604;</description></item><item><title>Un viajecito rapidito nomás</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/un-viajecito-rapidito-nomas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/un-viajecito-rapidito-nomas/</guid><description>Un fin de semana reparador, con un buen viaje para desconectarse de todo un por un momento.
&amp;#x2015; Aqui calientito, allá atras prefiero no ir por ahora... &amp;#x2015; El clima se estaba cien puntos el primer día, luego se puso feo. El clima ya no es como antes &amp;#x1f604;
No hubo muchas fotografías esta vez como parte del viaje, sino mas bién mas selfies. Aquí algunas.
&amp;#x2015; Practicando fotografía &amp;#x2015; &amp;#x2015; Nada mejor que un buen dia soleado &amp;#x2015; Yo me llevé algunos libros para leer y este otro campeón se llevo la tarea que no hizo en meses para que yo le supervise :evil:</description></item><item><title>Mejor sin redes sociales</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/mejor-sin-redes-sociales/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/mejor-sin-redes-sociales/</guid><description>Soy muy adicto a las redes sociales, ni automizando puedo estar al tanto de todo lo que pasa en internet. Pero luego me doy cuenta que mi mente se estresa, se cansa y no se estimula mas luego de estar leendo tantas cosas diferentes en tan poco tiempo. Dicen que eso afecta a la concetración, asi que me estoy poniendo mas fuerte para dejar de ver novedades en tan poco tiempo, osea, dejar de ver redes sociales.</description></item><item><title>Hogar dulce hogar</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/sweet-home-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/sweet-home-0/</guid><description>&amp;#x2015; Toma frontal en dia soleado &amp;#x2015; El hogar ya va tomando forma. No fué para nada fácil. A veces pienso hubiera sido mejor comprar una casa ya construida, pero bueno, son cosas que uno aprende en la vida y ya estamos a 50% del hogar dulce hogar! &amp;#x1f604;</description></item><item><title>El proceso de cambio</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/el-proces-de-cambio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/el-proces-de-cambio/</guid><description>He vivido ya buen tiempo en casas que no eran mias, en algun momento tenía que pensar seriamente en comprar la mia, propio esfuerzo, propio sacrificio, noches sin dormir, dias sin comer, dias sin familia. Al final del tunel se ve la luz, se requiere mucha perseverancia y paciencia.
El proceso de cambio toma tiempo y no siempre es perfecto, ¡pero llega! &amp;#x1f60b;</description></item><item><title>Los descanzos son importantes</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/los-descanzos-son-importantes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/los-descanzos-son-importantes/</guid><description>No sé donde dijeron que uno trabajaba 11 meses del año para poder tomar vacaciones un par de semanas, o que muchos trabajaban 5 días a la semana para descanzar dos, o que muchos trabajaban 8 horas al día para poder disfrutar de 3 o 4 horas solamente. Talvez sólo es un tema de percepción, pero igual, siento que ahora es el momento de dejar de trabajar tanto como lo hacía antes y disfrutar mas de la vida.</description></item><item><title>Momentos con la naturaleza</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/momentos-con-la-naturaleza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/momentos-con-la-naturaleza/</guid><description>Primera vez en la vida que había tenido este tipo de estres donde sentía un dolor incómodo en el pecho, de esa molestía como cuando hacer ejercicios intensos de mucho tiempo y te &amp;ldquo;macurcas&amp;rdquo;. El asuntito duró como dos semanas ya me siento mucho mejor..
&amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; pero tuve que dormir mejor &amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; alimentarme mejor &amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; meditar &amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; estar en paz &amp;#x2714;&amp;#xfe0f; continuar ejercitando No sabía exactamente dónde ir, una vez fuí al paseo de ingreso a Aranjuéz, pero esos autos y la gasolina que desprendían no me convencía, esta vez fuí al Jardín Botánico de la UMSA en Cota Cota.</description></item><item><title>Otra escapada de finde!</title><link>https://www.darvein.net/posts/otra-escapada-de-finde/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.darvein.net/posts/otra-escapada-de-finde/</guid><description>Esta escapada fué a Huatajata, como lo dije una vez, bien el lugar&amp;hellip; Antes yo no era de viajar o salir, pero ahora estoy con ganas &amp;#x1f604; y nadie quien nos pare &amp;#x1f60e;.
El lugar tiene botes, barcos, barcos inflábles giratorios (?), canchas, lugares para parilla, arena, etc.
Existen ya varios doctores que dijeron haber encontrado cura para el cancer y otras enfermedades pero misteriosamente fallecieron sin completar sus investigaciones, no recuerdo, pero uno de ellos decía que una manera efectiva de desestresarse es descargar la &amp;ldquo;energía&amp;rdquo; acumulada en nuestro cuerpo&amp;hellip; recomendaba pisar tierra con la planta de los pies, tan simple como eso y&amp;hellip; si, tan efectivo &amp;#x1f604;.</description></item></channel></rss>